<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>BMW, E39, Project, Upgrade, 2000 on E39Source</title><link>https://www.e39source.com/tags/bmw-e39-project-upgrade-2000/</link><description>Recent content in BMW, E39, Project, Upgrade, 2000 on E39Source</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://www.e39source.com/tags/bmw-e39-project-upgrade-2000/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>2010: The Story: Ryan’s 2000 BMW E39 M5:</title><link>https://www.e39source.com/blog/the-story-ryans-200-bmw-e39-m5/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.e39source.com/blog/the-story-ryans-200-bmw-e39-m5/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://e39source.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/12/IMG_0487.jpg" alt="Alt text">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>All cars have a story, and I’m about to get very carried away telling mine. It’ll be long, detailed, and full of links to &lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/user/E39Source/videos?view=0">YouTube videos&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="http://www.e39source.com/">website articles&lt;/a> that I have written through the process. This is nearly a decade in the making, after all.&lt;/p>
&lt;p> &lt;br/>&lt;br/>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Sunday, July 18th, 2010. 6:42pm.&lt;/strong> The corner of Village Way and Library Street, in the midwestern town of Hudson, Ohio. I was in the downtown area of my community with my grandparents at a concert on our square. During intermission, we always took a little stroll to get some ice cream. This stroll happened to be a tad more expensive, but much more fun. My M5 was poorly backed in to a spot, showing it’s age with the pre-facelift headlights, a gaudy front license plate, and more than a handful of stone chips in the hood and front bumper. There was an orange For Sale sign on the inside of the windshield, displaying the car’s year, make, model, and the owner’s phone number. I snapped a few photos with my iPhone 4, hence the exact aforementioned date and time. My grandparents were a lot less excited about the car than I was.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>2011: The Story: Ryan’s 2000 BMW E39 M5:</title><link>https://www.e39source.com/blog/the-story-ryans-200-bmw-e39-m5-2011/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.e39source.com/blog/the-story-ryans-200-bmw-e39-m5-2011/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>2011&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p> &lt;br/>&lt;br/>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>By this point, I had learned that I could not afford to have any service/maintenance/upgrades carried out through BMW dealerships. I was on my own. And I found that there was very little quality DIY content available online. After spending years making technology DIYs on YouTube, I toyed with the idea of switching to cars. In 2011, I created E39Source DIYs for the &lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=S-WjJgv7AHs">shift knob&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=RFTOM1-qXmU">parking brake handle&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=bkLTEcAdEMU">center console trim&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=MnScPFwnB58">cup-holders&lt;/a>, and I replaced a failed &lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=YSYNdfjVUro">rear park distance control sensor&lt;/a>. Mechanically, I replaced the &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=q9O6TjvA_vA">front brake rotors and pads&lt;/a>, fixed a squeaky window, and had my &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=QQF6lUmDvOA">parking brake shoes&lt;/a> replaced. I also replaced the front bumper, fog lights, grills, and had the hood and front bumper repainted. In December, I bought a &lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=JXQ3D9P9g9o">Peake R5/FCX-3&lt;/a> code reader. This kept me busy and poor for a long while. I found that 11 codes had been reported to the computer. I let Dave Walter BMW in Akron, Ohio do some diagnostics, and then I spent a month with the car in and out of service getting work done. The thermostat, water pump, spark plugs, O2 sensors, and several different sensors replaced. This removed all but 1 code: code AA, secondary air. This is the one that you don’t want. I let BMW try some solution through the engine to remove the carbon build-up in the system, and it still didn’t totally fix the problem. According to my full service history on the car, the engine had been removed in 2008, and the carbon channels had been drilled out.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>2012: The Story: Ryan’s 2000 BMW E39 M5:</title><link>https://www.e39source.com/blog/the-story-ryans-200-bmw-e39-m5-2012/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.e39source.com/blog/the-story-ryans-200-bmw-e39-m5-2012/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>2012&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p> &lt;br/>&lt;br/>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Fa t n eat b lts. My cluster’s pixels were committing suicide by the day. It turns out, somebody saw one of my videos showing the problem on YouTube. He sent me a message, telling me how to get BMW of North America to help fix the problem for less than the cost of a whole new cluster. This guy had a 2003 525iA do the same thing, and he is now partly responsible for this website, and one of my closest friends. Thank you, Bobby. I now have a &lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=9wWt6OlXfu4">face-lift working cluster&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>2013: The Story: Ryan’s 2000 BMW E39 M5:</title><link>https://www.e39source.com/blog/the-story-ryans-200-bmw-e39-m5-2013/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.e39source.com/blog/the-story-ryans-200-bmw-e39-m5-2013/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>2013&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p> &lt;br/>&lt;br/>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Navigation. In the 2001 model year, BMW upgraded the E39’s &lt;a href="http://e39source.com/archives/797">navigation&lt;/a> display to a 16:9 widescreen instrument. The computer also got upgraded. I took this a step further, and bought a MKIV computer in addition to 16:9 display. Big upgrade for this car, DVD readability and all!&lt;/p>
&lt;p> &lt;br/>&lt;br/>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I spent much of 2013 fixing the larger issues. They weren’t even large, but they bothered me. I replaced intake camshaft sensors, installed new floor matts and white fog bulbs, changed &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=jgBcC6nKDH0">transmission&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Ekmxh8du3I4">differential&lt;/a>oils, replaced control arms and tie rods, added LED license plate lights, had some more minor rust marks removed, changed shifter bushings, added a UUC Evo 3 short shift kit, replaced the &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=o3CP9RXiX0M">FSU and blower motor&lt;/a> and replaced my &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=iUTX5BkNz7c">mass air flow sensors&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>2014: The Story: Ryan’s 2000 BMW E39 M5:</title><link>https://www.e39source.com/blog/the-story-ryans-200-bmw-e39-m5-2014/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.e39source.com/blog/the-story-ryans-200-bmw-e39-m5-2014/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>2014&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p> &lt;br/>&lt;br/>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Things will get crazy this year. I have decided to make this car as nice as I can afford to. That means every screw, every clip, every bracket, every everything has to be present, and in good working condition. They also need to look good. I ordered over 400 new parts for this car this year. It got new OEM style 65 wheels, new tires, chassis braces, instrument cluster bezel, switches, knobs, fan clutch, engine fan, door sills, M-audio subs, front bumper, trim, fog lights, rear bumper, trim, diffuser, facelift steering wheel, a total over-haul in electronics, all exterior door trim, coolant expansion tank, new filters, parking brake rebuild, rear brake overhaul, M3 oil cap, oil return hoses, and all mounting and installation hardware associated with these things. That huge list represents less than 1/4 of the parts replaced. I want this car to look amazing, it deserves to. It was a 7/10 to begin with, but by selling all of the old parts still worth using, I can afford a 9/10. I also installed the Shark Injector software to remove the AA code, and make the car a bit more fun.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>2015: The Story: Ryan’s 2000 BMW E39 M5:</title><link>https://www.e39source.com/blog/the-story-ryans-200-bmw-e39-m5-2015/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.e39source.com/blog/the-story-ryans-200-bmw-e39-m5-2015/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>2015&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p> &lt;br/>&lt;br/>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Spring 2015 started with body work. I had the new side mirrors painted, rust removed from one rocker panel, and various other minor rust spot corrections. The car is now rust free! I did the brake fluid when new lines were installed, and got fresh coolant after a thermostat replacement. At 188,026 miles now, this car is more capable than any 2003 model I’ve ever seen. A full euro lighting conversion, all OEM parts, a short shift kit, Shark tune, M-audio woofers, SIRIUS XM, aux, upgraded navigation, fresh vitals, etc. 2015 carried on with a ton of improvements: 18mm Eibach rear sway bar, beast power brackets, &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=0Lq2tPzdGco">front PDC retrofit&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=bQbVkcupciM">aluminum pedals&lt;/a>, Eisenmann Race 4x76mm axle-back exhaust, fresh Pilot Super Sport tires, an oil change, OE front rotors and Hawk HPS pads, new front calipers, PDR, &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=zqYI074iNRs">seat trims and buttons&lt;/a>, and various other hardware and small trim bits. I also replaced all of the interior Titan-line trim. The center console, dashboard trims, door trims, all fresh. The old stuff was in okay condition, but it tends to get glossier with age. The fresh trim set is more of a matte finish, and freshens up the interior quite nicely. Seemingly, right after I ordered the fresh interior trim set, the prices on this stuff skyrocketed. I think I got one of the last sets.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>2016: The Story: Ryan’s 2000 BMW E39 M5:</title><link>https://www.e39source.com/blog/the-story-ryans-200-bmw-e39-m5-2016/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.e39source.com/blog/the-story-ryans-200-bmw-e39-m5-2016/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>2016&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p> &lt;br/>&lt;br/>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In March of 2016, the roads cleared enough for me to take the car into the shop. The plans had grown though. Not only was it getting a rebuilt 2002 engine and 2003 differential, but a full driveline, brake, gear linkage, and suspension refresh. Anything under the car that wasn’t set for at least 100,000 miles was to be rebuilt/replaced.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The engine work had been going on since January. The heads were sent out to a machine shop to be cleaned, and have new valve seals fitted. The valve clearances were checked, and they were all like new. The block was also sent out for cleaning and a polish. It came back like new too. Anything that is wearable inside the engine was replaced (minus the piston rings). Every seal, gasket, tensioner, washer, bolt, nut, etc. Hundreds of parts were replaced while re-constructing this engine. The VANOS system went to Dr. VANOS for new o-rings, cleaning, testing, and to have the helical gears machined so it’ll be as quiet as possible.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>2017: The Story: Ryan’s 2000 BMW E39 M5:</title><link>https://www.e39source.com/blog/the-story-ryans-200-bmw-e39-m5-2017/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.e39source.com/blog/the-story-ryans-200-bmw-e39-m5-2017/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>2017&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p> &lt;br/>&lt;br/>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>January, 2017&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://e39source.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/10/IMG_1442.jpg" alt="Alt text">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My original engine now in New York.&lt;/p>
&lt;p> &lt;br/>&lt;br/>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I got bored enough in January to reach out to the new owner of my old S62, and see what he had found out with it. He bought my used engine to install in a project car of his. He told me a year ago that he planned to rebuild it before installing it in another car. I received several photos of my old engine opened up, and taken apart. After 192,000 miles, the bottom end still looked clean, with no sludge or anything worrisome. The connecting rod bearings certainly showed some wear, but nothing that would have caused catastrophic failure. The new owner even said that the timing chain guides (original) still appeared to be quite strong. This engine had a lot of life left.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>2018: The Story: Ryan’s 2000 BMW E39 M5:</title><link>https://www.e39source.com/blog/the-story-ryans-200-bmw-e39-m5-2018/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.e39source.com/blog/the-story-ryans-200-bmw-e39-m5-2018/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>2018&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p> &lt;br/>&lt;br/>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For April Fools day, Kennan had the great idea to film an E39Source Intro- in the voice and grandeur of US President Donald J. Tump. You have to see &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=IS08mcduhrs">this video&lt;/a>!&lt;/p>
&lt;p> &lt;br/>&lt;br/>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://e39source.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/IMG_0925.png" alt="Alt text">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Kennan filming Trump’s intro with my M5.&lt;/p>
&lt;p> &lt;br/>&lt;br/>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://e39source.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/IMG_9574.png" alt="Alt text">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The April Fools video was a HUUUUGGEE success.&lt;/p>
&lt;p> &lt;br/>&lt;br/>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For the summer of 2018, I added the Rogue Engineering Diablo resonated x-pipe to my exhaust setup, which now features stock headers and cats, the Rogue x-pipe, and the 4x76mm Eisenmann Race mufflers. I love this sound and have no future plans to further change it. It has a great low-RPM sound, and screams like a Ferrari in the upper ranges. When driven tamely, it draws very little attention to itself too. The perfect setup! In May, I did some more basic maintenance: a brake fluid flush, e-box blower fan motor, and fresh center exhaust bushings to go with the new x-pipe.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>2019: The Story: Ryan’s 2000 BMW E39 M5:</title><link>https://www.e39source.com/blog/the-story-ryans-200-bmw-e39-m5-2019/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.e39source.com/blog/the-story-ryans-200-bmw-e39-m5-2019/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>2019&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p> &lt;br/>&lt;br/>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>E39Source is now an LLC, with a brick and mortar location. We rented a 3,500 square foot shop up in Escondido, 30 miles north of San Diego. We had two lifts installed, and got a badass set of tools. You can read more about what E39Source is doing now &lt;a href="https://e39source.com/about">here&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p> &lt;br/>&lt;br/>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://e39source.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/IMG_6449.png" alt="Alt text">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>New-style BMW battery (black)&lt;/p>
&lt;p> &lt;br/>&lt;br/>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>February, 2019&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This first winter in California was ‘rainy’ by California standards. That meant that my dad’s 1998 Ferrari 355 wasn’t driven as much over the winter as it usually does. When we attempted to start it to attend a Ferrari Owner’s Club drive to the wine country in Temecula, we got nothing but a series of clicks. The battery was dead- which meant my M5 had to run with Ferraris with that. And it kept up beautifully! Here are some shots from the gathering.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>2020: The Story: Ryan’s 2000 BMW E39 M5:</title><link>https://www.e39source.com/blog/the-story-ryans-200-bmw-e39-m5-2020/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.e39source.com/blog/the-story-ryans-200-bmw-e39-m5-2020/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>2020&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p> &lt;br/>&lt;br/>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I am now finally using this car for what I have been building it for for years! I wanted a reliable, daily-drivable M5 for when I got to California. It took me nearly a decade to build that car, and now I can finally use it. From 2014-2018, I drove the car around 3,500 miles per year. In 2019, I logged over 9,000 miles, and loved every one of them!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>2021: The Story: Ryan’s 2000 BMW E39 M5:</title><link>https://www.e39source.com/blog/the-story-ryans-200-bmw-e39-m5-2021/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.e39source.com/blog/the-story-ryans-200-bmw-e39-m5-2021/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>2021&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p> &lt;br/>&lt;br/>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As the E39Source, LLC service business gains more momentum, I started having the opportunity to work with some very special and unique BMWs (and their owners!) This car is nearly my identical twin; a gorgeous Silverstone/Silverstone 2001 M5. We completed loads of driveline, suspension, and cosmetic improvements on this car, and delivered it to a very happy customer in late January. Per customer request, I thoroughly test-drove this car until we were happy with it’s drivability and new feature functionality. I made a video about our &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=2nLxcwOU--4">newly available services here&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>2022: The Story: Ryan’s 2000 BMW E39 M5:</title><link>https://www.e39source.com/blog/the-story-ryans-200-bmw-e39-m5-2022/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.e39source.com/blog/the-story-ryans-200-bmw-e39-m5-2022/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>2022&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p> &lt;br/>&lt;br/>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We pick up 2022 while still waiting for the brake calipers to return from being refurbished. I took this opportunity to drop the exhaust and replace the various heat shields around and above the exhaust system. Mine were dirty, crusty, and had some of the mounting holes washed out due to aluminum corrosion. In order to remove one of the shields, the driveshaft had to come out. I noted a slight tick from the center support bearing, so I replaced that as well. Before installation, I installed a fresh flex disk while I’m in here. With the driveshaft out, I was staring at the bottom of the shifter assembly… with 6 year old bushings. See why I call this a can of worms? After new shifter carrier bushings, rod joint, and cup, I noticed a very crusty slave cylinder soft line. So, new slave cylinder, soft/hard line between the clutch slave and master cylinders, and all the brackets and hardware. While reinstalling the exhaust, I noticed the series of brackets were missing that hold it to the transmission. I checked photos from 2016, and they were missing then too! I have no idea what happened to those exhaust brackets. I ordered and installed the factory replacement parts.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>