<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Other-BMW-Content on E39Source</title><link>https://ajmameshin.github.io/E39Source/categories/other-bmw-content/</link><description>Recent content in Other-BMW-Content on E39Source</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://ajmameshin.github.io/E39Source/categories/other-bmw-content/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>BMW E39: P0443/Evap Code Diagnosis</title><link>https://ajmameshin.github.io/E39Source/blog/evap-code-diagnosis/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ajmameshin.github.io/E39Source/blog/evap-code-diagnosis/</guid><description>I just bought my 1998 BMW 540i two weeks ago, and I knew when I bought it that there was a check engine light on for an EVAP code. I pulled the code and it came up as P0443. I just wanted to outline a short diagnostic checklist of things to check when you experience this or any other EVAP code related to the purge valve.
Check your gas cap.</description></item><item><title>BMW Wheel Center Caps</title><link>https://ajmameshin.github.io/E39Source/blog/wheel-center-caps/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ajmameshin.github.io/E39Source/blog/wheel-center-caps/</guid><description>For the 2003 model year, BMW facelift the wheel center caps for the E39 M5. This new version looks more like the hood/trunk lid badge. Gone is the gray plastic bezel and in is a nice chrome ring. The plastic feels better, the badge is a hair bigger, and these new components seem to withstand the test of time better.
Objective: Update or refresh the look of your wheels with the new-style BMW wheel center caps.</description></item><item><title>Maintaining a Vintage BMW</title><link>https://ajmameshin.github.io/E39Source/blog/maintaining-a-vintage-bmw/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ajmameshin.github.io/E39Source/blog/maintaining-a-vintage-bmw/</guid><description>You’ve probably heard about the incredible story of the M1 that was found sitting in a garage in Italy for 34 years. But in case you need a refresher, it’s the 1981 production model that had only clocked 4,600 miles before being put in storage by its owner. Then last year, the vintage car specialists at Mint Classics discovered the automobile in its poor state. Fortunately it wasn’t too late, so now it’s being returned to its former glory.</description></item></channel></rss>