<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Other-BMW-Content on E39Source</title><link>https://www.e39source.com/categories/other-bmw-content/</link><description>Recent content in Other-BMW-Content on E39Source</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://www.e39source.com/categories/other-bmw-content/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>2014 BMW M5 and M6 to Receive Upgraded Competition Package</title><link>https://www.e39source.com/blog/2014-bmw-m5-and-m6-to-receive-upgraded-competition-package/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.e39source.com/blog/2014-bmw-m5-and-m6-to-receive-upgraded-competition-package/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://e39source.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/BMW-F10-M5-High-Quality-Wallpapers-1920x1200-wallpaper-01.jpg" alt="Alt text">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BMW is testing a new version of the F10 M5, which is expected to be launched this summer as a 2014 model. It will continue to be offered with its 560-hp, twin-turbo, 4.4-liter V-8, but there will also be an optional performance pack- called the Competition Package, which will consist of several upgrades to the current M5.&lt;/p>
&lt;p> &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The output of the higher-performance M5 and M6 models will rise from 560 to 575 horsepower. In addition, both models should receive distinct wheels, black exhaust tips, a revised suspension which will be tuned in favor of a sportier ride with crisper handling, and a more direct steering ratio.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>BMW Alarm Goes Off? Hood Sensor Replacement</title><link>https://www.e39source.com/blog/bmw-alarm-goes-off-hood-sensor-replacement/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.e39source.com/blog/bmw-alarm-goes-off-hood-sensor-replacement/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://e39source.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/IMG_7120.png" alt="Alt text">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Is your alarm going off randomly? In most cases, your culprit is a small hood security switch in the engine bay that takes no more than a few minutes to replace!&lt;/p>
&lt;p> &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Depending on which BMW model you own, you may have a ‘clown nose’ red light on your rear-view mirror. When you lock your car, this light should flash, every ~3 seconds or so. If the car thinks there is a fault in the alarm system (hood sensor failure) the light will flash rapidly, maybe 2 times per second or more immediately after locking.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>BMW Answers Tesla with a “Green” Supercar</title><link>https://www.e39source.com/blog/bmw-answers-tesla-with-a-green-supercar/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.e39source.com/blog/bmw-answers-tesla-with-a-green-supercar/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://e39source.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/11/c19b11e1d14610ea10e69d8b8a4da306.jpg" alt="Alt text">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Up till now, Tesla has had the market for high-end electric cars pretty much to itself. But that first-mover advantage is ending. BMW has just rolled out the i8, a plug-in supercar that will test just how much big spenders are willing to pay for a racer with a green badge. This real-life Batmobile starts at about $140,000, but availability is limited for now, and some sellers are asking well over $200,000 for the car.BMW says production should ramp up by next year. The i8 isn’t a full electric like the Tesla Model S, but a hybrid that has both an electric motor and a three-cylinder, twin-turbo gasoline engine.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>BMW at the 2013 Detroit Auto Show</title><link>https://www.e39source.com/blog/bmw-at-the-2013-detroit-auto-show/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.e39source.com/blog/bmw-at-the-2013-detroit-auto-show/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://e39source.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/2014-BMW-4-Series-Coupe-Concept-NAIAS-Main.jpg" alt="Alt text">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I’ve attended nearly ten consecutive showings of the Cleveland Auto Show, held at the International Exposition Center in Cleveland, Ohio. Only last year did we decide to hit the Detroit show too, known as NAIAS, or North American International Auto Show. We took my Dad’s 2008 X530is, and it ended up being a really nice show. BMW showcased the F30 3-series in each of the three trims, the F10 M5, and i3 and i8 concept vehicles.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>BMW Depreciation: E30 M3, E36 M3, E39 M5. Andrew’s Thoughts.</title><link>https://www.e39source.com/blog/bmw-depreciation-e30-m3-e36-m3-e39-m5/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.e39source.com/blog/bmw-depreciation-e30-m3-e36-m3-e39-m5/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://e39source.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/1987-bmw-e30-m3-and-1996-e36-m3-photo-365393-s-1280x782-1.jpg" alt="Alt text">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As an automotive enthusiast, I am never content with the M5. There will always be a car that is more comfortable, there will always be a car more reliable, there will always be a car that is faster, and there will always be a car that is just better. However, at the price point E39 M5’s are at, it is a great do-it-all car. And that is why I keep it around.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>BMW E36: Bi-Xenon Headlight Retrofit</title><link>https://www.e39source.com/blog/bmw-e36-bi-xenon-headlight-retrofit/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.e39source.com/blog/bmw-e36-bi-xenon-headlight-retrofit/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://e39source.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/06/WP_20160504_005.jpg" alt="Alt text">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>How do you get high intensity lighting for under $200 $50? Easy, peasy, lemon squeeze: all you need to do is retrofit your stock plastic lens E36 headlights with bi-xenon projectors. With some modification from a Dremel, razor blade, and a pry tool, you too can have HID lighting without resorting to a eat-ramen-every-night college-esque budget.&lt;/p>
&lt;p> &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>DIY on Andrew’s Channel&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>BMW E39 Cup Holder Replacement DIY</title><link>https://www.e39source.com/blog/bmw-e39-cup-holder-replacement-diy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.e39source.com/blog/bmw-e39-cup-holder-replacement-diy/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://e39source.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/E39-Cup-Holder-Replacement.jpg" alt="Alt text">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Today I installed replacement cup holders into my E39 540i/6. The following is a quick tutorial on how to do the same to your E39!&lt;/p>
&lt;p> &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Objective:&lt;/strong> Replace broken cup holders which no longer stay closed.&lt;/p>
&lt;p> &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Applicable Vehicles:&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1996-2003 BMW E39 5-series: 520i, 523i, 525i, 528i, 530i, 535i, 540i, M5.&lt;/p>
&lt;p> &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>BMW E39, E38, E46: LED License Plate Lights</title><link>https://www.e39source.com/blog/bmw-e39-e38-e46-led-license-plate-lights/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.e39source.com/blog/bmw-e39-e38-e46-led-license-plate-lights/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://e39source.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/07/after.jpg" alt="Alt text">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>An easy and affordable way to modernize the rear of your BMW is to update your license plate lights. Prior to ~2011, BMW had used very yellow and dim lights to illuminate the rear tag. These days they’re using significantly brighter LEDs that produce a very crisp and white colored light. I installed these lights into my 2000 M5, and have been happy with the results. They do NOT trigger a ‘check warning’ on the dash.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>BMW E39: Corner Sunshade Replacement</title><link>https://www.e39source.com/blog/bmw-e39-corner-sunshade-replacement/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.e39source.com/blog/bmw-e39-corner-sunshade-replacement/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://e39source.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/12/Sunshade1.png" alt="Alt text">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This article will detail the removal and re-installation of the corner sunshade on the rear doors of the E39 5-series.&lt;/p>
&lt;p> &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Objective:&lt;/strong> This article will detail the removal and re-installation of the corner sunshade on the rear doors of the E39 5-series.&lt;/p>
&lt;p> &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Applicable Vehicles:&lt;/strong> 1996-2003 BMW E39 5-series: 520i, 523i, 525i, 528i, 530i, 535i, 540i, M5.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>BMW E39: Trunk Carpet Replacement</title><link>https://www.e39source.com/blog/bmw-e39-trunk-carpet-replacement/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.e39source.com/blog/bmw-e39-trunk-carpet-replacement/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://e39source.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_2840.jpg" alt="Alt text">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Today I installed very lightly used carpeting into the trunk of my 2001 BMW 540i/6. The carpeting that was in the vehicle was in very poor condition due to abuse and lack of knowledge by the previous owner.&lt;/p>
&lt;p> &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Objective:&lt;/strong> Refresh the look of your trunk area.&lt;/p>
&lt;p> &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Applicable Vehicles:&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1996-2003 BMW E39 5-series: 520i, 523i, 525i, 528i, 530i, 535i, 540i, M5.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>BMW Initiates Recall For Over 780,000 Vehicles</title><link>https://www.e39source.com/blog/bmw-initiates-recall-for-over-780000-vehicles/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.e39source.com/blog/bmw-initiates-recall-for-over-780000-vehicles/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://e39source.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/bmw-recall-feat.png" alt="Alt text">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BMW has initiated a recall for several models, more than 780,000 vehicles worldwide, in countries such as Canada, Japan, South Africa, and the United States. There is a problem with the positive battery cable; the tin on the connector may degrade over time, causing electrical problems, stalling, or even a complete loss of power while the vehicle is in motion. The affected vehicles include: 1 Series coupes and convertibles (both 128i and 135i) from the 2008 to 2011 model years; 3 Series sedans, coupes, convertibles and sport wagons (both 328i and 335i) from the 2007 to 2012 model years; and Z4 roadsters from the 2009 model year to present date.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>BMW M50/M52: Intake Modification</title><link>https://www.e39source.com/blog/m52-intake-modification/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.e39source.com/blog/m52-intake-modification/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://e39source.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/06/WP_20160504_005.jpg" alt="Alt text">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>With this modification, your M52B25 or M52B28 engine will make more power. The M52B25 and M52B28 engines can be found in the E36, E39, E38, and in some early E46 models. This is not the easiest modification, but if you are at least a little bit handy, it is not difficult. Some people say that this will gain an additional 20HP, while some say it won’t give you any. I believe that there are power benefits.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>BMW N54 Tuning &amp; Maintenance Guide</title><link>https://www.e39source.com/blog/bmw-n54-tuning--maintenance-guide/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.e39source.com/blog/bmw-n54-tuning--maintenance-guide/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://e39source.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/BMW-N54-twin-turbo-I6_1200x1200.jpg" alt="Alt text">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Over the past few years, the N54 twin turbo 3.0 lite inline-6 has gained the reputation of being an easily tunable and powerful engine. With the N54 aging and the increasing number of modifications available, we are bound to begin seeing more blown engines and turbos. Although the block and internals are very strong, the N54 is prone to issues without the proper maintenance and repairs. Whether your N54 is stock or running a large single turbo set up, this guide will ensure your engine is running at its best.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>BMW Removes Manual Transmission From 5-Series</title><link>https://www.e39source.com/blog/bmw-removes-manual-transmission-from-5-series/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.e39source.com/blog/bmw-removes-manual-transmission-from-5-series/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://e39source.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/11/6mt.jpg" alt="Alt text">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Roughly a month ago, I was on BMW USA’s website and noticed the manual gearbox was removed from the F10 5 series. The standard gearbox is now the 8 speed auto (sigh) or there is the sport automatic transmission for an extra $500. When a manual gearbox is removed from a fine tuned driving instrument, a part of its soul has been removed.Thankfully the manual is still available on the 3 series (probably for a short time) and on the M series line up. Yes, I know that modern automatics are more reliable, get exceptional fuel economy and offer extremely quick shifts, however, if the reader shares the same views as I and believes a car should have, engine at the front, manual gearbox in the middle, and drive at the back, then what are we as driving aficionados to do. I suppose we could buy a used F10, E60, E39, and I guess manual gearboxes are becoming a thing of the past.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>BMW Swirl Scratch Removal</title><link>https://www.e39source.com/blog/bmw-swirl-scratch-removal/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.e39source.com/blog/bmw-swirl-scratch-removal/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://e39source.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/IMG_4186.jpg" alt="Alt text">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Here is how I removed the swirl scratches and replenished the finish on the hood of 540i/6.&lt;/p>
&lt;p> &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Objective:&lt;/strong> Buff out shallow scratches in the clear coat.&lt;/p>
&lt;p> &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Applicable Vehicles:&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>All clear-coated vehicles.&lt;/p>
&lt;p> &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Parts required:&lt;/strong> Zaino Z2, Z5, Z8, and Z18.&lt;/p>
&lt;p> &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>BMW Wheel Center Caps</title><link>https://www.e39source.com/blog/wheel-center-caps/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.e39source.com/blog/wheel-center-caps/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://e39source.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/IMG_0424-1-1024x668.jpg" alt="Alt text">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For the 2003 model year, BMW facelift the wheel center caps for the E39 M5. This new version looks more like the hood/trunk lid badge. Gone is the gray plastic bezel and in is a nice chrome ring. The plastic feels better, the badge is a hair bigger, and these new components seem to withstand the test of time better.&lt;/p>
&lt;p> &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Maintaining a Vintage BMW</title><link>https://www.e39source.com/blog/maintaining-a-vintage-bmw/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.e39source.com/blog/maintaining-a-vintage-bmw/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://e39source.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/Screen-Shot-2017-08-31-at-1.50.20-AM.png" alt="Alt text">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You’ve probably heard about the incredible story of the M1 that was found sitting in a garage in Italy for 34 years. But in case you need a refresher, it’s the 1981 production model that had only clocked 4,600 miles before being put in storage by its owner. Then last year, the vintage car specialists at Mint Classics discovered the automobile in its poor state. Fortunately it wasn’t too late, so now it’s being returned to its former glory.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Restoration Project: Alpina B10 V8</title><link>https://www.e39source.com/blog/restoration-project-alpina-b10-v8/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.e39source.com/blog/restoration-project-alpina-b10-v8/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://e39source.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/04/31354076_CP_photo1.jpeg" alt="Alt text">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After two weeks of a detailed check-up at BMW Dubai (AED 4,000 or $1,100 USD) plus my additional instructions, I came to understand that the core of this car is healthy. The only big mechanical aspects are: front wishbones, rear wheel bearings suspensions (Alpina specific, will cost a fortune as I want genuine OEM only), the rubber disc connecting the gearbox output to the prop-shaft, and the spinning crankshaft joint. Also the AC/dynamo belts and steering are weak.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Shit E39 Owners Say</title><link>https://www.e39source.com/blog/shit-e39-owners-say/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.e39source.com/blog/shit-e39-owners-say/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://e39source.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/09/IMG_27631.jpg" alt="Alt text">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We thought it may be rather amusing to put together a little video dedicated to BMW E39 owners. The three of us, listed below, are all E39Source owners and E39 M5 Owners. We hope you enjoy watching this video and guarantee that some of these things will sound familiar to you as a BMW/E39 owner!&lt;/p>
&lt;p> &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ryan Schultz, &lt;a href="http://e39source.com/archives/187">2000 M5&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Kennan Rolsen, &lt;a href="http://e39source.com/archives/1011">2001 525i/5&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Ultimate Car Detailing: Zaino</title><link>https://www.e39source.com/blog/the-ultimate-car-detailing-zaino/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.e39source.com/blog/the-ultimate-car-detailing-zaino/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://e39source.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/IMG_3282-1.png" alt="Alt text">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It’s a guy thing. In the garage or shop of any car enthusiast, you’re likely to find dozens of car products. Soaps, tire shines, glass cleaners, leather conditioners, assorted towels, brushes, sponges, etc. We like to spend our weekends polishing our cars, even if they only go back in the garage directly afterwards. For some reason, it’s a therapeutic process. Like any process, there are dozens of ways to go about it. With automotive detailing, there are millions of ways to do it wrong. Waxing and polishing products are tools, and like any tool, they are only productively effective when used correctly. Zaino products are my tools of choice. This article is designed to detail the correct way to complete the Zaino wax process on your vehicle, and then maintain all of your hard work.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>