<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Other-BMW-Content on E39Source</title><link>https://ajmameshin.github.io/E39Source/categories/other-bmw-content/</link><description>Recent content in Other-BMW-Content on E39Source</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://ajmameshin.github.io/E39Source/categories/other-bmw-content/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>BMW Answers Tesla with a “Green” Supercar</title><link>https://ajmameshin.github.io/E39Source/blog/bmw-answers-tesla-with-a-green-supercar/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ajmameshin.github.io/E39Source/blog/bmw-answers-tesla-with-a-green-supercar/</guid><description>Up till now, Tesla has had the market for high-end electric cars pretty much to itself. But that first-mover advantage is ending. BMW has just rolled out the i8, a plug-in supercar that will test just how much big spenders are willing to pay for a racer with a green badge. This real-life Batmobile starts at about $140,000, but availability is limited for now, and some sellers are asking well over $200,000 for the car.</description></item><item><title>BMW E36: Bi-Xenon Headlight Retrofit</title><link>https://ajmameshin.github.io/E39Source/blog/bmw-e36-bi-xenon-headlight-retrofit/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ajmameshin.github.io/E39Source/blog/bmw-e36-bi-xenon-headlight-retrofit/</guid><description>How do you get high intensity lighting for under $200 $50? Easy, peasy, lemon squeeze: all you need to do is retrofit your stock plastic lens E36 headlights with bi-xenon projectors. With some modification from a Dremel, razor blade, and a pry tool, you too can have HID lighting without resorting to a eat-ramen-every-night college-esque budget.
DIY on Andrew’s Channel</description></item><item><title>BMW M50/M52: Intake Modification</title><link>https://ajmameshin.github.io/E39Source/blog/m52-intake-modification/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ajmameshin.github.io/E39Source/blog/m52-intake-modification/</guid><description>With this modification, your M52B25 or M52B28 engine will make more power. The M52B25 and M52B28 engines can be found in the E36, E39, E38, and in some early E46 models. This is not the easiest modification, but if you are at least a little bit handy, it is not difficult. Some people say that this will gain an additional 20HP, while some say it won’t give you any. I believe that there are power benefits.</description></item><item><title>BMW N54 Tuning &amp; Maintenance Guide</title><link>https://ajmameshin.github.io/E39Source/blog/bmw-n54-tuning--maintenance-guide/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ajmameshin.github.io/E39Source/blog/bmw-n54-tuning--maintenance-guide/</guid><description>Over the past few years, the N54 twin turbo 3.0 lite inline-6 has gained the reputation of being an easily tunable and powerful engine. With the N54 aging and the increasing number of modifications available, we are bound to begin seeing more blown engines and turbos. Although the block and internals are very strong, the N54 is prone to issues without the proper maintenance and repairs. Whether your N54 is stock or running a large single turbo set up, this guide will ensure your engine is running at its best.</description></item><item><title>BMW Removes Manual Transmission From 5-Series</title><link>https://ajmameshin.github.io/E39Source/blog/bmw-removes-manual-transmission-from-5-series/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ajmameshin.github.io/E39Source/blog/bmw-removes-manual-transmission-from-5-series/</guid><description>Roughly a month ago, I was on BMW USA’s website and noticed the manual gearbox was removed from the F10 5 series. The standard gearbox is now the 8 speed auto (sigh) or there is the sport automatic transmission for an extra $500. When a manual gearbox is removed from a fine tuned driving instrument, a part of its soul has been removed.Thankfully the manual is still available on the 3 series (probably for a short time) and on the M series line up.</description></item><item><title>BMW Wheel Center Caps</title><link>https://ajmameshin.github.io/E39Source/blog/wheel-center-caps/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ajmameshin.github.io/E39Source/blog/wheel-center-caps/</guid><description>For the 2003 model year, BMW facelift the wheel center caps for the E39 M5. This new version looks more like the hood/trunk lid badge. Gone is the gray plastic bezel and in is a nice chrome ring. The plastic feels better, the badge is a hair bigger, and these new components seem to withstand the test of time better.
Objective: Update or refresh the look of your wheels with the new-style BMW wheel center caps.</description></item><item><title>Maintaining a Vintage BMW</title><link>https://ajmameshin.github.io/E39Source/blog/maintaining-a-vintage-bmw/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ajmameshin.github.io/E39Source/blog/maintaining-a-vintage-bmw/</guid><description>You’ve probably heard about the incredible story of the M1 that was found sitting in a garage in Italy for 34 years. But in case you need a refresher, it’s the 1981 production model that had only clocked 4,600 miles before being put in storage by its owner. Then last year, the vintage car specialists at Mint Classics discovered the automobile in its poor state. Fortunately it wasn’t too late, so now it’s being returned to its former glory.</description></item><item><title>Restoration Project: Alpina B10 V8</title><link>https://ajmameshin.github.io/E39Source/blog/restoration-project-alpina-b10-v8/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ajmameshin.github.io/E39Source/blog/restoration-project-alpina-b10-v8/</guid><description>After two weeks of a detailed check-up at BMW Dubai (AED 4,000 or $1,100 USD) plus my additional instructions, I came to understand that the core of this car is healthy. The only big mechanical aspects are: front wishbones, rear wheel bearings suspensions (Alpina specific, will cost a fortune as I want genuine OEM only), the rubber disc connecting the gearbox output to the prop-shaft, and the spinning crankshaft joint.</description></item></channel></rss>