<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>E39Source</title><link>https://www.e39source.com/</link><description>Recent content on E39Source</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://www.e39source.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>2010: The Story: Ryan’s 2000 BMW E39 M5:</title><link>https://www.e39source.com/blog/the-story-ryans-200-bmw-e39-m5/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.e39source.com/blog/the-story-ryans-200-bmw-e39-m5/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://e39source.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/12/IMG_0487.jpg" alt="Alt text">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>All cars have a story, and I’m about to get very carried away telling mine. It’ll be long, detailed, and full of links to &lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/user/E39Source/videos?view=0">YouTube videos&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="http://www.e39source.com/">website articles&lt;/a> that I have written through the process. This is nearly a decade in the making, after all.&lt;/p>
&lt;p> &lt;br/>&lt;br/>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Sunday, July 18th, 2010. 6:42pm.&lt;/strong> The corner of Village Way and Library Street, in the midwestern town of Hudson, Ohio. I was in the downtown area of my community with my grandparents at a concert on our square. During intermission, we always took a little stroll to get some ice cream. This stroll happened to be a tad more expensive, but much more fun. My M5 was poorly backed in to a spot, showing it’s age with the pre-facelift headlights, a gaudy front license plate, and more than a handful of stone chips in the hood and front bumper. There was an orange For Sale sign on the inside of the windshield, displaying the car’s year, make, model, and the owner’s phone number. I snapped a few photos with my iPhone 4, hence the exact aforementioned date and time. My grandparents were a lot less excited about the car than I was.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>2011: The Story: Ryan’s 2000 BMW E39 M5:</title><link>https://www.e39source.com/blog/the-story-ryans-200-bmw-e39-m5-2011/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.e39source.com/blog/the-story-ryans-200-bmw-e39-m5-2011/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>2011&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p> &lt;br/>&lt;br/>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>By this point, I had learned that I could not afford to have any service/maintenance/upgrades carried out through BMW dealerships. I was on my own. And I found that there was very little quality DIY content available online. After spending years making technology DIYs on YouTube, I toyed with the idea of switching to cars. In 2011, I created E39Source DIYs for the &lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=S-WjJgv7AHs">shift knob&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=RFTOM1-qXmU">parking brake handle&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=bkLTEcAdEMU">center console trim&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=MnScPFwnB58">cup-holders&lt;/a>, and I replaced a failed &lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=YSYNdfjVUro">rear park distance control sensor&lt;/a>. Mechanically, I replaced the &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=q9O6TjvA_vA">front brake rotors and pads&lt;/a>, fixed a squeaky window, and had my &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=QQF6lUmDvOA">parking brake shoes&lt;/a> replaced. I also replaced the front bumper, fog lights, grills, and had the hood and front bumper repainted. In December, I bought a &lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=JXQ3D9P9g9o">Peake R5/FCX-3&lt;/a> code reader. This kept me busy and poor for a long while. I found that 11 codes had been reported to the computer. I let Dave Walter BMW in Akron, Ohio do some diagnostics, and then I spent a month with the car in and out of service getting work done. The thermostat, water pump, spark plugs, O2 sensors, and several different sensors replaced. This removed all but 1 code: code AA, secondary air. This is the one that you don’t want. I let BMW try some solution through the engine to remove the carbon build-up in the system, and it still didn’t totally fix the problem. According to my full service history on the car, the engine had been removed in 2008, and the carbon channels had been drilled out.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>2012: The Story: Ryan’s 2000 BMW E39 M5:</title><link>https://www.e39source.com/blog/the-story-ryans-200-bmw-e39-m5-2012/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.e39source.com/blog/the-story-ryans-200-bmw-e39-m5-2012/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>2012&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p> &lt;br/>&lt;br/>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Fa t n eat b lts. My cluster’s pixels were committing suicide by the day. It turns out, somebody saw one of my videos showing the problem on YouTube. He sent me a message, telling me how to get BMW of North America to help fix the problem for less than the cost of a whole new cluster. This guy had a 2003 525iA do the same thing, and he is now partly responsible for this website, and one of my closest friends. Thank you, Bobby. I now have a &lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=9wWt6OlXfu4">face-lift working cluster&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>2013: The Story: Ryan’s 2000 BMW E39 M5:</title><link>https://www.e39source.com/blog/the-story-ryans-200-bmw-e39-m5-2013/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.e39source.com/blog/the-story-ryans-200-bmw-e39-m5-2013/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>2013&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p> &lt;br/>&lt;br/>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Navigation. In the 2001 model year, BMW upgraded the E39’s &lt;a href="http://e39source.com/archives/797">navigation&lt;/a> display to a 16:9 widescreen instrument. The computer also got upgraded. I took this a step further, and bought a MKIV computer in addition to 16:9 display. Big upgrade for this car, DVD readability and all!&lt;/p>
&lt;p> &lt;br/>&lt;br/>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I spent much of 2013 fixing the larger issues. They weren’t even large, but they bothered me. I replaced intake camshaft sensors, installed new floor matts and white fog bulbs, changed &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=jgBcC6nKDH0">transmission&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Ekmxh8du3I4">differential&lt;/a>oils, replaced control arms and tie rods, added LED license plate lights, had some more minor rust marks removed, changed shifter bushings, added a UUC Evo 3 short shift kit, replaced the &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=o3CP9RXiX0M">FSU and blower motor&lt;/a> and replaced my &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=iUTX5BkNz7c">mass air flow sensors&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>2014 BMW M5 and M6 to Receive Upgraded Competition Package</title><link>https://www.e39source.com/blog/2014-bmw-m5-and-m6-to-receive-upgraded-competition-package/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.e39source.com/blog/2014-bmw-m5-and-m6-to-receive-upgraded-competition-package/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://e39source.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/BMW-F10-M5-High-Quality-Wallpapers-1920x1200-wallpaper-01.jpg" alt="Alt text">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BMW is testing a new version of the F10 M5, which is expected to be launched this summer as a 2014 model. It will continue to be offered with its 560-hp, twin-turbo, 4.4-liter V-8, but there will also be an optional performance pack- called the Competition Package, which will consist of several upgrades to the current M5.&lt;/p>
&lt;p> &lt;br/>&lt;br/>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The output of the higher-performance M5 and M6 models will rise from 560 to 575 horsepower. In addition, both models should receive distinct wheels, black exhaust tips, a revised suspension which will be tuned in favor of a sportier ride with crisper handling, and a more direct steering ratio.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>2014: The Story: Ryan’s 2000 BMW E39 M5:</title><link>https://www.e39source.com/blog/the-story-ryans-200-bmw-e39-m5-2014/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.e39source.com/blog/the-story-ryans-200-bmw-e39-m5-2014/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>2014&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p> &lt;br/>&lt;br/>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Things will get crazy this year. I have decided to make this car as nice as I can afford to. That means every screw, every clip, every bracket, every everything has to be present, and in good working condition. They also need to look good. I ordered over 400 new parts for this car this year. It got new OEM style 65 wheels, new tires, chassis braces, instrument cluster bezel, switches, knobs, fan clutch, engine fan, door sills, M-audio subs, front bumper, trim, fog lights, rear bumper, trim, diffuser, facelift steering wheel, a total over-haul in electronics, all exterior door trim, coolant expansion tank, new filters, parking brake rebuild, rear brake overhaul, M3 oil cap, oil return hoses, and all mounting and installation hardware associated with these things. That huge list represents less than 1/4 of the parts replaced. I want this car to look amazing, it deserves to. It was a 7/10 to begin with, but by selling all of the old parts still worth using, I can afford a 9/10. I also installed the Shark Injector software to remove the AA code, and make the car a bit more fun.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>2015: The Story: Ryan’s 2000 BMW E39 M5:</title><link>https://www.e39source.com/blog/the-story-ryans-200-bmw-e39-m5-2015/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.e39source.com/blog/the-story-ryans-200-bmw-e39-m5-2015/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>2015&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p> &lt;br/>&lt;br/>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Spring 2015 started with body work. I had the new side mirrors painted, rust removed from one rocker panel, and various other minor rust spot corrections. The car is now rust free! I did the brake fluid when new lines were installed, and got fresh coolant after a thermostat replacement. At 188,026 miles now, this car is more capable than any 2003 model I’ve ever seen. A full euro lighting conversion, all OEM parts, a short shift kit, Shark tune, M-audio woofers, SIRIUS XM, aux, upgraded navigation, fresh vitals, etc. 2015 carried on with a ton of improvements: 18mm Eibach rear sway bar, beast power brackets, &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=0Lq2tPzdGco">front PDC retrofit&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=bQbVkcupciM">aluminum pedals&lt;/a>, Eisenmann Race 4x76mm axle-back exhaust, fresh Pilot Super Sport tires, an oil change, OE front rotors and Hawk HPS pads, new front calipers, PDR, &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=zqYI074iNRs">seat trims and buttons&lt;/a>, and various other hardware and small trim bits. I also replaced all of the interior Titan-line trim. The center console, dashboard trims, door trims, all fresh. The old stuff was in okay condition, but it tends to get glossier with age. The fresh trim set is more of a matte finish, and freshens up the interior quite nicely. Seemingly, right after I ordered the fresh interior trim set, the prices on this stuff skyrocketed. I think I got one of the last sets.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>2016: The Story: Ryan’s 2000 BMW E39 M5:</title><link>https://www.e39source.com/blog/the-story-ryans-200-bmw-e39-m5-2016/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.e39source.com/blog/the-story-ryans-200-bmw-e39-m5-2016/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>2016&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p> &lt;br/>&lt;br/>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In March of 2016, the roads cleared enough for me to take the car into the shop. The plans had grown though. Not only was it getting a rebuilt 2002 engine and 2003 differential, but a full driveline, brake, gear linkage, and suspension refresh. Anything under the car that wasn’t set for at least 100,000 miles was to be rebuilt/replaced.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The engine work had been going on since January. The heads were sent out to a machine shop to be cleaned, and have new valve seals fitted. The valve clearances were checked, and they were all like new. The block was also sent out for cleaning and a polish. It came back like new too. Anything that is wearable inside the engine was replaced (minus the piston rings). Every seal, gasket, tensioner, washer, bolt, nut, etc. Hundreds of parts were replaced while re-constructing this engine. The VANOS system went to Dr. VANOS for new o-rings, cleaning, testing, and to have the helical gears machined so it’ll be as quiet as possible.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>2017: The Story: Ryan’s 2000 BMW E39 M5:</title><link>https://www.e39source.com/blog/the-story-ryans-200-bmw-e39-m5-2017/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.e39source.com/blog/the-story-ryans-200-bmw-e39-m5-2017/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>2017&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p> &lt;br/>&lt;br/>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>January, 2017&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://e39source.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/10/IMG_1442.jpg" alt="Alt text">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My original engine now in New York.&lt;/p>
&lt;p> &lt;br/>&lt;br/>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I got bored enough in January to reach out to the new owner of my old S62, and see what he had found out with it. He bought my used engine to install in a project car of his. He told me a year ago that he planned to rebuild it before installing it in another car. I received several photos of my old engine opened up, and taken apart. After 192,000 miles, the bottom end still looked clean, with no sludge or anything worrisome. The connecting rod bearings certainly showed some wear, but nothing that would have caused catastrophic failure. The new owner even said that the timing chain guides (original) still appeared to be quite strong. This engine had a lot of life left.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>2018: The Story: Ryan’s 2000 BMW E39 M5:</title><link>https://www.e39source.com/blog/the-story-ryans-200-bmw-e39-m5-2018/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.e39source.com/blog/the-story-ryans-200-bmw-e39-m5-2018/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>2018&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p> &lt;br/>&lt;br/>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For April Fools day, Kennan had the great idea to film an E39Source Intro- in the voice and grandeur of US President Donald J. Tump. You have to see &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=IS08mcduhrs">this video&lt;/a>!&lt;/p>
&lt;p> &lt;br/>&lt;br/>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://e39source.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/IMG_0925.png" alt="Alt text">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Kennan filming Trump’s intro with my M5.&lt;/p>
&lt;p> &lt;br/>&lt;br/>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://e39source.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/IMG_9574.png" alt="Alt text">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The April Fools video was a HUUUUGGEE success.&lt;/p>
&lt;p> &lt;br/>&lt;br/>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For the summer of 2018, I added the Rogue Engineering Diablo resonated x-pipe to my exhaust setup, which now features stock headers and cats, the Rogue x-pipe, and the 4x76mm Eisenmann Race mufflers. I love this sound and have no future plans to further change it. It has a great low-RPM sound, and screams like a Ferrari in the upper ranges. When driven tamely, it draws very little attention to itself too. The perfect setup! In May, I did some more basic maintenance: a brake fluid flush, e-box blower fan motor, and fresh center exhaust bushings to go with the new x-pipe.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>2019: The Story: Ryan’s 2000 BMW E39 M5:</title><link>https://www.e39source.com/blog/the-story-ryans-200-bmw-e39-m5-2019/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.e39source.com/blog/the-story-ryans-200-bmw-e39-m5-2019/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>2019&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p> &lt;br/>&lt;br/>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>E39Source is now an LLC, with a brick and mortar location. We rented a 3,500 square foot shop up in Escondido, 30 miles north of San Diego. We had two lifts installed, and got a badass set of tools. You can read more about what E39Source is doing now &lt;a href="https://e39source.com/about">here&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p> &lt;br/>&lt;br/>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://e39source.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/IMG_6449.png" alt="Alt text">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>New-style BMW battery (black)&lt;/p>
&lt;p> &lt;br/>&lt;br/>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>February, 2019&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This first winter in California was ‘rainy’ by California standards. That meant that my dad’s 1998 Ferrari 355 wasn’t driven as much over the winter as it usually does. When we attempted to start it to attend a Ferrari Owner’s Club drive to the wine country in Temecula, we got nothing but a series of clicks. The battery was dead- which meant my M5 had to run with Ferraris with that. And it kept up beautifully! Here are some shots from the gathering.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>2020: The Story: Ryan’s 2000 BMW E39 M5:</title><link>https://www.e39source.com/blog/the-story-ryans-200-bmw-e39-m5-2020/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.e39source.com/blog/the-story-ryans-200-bmw-e39-m5-2020/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>2020&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p> &lt;br/>&lt;br/>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I am now finally using this car for what I have been building it for for years! I wanted a reliable, daily-drivable M5 for when I got to California. It took me nearly a decade to build that car, and now I can finally use it. From 2014-2018, I drove the car around 3,500 miles per year. In 2019, I logged over 9,000 miles, and loved every one of them!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>2021: The Story: Ryan’s 2000 BMW E39 M5:</title><link>https://www.e39source.com/blog/the-story-ryans-200-bmw-e39-m5-2021/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.e39source.com/blog/the-story-ryans-200-bmw-e39-m5-2021/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>2021&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p> &lt;br/>&lt;br/>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As the E39Source, LLC service business gains more momentum, I started having the opportunity to work with some very special and unique BMWs (and their owners!) This car is nearly my identical twin; a gorgeous Silverstone/Silverstone 2001 M5. We completed loads of driveline, suspension, and cosmetic improvements on this car, and delivered it to a very happy customer in late January. Per customer request, I thoroughly test-drove this car until we were happy with it’s drivability and new feature functionality. I made a video about our &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=2nLxcwOU--4">newly available services here&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>2022: The Story: Ryan’s 2000 BMW E39 M5:</title><link>https://www.e39source.com/blog/the-story-ryans-200-bmw-e39-m5-2022/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.e39source.com/blog/the-story-ryans-200-bmw-e39-m5-2022/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>2022&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p> &lt;br/>&lt;br/>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We pick up 2022 while still waiting for the brake calipers to return from being refurbished. I took this opportunity to drop the exhaust and replace the various heat shields around and above the exhaust system. Mine were dirty, crusty, and had some of the mounting holes washed out due to aluminum corrosion. In order to remove one of the shields, the driveshaft had to come out. I noted a slight tick from the center support bearing, so I replaced that as well. Before installation, I installed a fresh flex disk while I’m in here. With the driveshaft out, I was staring at the bottom of the shifter assembly… with 6 year old bushings. See why I call this a can of worms? After new shifter carrier bushings, rod joint, and cup, I noticed a very crusty slave cylinder soft line. So, new slave cylinder, soft/hard line between the clutch slave and master cylinders, and all the brackets and hardware. While reinstalling the exhaust, I noticed the series of brackets were missing that hold it to the transmission. I checked photos from 2016, and they were missing then too! I have no idea what happened to those exhaust brackets. I ordered and installed the factory replacement parts.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>About Us</title><link>https://www.e39source.com/about-us/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.e39source.com/about-us/</guid><description>&lt;style>
.centered-table-img img {
 display: block;
 margin-left: auto;
 margin-right: auto;
}
.no-lines,
.no-lines th,
.no-lines td,
.no-lines tr {
 border: none !important;
 border-collapse: collapse !important;
}
 
.no-lines td:first-child {
 padding-right: 20px; 
}

 
@media (max-width: 768px) {
 .table-responsive .table,
 .table-responsive .table th,
 .table-responsive .table td,
 .table-responsive .table tr {
 border: none !important; 
 border-collapse: collapse !important; 
 font-size: 0.8em; 
 padding: 8px; 
 }
 
 .centered-table-img img {
 max-width: 150px; 
 height: auto; 
 } 
}
&lt;/style>





&lt;div class="table-responsive">
&lt;table class="%!s(&lt;nil>) text-left no-lines"
 &lt;thead class="%!s(&lt;nil>) text-left"
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;th>&lt;/th>
 &lt;th>&lt;/th>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;/thead>
 &lt;tbody>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td class="centered-table-img"> &lt;/td>
 &lt;td class="centered-table-img">&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td class="centered-table-img">&lt;img src="../img/AboutPicRyan_resized.png" alt="img">&lt;/td>
 &lt;td class="centered-table-img">Ryan Schultz&amp;rsquo;s love of cars started at a young age, thanks to the influence from his grandfather and father back in his home state of Ohio. In 2003, Ryan’s father Gary purchased a BMW 530i, and thus began his love for BMW and the E39 platform. In 2010, Ryan acquired his 2000 Silverstone M5 - his first car.  Unable to afford costly dealership service, he quickly realized he needed to be able to perform his own service and restoration work.  After earning his Business Management degree from Kent State University in 2016, he fulfilled his life-long dream of moving to San Diego to immerse himself in Southern-California car culture and establish E39Source as a brick-and-mortar operation dedicated to exceptional BMW service.  He is an active member in the BMW CCA and serves on the Board of Directors for the San Diego Region of the Ferrari Owners Club. Ryan’s pursuit of perfection and inordinately high attention to detail has become the very backbone of what E39Source is today.&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td class="centered-table-img"> &lt;/td>
 &lt;td class="centered-table-img">&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>

&lt;/div>


















&lt;style>
.centered-table-img img {
 display: block;
 margin-left: auto;
 margin-right: auto;
}
.no-lines,
.no-lines th,
.no-lines td,
.no-lines tr {
 border: none !important;
 border-collapse: collapse !important;
}
 
.no-lines td:first-child {
 padding-right: 20px; 
}

 
@media (max-width: 768px) {
 .table-responsive .table,
 .table-responsive .table th,
 .table-responsive .table td,
 .table-responsive .table tr {
 border: none !important; 
 border-collapse: collapse !important; 
 font-size: 0.8em; 
 padding: 8px; 
 }
 
 .centered-table-img img {
 max-width: 150px; 
 height: auto; 
 } 
}
&lt;/style>





&lt;div class="table-responsive">
&lt;table class="%!s(&lt;nil>) text-right no-lines"
 &lt;thead class="%!s(&lt;nil>) text-right"
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;th>&lt;/th>
 &lt;th>&lt;/th>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;/thead>
 &lt;tbody>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td class="centered-table-img"> &lt;/td>
 &lt;td class="centered-table-img">&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td class="centered-table-img">Gary Schultz is a co-owner of E39Source and has been a car enthusiast since childhood. His love of cars was passed down from his father who enjoyed working on his American-made vehicles. Gary grew up near Akron, Ohio and has a BA degree in Economics from Kent State University. After graduating he worked for Progressive Corporation headquartered in Cleveland, Ohio as an IT Operations Manager. After nearly 30 years at Progressive Gary decided to move to a better climate and lifestyle in Southern California where he worked for HP in Rancho Bernardo for 10 years before expanding E39Source, LLC in Escondido with Ryan in 2019. Gary owns two BMW M5s, a manual-converted E60 and an F10 as well as a Ferrari 355 F1 Spider. Both Gary and Ryan are active participants in the San Diego chapter of the Ferrari Owner Club where they sit on the Board of Directors and assist in event planning and club operations.&lt;/td>
 &lt;td class="centered-table-img">&lt;img src="../img/MEWP1342_resized_resized.png" alt="img">&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td class="centered-table-img"> &lt;/td>
 &lt;td class="centered-table-img">&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>

&lt;/div>


















&lt;style>
.centered-table-img img {
 display: block;
 margin-left: auto;
 margin-right: auto;
}
.no-lines,
.no-lines th,
.no-lines td,
.no-lines tr {
 border: none !important;
 border-collapse: collapse !important;
}
 
.no-lines td:first-child {
 padding-right: 20px; 
}

 
@media (max-width: 768px) {
 .table-responsive .table,
 .table-responsive .table th,
 .table-responsive .table td,
 .table-responsive .table tr {
 border: none !important; 
 border-collapse: collapse !important; 
 font-size: 0.8em; 
 padding: 8px; 
 }
 
 .centered-table-img img {
 max-width: 150px; 
 height: auto; 
 } 
}
&lt;/style>





&lt;div class="table-responsive">
&lt;table class="%!s(&lt;nil>) text-right no-lines"
 &lt;thead class="%!s(&lt;nil>) text-right"
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;th>&lt;/th>
 &lt;th>&lt;/th>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;/thead>
 &lt;tbody>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td class="centered-table-img"> &lt;/td>
 &lt;td class="centered-table-img">&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td class="centered-table-img">&lt;img src="../img/Alan_Lopes_Pic_resized-2.png" alt="img">&lt;/td>
 &lt;td class="centered-table-img">Alan Lopes is the lead technician at E39Source. He is a true car enthusiast and a huge BMW fan who has been working on cars since the age of 17. Born and raised in Brooklyn, New York, he moved to California in 2017 to escape the city life and embrace the palm trees and sunshine. The vibrant car culture in California was another compelling reason for his relocation, and he is now living the dream! Alan currently owns an early model BMW E30 5-speed, which he acquired from the original owner here in California and continues to restore in his spare time.&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td class="centered-table-img"> &lt;/td>
 &lt;td class="centered-table-img">&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>

&lt;/div></description></item><item><title>Alex’s 1999 BMW E39 540i/6 Introduction</title><link>https://www.e39source.com/blog/alexs-1999-bmw-e39-540i6-indroduction/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.e39source.com/blog/alexs-1999-bmw-e39-540i6-indroduction/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://e39source.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/0710152028b.jpg" alt="Alt text">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There comes a point in time when people decide that they want to make a change in life. For me, that change was owning a BMW. The first I heard of BMW’s was as a kid going to the auto show with my father, and grandfather. It wasn’t until high school that I really became a car guy. The very first time I rode in a E39 was in 2011, with Ryan’s 2000 E39 M5. I immediately fell in love with that car, and knew that I had to have one. It wasn’t until 4 years later that I can finally say that I am a proud owner of a BMW. I purchased this vehicle off of my good friend, Razvan who gave me a fantastic deal on this beautiful machine.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Alex’s 2000 BMW E46 328i Introduction</title><link>https://www.e39source.com/blog/alexs-2000-bmw-e46-328i-introduction/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.e39source.com/blog/alexs-2000-bmw-e46-328i-introduction/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://e39source.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/01/IMG_3171.jpg" alt="Alt text">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If I were to tell you that I’ve always been a fan of BMW, I’d be lying. Two years ago, if you were to tell me my first car would be an E46, I would have called you crazy! Living in Buffalo, NY, I pictured my first car as some sort of all wheel drive vehicle. I really was set on an older WRX, due to the decent performance, and great all wheel drive system. I was also your typical Fast and Furious type kid who drooled over JDM “riced” out cars. It’s bad, I know. Luckily, one trip to visit my brother in San Francisco changed my taste in cars completely.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Andres’ 2000 540i 6 Introduction</title><link>https://www.e39source.com/blog/andres-2000-540i-6-introduction/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.e39source.com/blog/andres-2000-540i-6-introduction/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://e39source.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/IMG_5663.jpg" alt="Alt text">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Hello E39 Source, my name is Andres and I’d like to introduce my 2000 540i/6. Here’s a little background information about how I found my car and what I’ve done to it. I’ve been a car guy for as long as I can remember; my grandpa’s a mechanic and my dad races vintage cars in SCCA. The day I turned fifteen and got my learner’s license, I was already looking into what my first car could possibly be. At first, I was looking into Subaru Legacy Outback wagons. Why?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Andrew’s 2000 BMW M5 Introduction</title><link>https://www.e39source.com/blog/andrews-2000-bmw-m5-introduction/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.e39source.com/blog/andrews-2000-bmw-m5-introduction/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://e39source.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/12/Andrew-M5.png" alt="Alt text">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>M5 ownership is a grand experience, even though it has been riddled with mistakes, hard work, and pure luck. My name is Andrew, and I didn’t start out with my current M5, but rather another BMW: my mother’s 2003 E53 X5. It has the 3.0 liter M54 motor, and a religious service history from the dealer/independent specialists so I would never be let down. It took me until halfway through my senior year in high school and I was using the X5’s utility to the max. I was a three sport athlete, and also a volunteer fire fighter, so I was driving to-and-from practice, my home, and the fire house quite often. A plain soccer-mobile X5 was boring for a trending high school senior, so I started to modify it subtly. However, the interior got hit hard with my crazy hormones, and my style reflected that; I put plaid fabric over the wood trim, and vinyled my center console so all my friends could sign it.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Andrew’s New Benz!</title><link>https://www.e39source.com/blog/andrews-new-benz/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.e39source.com/blog/andrews-new-benz/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://e39source.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/12/IMG_5355.jpg" alt="Alt text">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My past BMW’s were fun cars. I had a great time driving them, and I learned a lot fixing them. However, they got a bit repetitive after having cars so similar: the E53 X5, E36 318ti, and the E36 328i. These all shared so much in common that I could go through the motions to change out a thermostat or replace an oil filter housing gasket with my eyes closed. So, what does a car guy do when they need a new project to tinker on? He moves on and gets a 1995 W124 Mercedes E320!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Auxiliary Input Kit Installation (Non-Nav)</title><link>https://www.e39source.com/blog/auxiliary-input-kit-installation-non-nav/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.e39source.com/blog/auxiliary-input-kit-installation-non-nav/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://e39source.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/07/190895_x800.jpg" alt="Alt text">&lt;/p>
&lt;p> &lt;br/>&lt;br/>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This article will go over the required parts and steps to install a hard-wired factory BMW auxiliary input kit to your E39 5-series without factory navigation.&lt;/p>
&lt;p> &lt;br/>&lt;br/>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Objective:&lt;/strong> Install a factory BMW hard-wired auxiliary input cable to your 5-series.&lt;/p>
&lt;p> &lt;br/>&lt;br/>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Applicable Vehicles:&lt;/strong> 1997-2003 BMW E39 5-series (Without Navigation): 520i, 523i, 525i, 528i, 530i, 535i, 540i, M5.&lt;/p>
&lt;p> &lt;br/>&lt;br/>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>DISCLOSURE:&lt;/strong> This post may contain affiliate links, meaning when you click the links and make a purchase, we receive a commission.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>BMW 16:9 Navigation Display Knobs</title><link>https://www.e39source.com/blog/bmw-169-navigation-display-knobs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.e39source.com/blog/bmw-169-navigation-display-knobs/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://e39source.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/12/IMG_4915.jpg" alt="Alt text">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A weak point for an article, yes, but something nonetheless that we should address. As new, enthusiastic owners buy up BMWs, we often like to do a little maintenance. Replace some trim here, a &lt;a href="http://e39source.com/archives/416">shift knob&lt;/a> there, et cetera. After years of use, the somewhat-cheap rubber knobs really deteriorate. They look scuffed, and feel slushy. Replacing them can improve the feel of your radio and navigation system!&lt;/p>
&lt;p> &lt;br/>&lt;br/>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Objective:&lt;/strong> Refresh navigation display with fresh, new knobs.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>BMW Alarm Goes Off? Hood Sensor Replacement</title><link>https://www.e39source.com/blog/bmw-alarm-goes-off-hood-sensor-replacement/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.e39source.com/blog/bmw-alarm-goes-off-hood-sensor-replacement/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://e39source.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/IMG_7120.png" alt="Alt text">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Is your alarm going off randomly? In most cases, your culprit is a small hood security switch in the engine bay that takes no more than a few minutes to replace!&lt;/p>
&lt;p> &lt;br/>&lt;br/>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Depending on which BMW model you own, you may have a ‘clown nose’ red light on your rear-view mirror. When you lock your car, this light should flash, every ~3 seconds or so. If the car thinks there is a fault in the alarm system (hood sensor failure) the light will flash rapidly, maybe 2 times per second or more immediately after locking.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>BMW Answers Tesla with a “Green” Supercar</title><link>https://www.e39source.com/blog/bmw-answers-tesla-with-a-green-supercar/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.e39source.com/blog/bmw-answers-tesla-with-a-green-supercar/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://e39source.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/11/c19b11e1d14610ea10e69d8b8a4da306.jpg" alt="Alt text">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Up till now, Tesla has had the market for high-end electric cars pretty much to itself. But that first-mover advantage is ending. BMW has just rolled out the i8, a plug-in supercar that will test just how much big spenders are willing to pay for a racer with a green badge. This real-life Batmobile starts at about $140,000, but availability is limited for now, and some sellers are asking well over $200,000 for the car.BMW says production should ramp up by next year. The i8 isn’t a full electric like the Tesla Model S, but a hybrid that has both an electric motor and a three-cylinder, twin-turbo gasoline engine.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>BMW at the 2013 Detroit Auto Show</title><link>https://www.e39source.com/blog/bmw-at-the-2013-detroit-auto-show/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.e39source.com/blog/bmw-at-the-2013-detroit-auto-show/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://e39source.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/2014-BMW-4-Series-Coupe-Concept-NAIAS-Main.jpg" alt="Alt text">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I’ve attended nearly ten consecutive showings of the Cleveland Auto Show, held at the International Exposition Center in Cleveland, Ohio. Only last year did we decide to hit the Detroit show too, known as NAIAS, or North American International Auto Show. We took my Dad’s 2008 X530is, and it ended up being a really nice show. BMW showcased the F30 3-series in each of the three trims, the F10 M5, and i3 and i8 concept vehicles.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>BMW Depreciation: E30 M3, E36 M3, E39 M5. Andrew’s Thoughts.</title><link>https://www.e39source.com/blog/bmw-depreciation-e30-m3-e36-m3-e39-m5.-andrews-thoughts./</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.e39source.com/blog/bmw-depreciation-e30-m3-e36-m3-e39-m5.-andrews-thoughts./</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://e39source.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/1987-bmw-e30-m3-and-1996-e36-m3-photo-365393-s-1280x782-1.jpg" alt="Alt text">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As an automotive enthusiast, I am never content with the M5. There will always be a car that is more comfortable, there will always be a car more reliable, there will always be a car that is faster, and there will always be a car that is just better. However, at the price point E39 M5’s are at, it is a great do-it-all car. And that is why I keep it around.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>BMW E36: Bi-Xenon Headlight Retrofit</title><link>https://www.e39source.com/blog/bmw-e36-bi-xenon-headlight-retrofit/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.e39source.com/blog/bmw-e36-bi-xenon-headlight-retrofit/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://e39source.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/06/WP_20160504_005.jpg" alt="Alt text">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>How do you get high intensity lighting for under $200 $50? Easy, peasy, lemon squeeze: all you need to do is retrofit your stock plastic lens E36 headlights with bi-xenon projectors. With some modification from a Dremel, razor blade, and a pry tool, you too can have HID lighting without resorting to a eat-ramen-every-night college-esque budget.&lt;/p>
&lt;p> &lt;br/>&lt;br/>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>DIY on Andrew’s Channel&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
 &lt;iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share; fullscreen" loading="eager" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/X3sn2JmZlro?autoplay=0&amp;amp;controls=1&amp;amp;end=0&amp;amp;loop=0&amp;amp;mute=0&amp;amp;start=0" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" title="YouTube video">&lt;/iframe>
 &lt;/div>

&lt;p> &lt;br/>&lt;br/>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>BMW E39 528i: Cooling System Bleeding Insight</title><link>https://www.e39source.com/blog/cooling-system-bleeding-insight/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.e39source.com/blog/cooling-system-bleeding-insight/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://e39source.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/unnamed.jpg" alt="Alt text">&lt;/p>
&lt;p> &lt;br/>&lt;br/>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Lesson Learned – Do Not Overfill the Cooling System. I described my experience changing the thermostat housing on my 1997 528i, but I did not describe the problem (a result of my mistake) that followed. As background, all the cars I previously worked on were older, and used a more antiquated cooling system design. “Back in the day”, the cooling system was filled directly into the radiator, and the radiator cap has a pressure relief valve built into it. Excess pressure and (important for this discussion) excess coolant vented from the system through a tube to either the ground or an atmospheric reservoir.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>BMW E39 528i: Front Control Arm Insight</title><link>https://www.e39source.com/blog/front-control-arm-insight/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.e39source.com/blog/front-control-arm-insight/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://e39source.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/2003_BMW_520i_ES_SE_Automatic_2.2_Front-1536x701.jpg" alt="Alt text">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I was experiencing a slight shimmy whenever I braked hard at speeds in excess of 40mph. It felt like brake judder, but was intermittent, not at low speed. When I jacked up the car, I could move the front left wheel toe-in/toe-out about a quarter of an inch. An inspection from underneath while my wife moved the wheel showed that the ball joint into the left knuckle was worn and moving. Figuring that if the left one was bad, the right one probably would fail soon, I replaced both.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>BMW E39 528i: Thermostat Housing DIY Insight</title><link>https://www.e39source.com/blog/thermostat-housing-diy-insight/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.e39source.com/blog/thermostat-housing-diy-insight/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://e39source.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/xqzslqkmg1msrrio6kph-1536x864.jpg" alt="Alt text">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Lesson Learned: at least on my 1997 528i sedan, the radiator shroud can be removed, and replaced, with the fan still installed on the fan clutch. I had to replace a leaky thermostat housing/radiator hose connector on my 1997 528i sedan. RealOEM.com indicates that two different radiator options were available on this vehicle. Mine is the one with the separate overflow tank on the passenger side of the radiator.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>BMW E39 Cup Holder Replacement DIY</title><link>https://www.e39source.com/blog/bmw-e39-cup-holder-replacement-diy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.e39source.com/blog/bmw-e39-cup-holder-replacement-diy/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://e39source.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/E39-Cup-Holder-Replacement.jpg" alt="Alt text">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Today I installed replacement cup holders into my E39 540i/6. The following is a quick tutorial on how to do the same to your E39!&lt;/p>
&lt;p> &lt;br/>&lt;br/>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Objective:&lt;/strong> Replace broken cup holders which no longer stay closed.&lt;/p>
&lt;p> &lt;br/>&lt;br/>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Applicable Vehicles:&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1996-2003 BMW E39 5-series: 520i, 523i, 525i, 528i, 530i, 535i, 540i, M5.&lt;/p>
&lt;p> &lt;br/>&lt;br/>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Parts required:&lt;/strong> &lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=1vz0CwG/oc8&amp;amp;mid=43304&amp;amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.ecstuning.com%2FSearch%2FSiteSearch%2F51168190205%2F">51168190205&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p> &lt;br/>&lt;br/>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Cost:&lt;/strong> $30-$100&lt;/p>
&lt;p> &lt;br/>&lt;br/>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Difficulty:&lt;/strong> Very Low&lt;/p>
&lt;p> &lt;br/>&lt;br/>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Time Required:&lt;/strong> 5-10 minutes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p> &lt;br/>&lt;br/>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Procedure:&lt;/strong> To see how to do this for yourself, watch the embedded video below!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>BMW E39 Headliner Replacement DIY</title><link>https://www.e39source.com/blog/bmw-e39-headliner-replacement-diy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.e39source.com/blog/bmw-e39-headliner-replacement-diy/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://e39source.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/IMG_4272.jpg" alt="Alt text">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I recently replaced the headliner in my E39 540i/6 with the Alcantara headliner exclusive to the E39 M5, and here is how I did it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p> &lt;br/>&lt;br/>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Objective:&lt;/strong> Remove and reinstall the headliner.&lt;/p>
&lt;p> &lt;br/>&lt;br/>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Applicable Vehicles:&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1996-2003 BMW E39 5-series: 520i, 523i, 525i, 528i, 530i, 535i, 540i, M5.&lt;/p>
&lt;p> &lt;br/>&lt;br/>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Parts required:&lt;/strong> Replacement headliner, hardware inn color of choice.&lt;/p>
&lt;p> &lt;br/>&lt;br/>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Cost:&lt;/strong> $100-$750&lt;/p>
&lt;p> &lt;br/>&lt;br/>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Difficulty:&lt;/strong> Moderate.&lt;/p>
&lt;p> &lt;br/>&lt;br/>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Time Required:&lt;/strong> 4-6 hours.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>BMW E39 M5 Camshaft Position Sensors</title><link>https://www.e39source.com/blog/bmw-e39-m5-camshaft-position-sensors/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.e39source.com/blog/bmw-e39-m5-camshaft-position-sensors/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://e39source.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/S62.png" alt="Alt text">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It’s always something, right? Usually electrical sensors are the most prominent, annoying, and expensive problems we have with these cars, and this only perpetuates this theory. Own an E39 M5 for long enough, and you’ll end up having to replace the cam sensors.&lt;/p>
&lt;p> &lt;br/>&lt;br/>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>What is a Camshaft Position Sensor?&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Let’s start with a camshaft. Put basically, the camshaft is responsible for opening and closing intake and exhaust valves in a combustion engine. A camshaft position sensor senses the position of the camshaft as it revolves, reporting back to the VANOS (variable intake and exhaust valve timing system) telling it where the camshaft sits. This all enhances performance, efficiency, and overall smoothness of the engine. Since the M5’s engine is a ‘V’8, there are two cylinder banks, and thus four camshafts. Each cylinder bank has one intake, and one exhaust camshaft. Each camshaft has a CPS (camshaft position sensor). This brings the total to four CPS, two intake, and two exhaust.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>BMW E39 M5: Floor/Trunk Mats</title><link>https://www.e39source.com/blog/trunk-mats/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.e39source.com/blog/trunk-mats/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://e39source.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/IMG_7047.jpg" alt="Alt text">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Really Ryan, a post about floor mats? Yeah. This article will identify the proper floor mat part numbers for our E39 M5s. Caramel and English Green are longer available, but black is; and BMW has recently updated it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p> &lt;br/>&lt;br/>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Winter&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Genuine BMW Black Rubber, Front: &lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=1vz0CwG/oc8&amp;amp;mid=43304&amp;amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.ecstuning.com%2Fb-genuine-bmw-parts%2Ffront-rubber-floor-mat-set-black%2F82550302997%2F">82550302997&lt;/a>
Other Brands and Options: &lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=1vz0CwG/oc8&amp;amp;mid=43304&amp;amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.ecstuning.com%2FBMW-E39-M5-S62_5.0L%2FInterior%2FFloor_Mats%2FRubber%2F">ECS Tuning&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p> &lt;br/>&lt;br/>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Summer&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Genuine BMW Black Carpet, Set of Four: &lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=1vz0CwG/oc8&amp;amp;mid=43304&amp;amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.ecstuning.com%2Fb-genuine-bmw-parts%2F--m-carpeted-floor-mats-anthracite-black%2F82110009046%2F">82110009046&lt;/a>
Other Brands and Options: &lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=1vz0CwG/oc8&amp;amp;mid=43304&amp;amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.ecstuning.com%2FBMW-E39-M5-S62_5.0L%2FInterior%2FFloor_Mats%2FCarpeted%2F">ECS Tuning&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p> &lt;br/>&lt;br/>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Caramel and English Green mats are no longer available new. I recommend that owners of cars with these interiors try the black mats; they prove to be much more practical than the lighter colors.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>BMW E39 M5: Front PDC Retrofit</title><link>https://www.e39source.com/blog/front-pdc-retrofit/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.e39source.com/blog/front-pdc-retrofit/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://e39source.com/wp-content/uploads/2010/05/IMG_7300.jpg" alt="Alt text">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For the 2000 model year, E39 M5s optioned with S508A Park Distance Control PDC included only 4 rear sensors. It wasn’t until the 2001 facelift that BMW added an additional 4 front sensors to the PDC option. This article and video content will detail how to retrofit the four front sensors to your 2000 BMW M5.&lt;/p>
&lt;p> &lt;br/>&lt;br/>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>This article is a supplement to the primary DIY video posted at the bottom of this article. Reference that video to see the steps in action and for a better visual explanation.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>BMW E39 M5: Must Have Mods</title><link>https://www.e39source.com/blog/must-have-mods/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.e39source.com/blog/must-have-mods/</guid><description>I bought my 2000 BMW M5 in 2010; it was my first car and I was 17 years old. Somehow, I didn’t kill myself. By 2011, the void of E39 M5 DIY content online made me think ‘If I want to see this content, maybe others would too.’ I decided to spearhead the lack of online content with E39Source. This has allowed me to connect with thousands of fellow E39 (M5) owners. Now after 12+ years of E39 M5 experience, I have come to know this platform quite well. For the first 8 years, I serviced my own vehicle. Since 2018, I have been offering my speciality E39 M5 services professionally at our shop located in San Diego, California&amp;hellip;</description></item><item><title>BMW E39, E38, E46: LED License Plate Lights</title><link>https://www.e39source.com/blog/bmw-e39-e38-e46-led-license-plate-lights/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.e39source.com/blog/bmw-e39-e38-e46-led-license-plate-lights/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://e39source.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/07/after.jpg" alt="Alt text">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>An easy and affordable way to modernize the rear of your BMW is to update your license plate lights. Prior to ~2011, BMW had used very yellow and dim lights to illuminate the rear tag. These days they’re using significantly brighter LEDs that produce a very crisp and white colored light. I installed these lights into my 2000 M5, and have been happy with the results. They do NOT trigger a ‘check warning’ on the dash.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>BMW E39: Automatic Headlight Retrofit</title><link>https://www.e39source.com/blog/automatic-headlight-retrofit/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.e39source.com/blog/automatic-headlight-retrofit/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="../img/IMG_0060.jpeg" alt="Alt Text">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For the 2002 model year (from 9/1/2001 production), BMWs came standard with automatic headlights. Five components need to be installed or replaced to bring this functionality to earlier models. This article details the steps that must be completed to retrofit automatic headlights. Additionally, please view the video at the bottom of this post for more detail.&lt;/p>
&lt;p> &lt;br/>&lt;br/>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Objective:&lt;/strong> Retrofit automatic headlights to a BMW E39 5-series.&lt;/p>
&lt;p> &lt;br/>&lt;br/>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Applicable Vehicles:&lt;/strong> 1997-2001 BMW E39 5-series: 520i, 523i, 525i, 528i, 530i, 535i, 540i, M5. Information from this article can also be applied to the 1994-2001 BMW E38 7-series: 730i, 740i, 740iL, 750iL, the E53 BMW X5, and the 1999-2006 BMW E46 3-series: 323i, 325i, 328i, 330i, M3.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>BMW E39: Corner Sunshade Replacement</title><link>https://www.e39source.com/blog/bmw-e39-corner-sunshade-replacement/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.e39source.com/blog/bmw-e39-corner-sunshade-replacement/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://e39source.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/12/Sunshade1.png" alt="Alt text">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This article will detail the removal and re-installation of the corner sunshade on the rear doors of the E39 5-series.&lt;/p>
&lt;p> &lt;br/>&lt;br/>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Objective:&lt;/strong> This article will detail the removal and re-installation of the corner sunshade on the rear doors of the E39 5-series.&lt;/p>
&lt;p> &lt;br/>&lt;br/>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Applicable Vehicles:&lt;/strong> 1996-2003 BMW E39 5-series: 520i, 523i, 525i, 528i, 530i, 535i, 540i, M5.&lt;/p>
&lt;p> &lt;br/>&lt;br/>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Parts required:&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Left Corner Sunshade: &lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=1vz0CwG/oc8&amp;amp;mid=43304&amp;amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.ecstuning.com%2Fb-genuine-bmw-parts%2Frear-sun-shade-left%2F51167110205%2F">51167110205&lt;/a>
Right Corner Sunshade: &lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=1vz0CwG/oc8&amp;amp;mid=43304&amp;amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.ecstuning.com%2Fb-genuine-bmw-parts%2Frear-sun-shade-right%2F51167110206%2F">51167110206&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p> &lt;br/>&lt;br/>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Difficulty:&lt;/strong> Low&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>BMW E39: Europe vs North America</title><link>https://www.e39source.com/blog/europe_vs_north_america/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.e39source.com/blog/europe_vs_north_america/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="../img/IMG_3639.jpeg" alt="Europe vs North America 1">&lt;/p>
&lt;p> &lt;br/>&lt;br/>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is a post that may continue to grow and evolve. There are countless variations between BMWs produced and sold in the European market vs those sold here, in the US / North American (DE93) market. This article will highlight some of those differences.&lt;/p>
&lt;p> &lt;br/>&lt;br/>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Hyperlinks in this article will point to more E39Source content about installing or retrofitting some of these components.&lt;/p>
&lt;p> &lt;br/>&lt;br/>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>BMW E39: Facelift Lighting</title><link>https://www.e39source.com/blog/facelift-lighting/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.e39source.com/blog/facelift-lighting/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://e39source.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/M5.jpg" alt="Alt text">&lt;/p>
&lt;p> &lt;br/>&lt;br/>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BMW made constant changes to the E39 throughout production. I detail the majority of these changes &lt;a href="https://e39source.com/archives/1848">this article&lt;/a>. Some of the most noticeable differences are in the lighting elements. The 2001 facelift brought new headlights, fog lights, and tail lights to the E39. This article will detail the upgrade process from 1996-2000 lights to 2001+ lights.&lt;/p>
&lt;p> &lt;br/>&lt;br/>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There is a right way and a wrong way to go about this. If you use Ebay to search for E39 headlights and tail lights, you will find several significantly cheaper alternatives to what I recommend using. To anybody that knows BMWs, the cheap lights will be quickly recognized as fake and gaudy. I made the mistake of installing Depo headlights on my M5 many years ago- I didn’t know better. They had writing all over the lenses, were not proportioned correctly, and had 5 individual LEDs in each halo ring, which were clearly visible at night. The OEM lights are so much more elegant, provide a smoother, more even light, and are significantly more expensive. You get what you pay for.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>BMW E39: Facelift Steering Wheel Upgrade</title><link>https://www.e39source.com/blog/facelift-steering-wheel-upgrade/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.e39source.com/blog/facelift-steering-wheel-upgrade/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://e39source.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/01/IMG_2978.jpg" alt="Alt text">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For 2001, BMW gave the E39 M5 the E46 M3 steering wheel. Before this, it had used the E36 M3’s wheel. The newer wheel looks a lot more modern and feels much more sporty due to it’s thicker girth, and more pronounced side bolsters. The E46 wheel also allows you to finally see both the top of the gauges and the cluster LCD display at the same time! Depending on when your E39 was made, this update process can be super easy, or damn near impossible. Let’s get to it.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>BMW E39: HVAC Panel Facelift</title><link>https://www.e39source.com/blog/hvac-panel-facelift/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.e39source.com/blog/hvac-panel-facelift/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="../img/541B-1536x1152.jpg" alt="Alt text">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is a minor item to facelift, but it was included in the E39 2001 model year refresh nonetheless. From 9/00 production, BMW replaced the REST button with a MAX AC button. But fear not, REST functionality is not lost! This article details how to properly retrofit the new HVAC panel and associated solar sensor.&lt;/p>
&lt;p> &lt;br/>&lt;br/>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Objective:&lt;/strong> Facelift HVAC panel to add MAX AC button and functionality.&lt;/p>
&lt;p> &lt;br/>&lt;br/>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>BMW E39: M52, M54 Spark Plug Replacement</title><link>https://www.e39source.com/blog/bmw-e39-m52-m54-spark-plug-replacement/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.e39source.com/blog/bmw-e39-m52-m54-spark-plug-replacement/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://e39source.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/Photo-Feb-16-4-27-53-PM.jpg" alt="Alt text">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Today I installed new spark plugs into my E39 525iA. The following is a quick tutorial on how to do the same to your E39!&lt;/p>
&lt;p> &lt;br/>&lt;br/>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Objective:&lt;/strong> Replace the spark plugs in your vehicle, helping it run better and more effeciently.&lt;/p>
&lt;p> &lt;br/>&lt;br/>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Applicable Vehicles:&lt;/strong> 1996-2003 BMW E39 5-series with 6 cylinder engines: 520i, 523i, 525i, 528i, 530i.&lt;/p>
&lt;p> &lt;br/>&lt;br/>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Parts Required:&lt;/strong> 6 OEM, Bosch, or NGK (&lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=1vz0CwG/oc8&amp;amp;mid=43304&amp;amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.ecstuning.com%2Fb-ngk-parts%2Fspark-plugs-set-of-six%2Fbkr6equp-space-6%2F">What I used&lt;/a>) spark plugs.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>BMW E39: Navigation System Upgrades: (Computer, Display, Software, Maps)</title><link>https://www.e39source.com/blog/nav-guide/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.e39source.com/blog/nav-guide/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="../img/IMG_1.jpg" alt="Nav Guide Image">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In this article, I discuss in detail the steps, hardware, and software required to upgrade your BMW’s navigation computer, display, software, and maps. The information in this article is only applicable to BMWs that speak the same electronics ‘language’. Many BMW models and series speak this same language, utilize the same connectors, and make use of the same hardware-software interface.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Applicable Vehicles:&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>E38 7-series (1994-2001) &lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>E46 3-series (1999-2006) &lt;/p></description></item><item><title>BMW E39: P0443/Evap Code Diagnosis</title><link>https://www.e39source.com/blog/evap-code-diagnosis/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.e39source.com/blog/evap-code-diagnosis/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://e39source.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/07/Yk4SXyaz1hWT.jpg" alt="Alt text">&lt;/p>
&lt;p> &lt;br/>&lt;br/>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I just bought my 1998 BMW 540i two weeks ago, and I knew when I bought it that there was a check engine light on for an EVAP code. I pulled the code and it came up as P0443. I just wanted to outline a short diagnostic checklist of things to check when you experience this or any other EVAP code related to the purge valve.&lt;/p>
&lt;p> &lt;br/>&lt;br/>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>BMW E39: Shift Knob Replacement</title><link>https://www.e39source.com/blog/shift-nob-replacement/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.e39source.com/blog/shift-nob-replacement/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://e39source.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/12/Shift-Knob.png" alt="Alt text">&lt;/p>
&lt;p> &lt;br/>&lt;br/>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The shifter is one of the most touched parts of the vehicle. If you own your 5-series long enough, you will probably want to replace it. What are the correct part numbers? Which one does your vehicle need? How do you change it?&lt;/p>
&lt;p> &lt;br/>&lt;br/>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Objective:&lt;/strong> This article will detail the replacement of the manual shift knob found in a BMW E39 5-series. A video of wiring an M5 shift knob is embedded at the bottom, as well as wiring an M shift knob into a non-M BMW.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>BMW E39: SIRIUS XM, Aux Input, BM53 Radio Retrofit</title><link>https://www.e39source.com/blog/sirius-xm/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.e39source.com/blog/sirius-xm/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="../img/IMG_3169.jpeg" alt="E39 SIRIUS XM, Aux, Radio 1">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Welcome to what is going to be a very thorough and detailed article. I am going to break down exactly what you need to do to retrofit a BM53 Radio, Auxiliary Input, and SIRIUS XM radio into your BMW E39 5-series. All of the components used in this DIY are Genuine BMW. No Chinese aftermarket garbage head units here!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>DISCLOSURE: This post may contain affiliate links, meaning when you click the links and make a purchase, we receive a commission.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>BMW E39: Trunk Carpet Replacement</title><link>https://www.e39source.com/blog/bmw-e39-trunk-carpet-replacement/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.e39source.com/blog/bmw-e39-trunk-carpet-replacement/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://e39source.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_2840.jpg" alt="Alt text">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Today I installed very lightly used carpeting into the trunk of my 2001 BMW 540i/6. The carpeting that was in the vehicle was in very poor condition due to abuse and lack of knowledge by the previous owner.&lt;/p>
&lt;p> &lt;br/>&lt;br/>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Objective:&lt;/strong> Refresh the look of your trunk area.&lt;/p>
&lt;p> &lt;br/>&lt;br/>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Applicable Vehicles:&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1996-2003 BMW E39 5-series: 520i, 523i, 525i, 528i, 530i, 535i, 540i, M5.&lt;/p>
&lt;p> &lt;br/>&lt;br/>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Parts required:&lt;/strong> Replacement carpet panels.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>BMW E39: Trunk Escape Handle Retrofit</title><link>https://www.e39source.com/blog/trunck-escape-handle-retrofit/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.e39source.com/blog/trunck-escape-handle-retrofit/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://e39source.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/IMG_1227.jpeg" alt="Alt text">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For the 2002 model year (from 9/1/2001 production), the BMW E39 came standard with an emergency trunk release handle. Six components need to be installed or replaced to bring this feature to older E39s. This article details the steps that must be completed in order to retrofit the emergency release handle. Please see the video at the bottom of this post as well.&lt;/p>
&lt;p> &lt;br/>&lt;br/>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Objective&lt;/strong>: Retrofit emergency trunk release handle to a BMW E39 5-series.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>BMW E39: Trunk Release Handle Replacement</title><link>https://www.e39source.com/blog/bmw-e39-trunk-release-handle-replacement/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.e39source.com/blog/bmw-e39-trunk-release-handle-replacement/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://e39source.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/TrunkRelease.jpg" alt="Alt text">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Today I replaced the trunk release pushbutton in my 2001 540i/6. Here is how I did it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p> &lt;br/>&lt;br/>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Objective:&lt;/strong> Replace the trunk release pushbutton due to deteriorated rubber covering failing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p> &lt;br/>&lt;br/>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Applicable Vehicles:&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1996-2003 BMW E39 5-series: 520i, 523i, 525i, 528i, 530i, 535i, 540i, M5.&lt;/p>
&lt;p> &lt;br/>&lt;br/>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Parts required:&lt;/strong> Release Handle &lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=1vz0CwG/oc8&amp;amp;mid=43304&amp;amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.ecstuning.com%2Fb-genuine-bmw-parts%2Ftrunk-lock-push-button%2F51248168035%2F">51248168035&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p> &lt;br/>&lt;br/>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Cost:&lt;/strong> $85&lt;/p>
&lt;p> &lt;br/>&lt;br/>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Difficulty:&lt;/strong> Low&lt;/p>
&lt;p> &lt;br/>&lt;br/>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Time Required:&lt;/strong> 15 minutes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p> &lt;br/>&lt;br/>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Procedure:&lt;/strong> To see how to do this for yourself, watch the embedded video below!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>BMW E39: Trunk Tools</title><link>https://www.e39source.com/blog/trunk-tools/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.e39source.com/blog/trunk-tools/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="../img/bmw_toolkit_labelled.jpeg" alt="Alt text">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This post lists all of the parts that can be fitted to the E39’s trunk tool kit. Not all of these tools were included for the DE93 (North American) market cars. Specifically, we didn’t receive tools A, I, or J.&lt;/p>
&lt;p> &lt;br/>&lt;br/>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>TOOL,	PART NUMBER,	DESCRIPTION:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>KIT	&lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=1vz0CwG/oc8&amp;amp;mid=43304&amp;amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.ecstuning.com%2Fb-genuine-bmw-parts%2Ftool-box%2F71111182774%2F">71111180684&lt;/a>	Tool kit case pre-facelift (NLA)	production ended 11/22/2001&lt;/p>
&lt;p>KIT	&lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=1vz0CwG/oc8&amp;amp;mid=43304&amp;amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.ecstuning.com%2Fb-genuine-bmw-parts%2Ftool-box%2F71111182774%2F">71111182774&lt;/a>	Tool kit case facelift	production started 09/1995&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A	&lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=1vz0CwG/oc8&amp;amp;mid=43304&amp;amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.ecstuning.com%2Fb-genuine-european-bmw-parts%2Fwarning-triangle-with-container-no-longer-available%2F71601092427%7Eoee%2F">71601092427&lt;/a>	Warning triangle with container (NLA)	production ended 05/2000&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>BMW E39: Wireless Charging</title><link>https://www.e39source.com/blog/wireless-charging/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.e39source.com/blog/wireless-charging/</guid><description>In this article, we’ll discuss the required parts and procedures to retrofit wireless phone charging to your BMW E39 5-series. That’s right- a feature not available on many modern BMWs- in your 20+ year old one. And the best part? The parts cost less than $35. Be sure to watch the embedded YouTube video below, which shows these steps in more detail.</description></item><item><title>BMW Initiates Recall For Over 780,000 Vehicles</title><link>https://www.e39source.com/blog/bmw-initiates-recall-for-over-780000-vehicles/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.e39source.com/blog/bmw-initiates-recall-for-over-780000-vehicles/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://e39source.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/bmw-recall-feat.png" alt="Alt text">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BMW has initiated a recall for several models, more than 780,000 vehicles worldwide, in countries such as Canada, Japan, South Africa, and the United States. There is a problem with the positive battery cable; the tin on the connector may degrade over time, causing electrical problems, stalling, or even a complete loss of power while the vehicle is in motion. The affected vehicles include: 1 Series coupes and convertibles (both 128i and 135i) from the 2008 to 2011 model years; 3 Series sedans, coupes, convertibles and sport wagons (both 328i and 335i) from the 2007 to 2012 model years; and Z4 roadsters from the 2009 model year to present date.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>BMW M50/M52: Intake Modification</title><link>https://www.e39source.com/blog/m52-intake-modification/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.e39source.com/blog/m52-intake-modification/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://e39source.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/06/WP_20160504_005.jpg" alt="Alt text">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>With this modification, your M52B25 or M52B28 engine will make more power. The M52B25 and M52B28 engines can be found in the E36, E39, E38, and in some early E46 models. This is not the easiest modification, but if you are at least a little bit handy, it is not difficult. Some people say that this will gain an additional 20HP, while some say it won’t give you any. I believe that there are power benefits.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>BMW M52 I6: Serpentine Belt DIY</title><link>https://www.e39source.com/blog/serpentine-belt-diy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.e39source.com/blog/serpentine-belt-diy/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://e39source.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/pic01.jpg" alt="Alt text">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A serpentine, or accessory belt, is a part shared by all internal combustion piston engines. Knowing how to replace one would be a valuable skill for anyone to have. This article walks the reader through each step required to replace either the serpentine or AC belt on the BMW M52 inline 6-cylinder engine.&lt;/p>
&lt;p> &lt;br/>&lt;br/>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This post was submitted to E39Source by Brian M&lt;/p>
&lt;p> &lt;br/>&lt;br/>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Objective:&lt;/strong> Replace serpentine belt and/or AC belt on M52 I6 powered BMW.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>BMW N54 Tuning &amp; Maintenance Guide</title><link>https://www.e39source.com/blog/bmw-n54-tuning--maintenance-guide/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.e39source.com/blog/bmw-n54-tuning--maintenance-guide/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://e39source.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/BMW-N54-twin-turbo-I6_1200x1200.jpg" alt="Alt text">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Over the past few years, the N54 twin turbo 3.0 lite inline-6 has gained the reputation of being an easily tunable and powerful engine. With the N54 aging and the increasing number of modifications available, we are bound to begin seeing more blown engines and turbos. Although the block and internals are very strong, the N54 is prone to issues without the proper maintenance and repairs. Whether your N54 is stock or running a large single turbo set up, this guide will ensure your engine is running at its best.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>BMW Removes Manual Transmission From 5-Series</title><link>https://www.e39source.com/blog/bmw-removes-manual-transmission-from-5-series/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.e39source.com/blog/bmw-removes-manual-transmission-from-5-series/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://e39source.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/11/6mt.jpg" alt="Alt text">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Roughly a month ago, I was on BMW USA’s website and noticed the manual gearbox was removed from the F10 5 series. The standard gearbox is now the 8 speed auto (sigh) or there is the sport automatic transmission for an extra $500. When a manual gearbox is removed from a fine tuned driving instrument, a part of its soul has been removed.Thankfully the manual is still available on the 3 series (probably for a short time) and on the M series line up. Yes, I know that modern automatics are more reliable, get exceptional fuel economy and offer extremely quick shifts, however, if the reader shares the same views as I and believes a car should have, engine at the front, manual gearbox in the middle, and drive at the back, then what are we as driving aficionados to do. I suppose we could buy a used F10, E60, E39, and I guess manual gearboxes are becoming a thing of the past.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>BMW Swirl Scratch Removal</title><link>https://www.e39source.com/blog/bmw-swirl-scratch-removal/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.e39source.com/blog/bmw-swirl-scratch-removal/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://e39source.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/IMG_4186.jpg" alt="Alt text">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Here is how I removed the swirl scratches and replenished the finish on the hood of 540i/6.&lt;/p>
&lt;p> &lt;br/>&lt;br/>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Objective:&lt;/strong> Buff out shallow scratches in the clear coat.&lt;/p>
&lt;p> &lt;br/>&lt;br/>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Applicable Vehicles:&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>All clear-coated vehicles.&lt;/p>
&lt;p> &lt;br/>&lt;br/>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Parts required:&lt;/strong> Zaino Z2, Z5, Z8, and Z18.&lt;/p>
&lt;p> &lt;br/>&lt;br/>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Cost:&lt;/strong> $100&lt;/p>
&lt;p> &lt;br/>&lt;br/>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Difficulty:&lt;/strong> Medium&lt;/p>
&lt;p> &lt;br/>&lt;br/>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Time Required:&lt;/strong> Depends on how you want to do it!&lt;/p>
&lt;p> &lt;br/>&lt;br/>&lt;/p>
&lt;div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
 &lt;iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share; fullscreen" loading="eager" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/VZ0vzL-b28w?autoplay=0&amp;amp;controls=1&amp;amp;end=0&amp;amp;loop=0&amp;amp;mute=0&amp;amp;start=0" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" title="YouTube video">&lt;/iframe>
 &lt;/div>

&lt;p> &lt;br/>&lt;br/>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>BMW Wheel Center Caps</title><link>https://www.e39source.com/blog/wheel-center-caps/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.e39source.com/blog/wheel-center-caps/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://e39source.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/IMG_0424-1-1024x668.jpg" alt="Alt text">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For the 2003 model year, BMW facelift the wheel center caps for the E39 M5. This new version looks more like the hood/trunk lid badge. Gone is the gray plastic bezel and in is a nice chrome ring. The plastic feels better, the badge is a hair bigger, and these new components seem to withstand the test of time better.&lt;/p>
&lt;p> &lt;br/>&lt;br/>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Objective:&lt;/strong> Update or refresh the look of your wheels with the new-style BMW wheel center caps.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>BMW’s Bastard Child: My E36 318ti</title><link>https://www.e39source.com/blog/bmws-bastard-child-my-e36-318ti/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.e39source.com/blog/bmws-bastard-child-my-e36-318ti/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://e39source.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/11/Exterior.jpg" alt="Alt text">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Let’s keep things short, and get this started. I sold my E39 M5 at a good price, but I still miss it dearly. I’m in college studying engineering and pre-med, so I’m going to be in school for a long time. I don’t have the time anymore for photo shoots, car washes and detailing all the time. I needed something cheap, reliable and plain; and it had to be a good project car for some great E39Source content. I decided to buy a Ti – it’s a big F-U to all the viewer’s that thought I was going to get something flashy, and worst of all, everybody hates how it looks.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Case Study: The Cost of Owning a BMW E39 M5</title><link>https://www.e39source.com/blog/the-cost-of-owning-a-bmw-e39-m5/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.e39source.com/blog/the-cost-of-owning-a-bmw-e39-m5/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://e39source.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/15874968_761549550662427_5807226607884989751_o-1536x1024.png" alt="Alt text">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Anybody can afford to buy a used BMW. But maintaining a used BMW is another story. After all, the most expensive car you every buy will probably be a cheap BMW. This is a case study of an E39 M5 owner after 9 years and 100,000 miles. So, what did that cost?&lt;/p>
&lt;p> &lt;br/>&lt;br/>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>1. The operating cost of the car is 53 Cents per mile.&lt;/strong> The average cost for a large sedan is 56 cents per mile (AAA 2018). You get that number by dividing total miles driven by everything you put into it, like gas, insurance, repairs, and the cost of the car when you bought it versus value if you sold it today (depreciation).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Charlie’s 2002 BMW 520i SE Introduction</title><link>https://www.e39source.com/blog/charlies-2002-bmw-520i-se-introduction/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.e39source.com/blog/charlies-2002-bmw-520i-se-introduction/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://e39source.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/01/DSC_0037.jpg" alt="Alt text">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Hi everyone, I’m really excited to share my new vehicle with you! I have always wanted a saloon, or sedan as you guys in the states call them. I am a tall guy, 6’7″, so trying to find the right vehicle is a pain! I have to find one first, and ask to sit in the car, which is always an awkward conversation. If I fit in it, then I know what to look for. I originally wanted something classy, like a Mercedes-Benz, but then I realized the costs of repair would be astronomical, and I really didn’t think at my age, 19, it would be very sensible. I then remembered how my step dad always loved his BMW. He had a 1999 3-series, and I loved it. He actually destroyed it by putting on big tires and stupid suspension, meaning that when you went round a bend, you could smell and hear the rubber burning on the wheel arch. That car though was the birth of my strong desire to own a BMW.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Christian’s 1999 540i Introduction</title><link>https://www.e39source.com/blog/christians-1999-540i-introduction/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.e39source.com/blog/christians-1999-540i-introduction/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://e39source.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/07/bmw4.jpg" alt="Alt text">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As far back as I can remember I have been obsessed with cars, and most recently that obsession has been channeled to my 1999 540i. My passion for cars is definitely in my family’s blood. My grandpa had a very strong interest in cars, some of which are some of the most beautiful cars from the 20th century in my opinion. These cars included a 1969 Signal Orange Porsche 911E, 1958 Blue Jaguar XK-140 convertible, 1968 Jaguar E-type convertible in Tan, and a 1966 Lincoln Continental convertible in Black with the suicide doors. Growing up around these cars gave me a solid understanding about cars and how awesome they can be.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Christian’s 2000 BMW E46 330ci</title><link>https://www.e39source.com/blog/christains-2000-bmw-e46-330ci/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.e39source.com/blog/christains-2000-bmw-e46-330ci/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://e39source.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/32792736756_149d324a3a.jpg" alt="Alt text">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Christian’s family had tried a BMW before- and it didn’t go well. What was so terrible about that first BMW? What is it about this E46 330ci that changed things? This is the story of Christian’s first car- a 2000 E46 finished in Oxford Green metallic.&lt;/p>
&lt;p> &lt;br/>&lt;br/>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I never thought I would say this, but I bought a BMW! Let me give that statement some context. BMW’s don’t have the best reputation in my family. My Dad owned a 2005 BMW E65 735i Sport from 2009-2010. “The most unreliable car I’ve ever owned”, in his words. It was a brilliant machine to drive, and was actually the very first car I drove prior to learning how to drive a manual. Cue the haters, but I am a partial lover of the infamous bangle-butt generation of the BMW 7. Something about it screams unparalleled practicality whilst also having supercomputer power. However, that was also the car’s achilles heel. The E65 was just stupidly complicated. My Father’s example had numerous problems with the iDrive system, engine timing chain components, and a large number of sensors that simply decided to go on strike and stop working for no apparent reason. As you could’ve guessed, this caused the car’s systems to go haywire. All those headaches from an (at the time) 5 year old with only 65,000km. This was supposed to be The Ultimate Driving Machine. What was I in for when I purchased my 16 year old, 110,000km 330ci? One word: bliss.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Colton’s 2001 BMW 540i Introduction</title><link>https://www.e39source.com/blog/coltons-2001-bmw-540i-introduction/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.e39source.com/blog/coltons-2001-bmw-540i-introduction/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://e39source.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/540_Driveway1.png" alt="Alt text">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On Thursday, September 6th, 2012 at 5:08am I turned the key to the first ignition slot on what would turn into one of the biggest decisions of my life thus far. Let me start from the beginning. I’ve always been interested in automobiles, ever since I was a young boy. I was the boy who had a box full of matchbox cars which I would drive around on the floor for hours imagining different scenarios. I had quite the imagination. As I grew older, I started to lean towards Ford trucks, mainly because my father had purchased a 2002 F-150 Super-crew. That truck was all I knew as far as vehicles were concerned, that was until I met a friend of mine: Ryan Schultz.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Compromise – Updates with Andrew and His 2000 M5</title><link>https://www.e39source.com/blog/compromise-updates-with-andrew-and-his-2000-m5/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.e39source.com/blog/compromise-updates-with-andrew-and-his-2000-m5/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://e39source.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/Screen-Shot-2012-12-15-at-5.17.27-PM.png" alt="Alt text">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I’ve had my M5 for about seven months now, but I have only driven it 2500 miles. That is plenty of time to get familiar with my vehicle, but not enough to determine it’s reliability. For example, when I went to top off the tank before putting my M5 back into storage, it threw an SES code on the cluster. I plugged in my cheap-o generic OBDII scanner, and it came up with a P1526 and P0022 code, “A” Camshaft Position Actuator Control Open Circuit Bank 2 and “A” Camshaft Position – Timing over-retarded (Bank 2) respectively. I had the same two related codes over the summer when I first got my car, and that was when I opened up my bank 2 VANOS solenoids to check their operation. I have now confirmed that I need an intake CPS (Camshaft Position Sensor), which I plan on doing in late May.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Contact</title><link>https://www.e39source.com/contact/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.e39source.com/contact/</guid><description>&lt;p>E39Source was founded in September, 2011 in Hudson, Ohio, and was inspired by the significant void of quality online BMW E39 content. Co-founder Ryan Schultz acquired his 2000 M5 in July, 2010, and has been creating informational and educational content since. In 2018, Ryan and E39Source re-located to San Diego, California where they currently use their brick-and-mortar facility to provide world-class BMW service and support.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To contact us, please fill out the form below.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Danny’s Imola 2000 BMW M5</title><link>https://www.e39source.com/blog/dannys-imola-2000-bmw-m5/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.e39source.com/blog/dannys-imola-2000-bmw-m5/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://e39source.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/06/M5_1.jpg" alt="Alt text">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I was contemplating doing a video of the car and recorded one only to realize that my spoken English isn’t what it once was (Swedish sing-a-song-accent haha) so I’ll make a written post of my recently acquired M5 instead. I found out about the car a few months ago via a friend and I loosely knew the previous owner before as I were childhood friends with his brother.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Daryl’s 2001 525i Introduction</title><link>https://www.e39source.com/blog/daryls-2001-525i-introduction/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.e39source.com/blog/daryls-2001-525i-introduction/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://e39source.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/09/E39-Project-021-1-of-1.jpg" alt="Alt text">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>G’day from sunny Brisbane, Queensland Australia! I’m Daryl, however I go by the online name Dodgy Haro on most car forums (clubroadster + club4AG) which I participate in. My car background is mainly JDM (previous AE86 and Na6 Miata owner amongst other cars) however I do appreciate European rides too and how they generally handle better on highways and don’t impart that plastic feeling you get from some Japanese cars. I’ve just taken delivery of my new (old) 2001 BMW E39 525i sedan in gorgeous Imola red about a week ago. She is a bit tatty cosmetic-wise however she is a diamond in the rough to my eyes.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Downloads</title><link>https://www.e39source.com/downloads/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.e39source.com/downloads/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="resources--downloads">Resources &amp;amp; Downloads&lt;/h1>
&lt;p> &lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="navigation-software--resources--e39-e38-e46-e53-e83-e52">NAVIGATION SOFTWARE &amp;amp; RESOURCES: E39, E38, E46, E53, E83, E52&lt;/h4>
&lt;p> 
&lt;a href="https://www.e39source.com/blog/nav-guide/">Link to BMW navigation article&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>MKIV: &lt;a href="https://www.dropbox.com/scl/fi/390kj9a8h5mptluaj2tsw/BMW-MKIV-V32-Stock.iso?rlkey=mpfutmy2t41n0o4l6ehis429v&amp;amp;dl=1">SW 4-1/00 (V32)&lt;/a> (Stock BMW software)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>MKIV: &lt;a href="https://www.dropbox.com/scl/fi/9upwz9ibhfo5jljufpsi9/BMW-MKIV-V32-Modified.zip?rlkey=5cq80yspdplwutoceun9laoa8&amp;amp;dl=1">SW 4-1/00 (V32)&lt;/a> (Modified version: ///M logo splash, night mode color 2, speed camera alerts, warning auto-accept)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>MKIII: &lt;a href="https://www.dropbox.com/scl/fi/qjfekv1j07ljgbzw2pksm/BMW-MKIII-V23-M2F1.zip?rlkey=28k1cgj6eimjdwu49h3jzcjk8&amp;amp;dl=1">SW 3-1/65 (V23)&lt;/a> (Modified version: ///M logo splash, warning auto-accept)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>MKIII: &lt;a href="https://www.dropbox.com/scl/fi/9pd3zt9zw4f63pgslv98j/BMW-MKIII-Key-CD.zip?rlkey=c85ui85m5ueolfn698ry52cs1&amp;amp;dl=1">Key CD&lt;/a> (if needed)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.dropbox.com/scl/fi/3177ez8btb3uab6yma31z/NavTweak.zip?rlkey=4j0a9k1abf2lyfvdtkfs0i155&amp;amp;dl=1">NavTweak&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.dropbox.com/scl/fi/iyiyrwk3bhpte02gnu9t7/NavSpeak.zip?rlkey=1psr8oon9w1mtobq7qjigxetz&amp;amp;dl=1">NavSpeak&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.dropbox.com/s/6zug7m8sj8pjxpl/Navigation%20Update%20Instructions%20Public.pdf?dl=1">Navigation Software Update Instructions&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.dropbox.com/s/xcb8scmkf90ljd7/BMW%20MKII%20Navigation%20Owners%20Manual.pdf?dl=1">BMW MKII Navigation Owners Manual&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.dropbox.com/s/01i2jhrb8tmpcbz/BMW%20MKIV%20Navigation%20Owners%20Manual.pdf?dl=1">BMW MKIV Navigation Owners Manual&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.dropbox.com/s/p2tkgapcxck5ejy/BMW%20Navigation%20Guide.pdf?dl=1">BMW Navigation Systems Guide&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p> &lt;/p></description></item><item><title>E39 M5 Engine Reliability</title><link>https://www.e39source.com/blog/engine-reliability/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.e39source.com/blog/engine-reliability/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="../img/IMG_1030.jpeg" alt="E39 Reliability">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Over the past 6 years, my team and I have serviced hundreds of E39 M5s (and a few Z8s!) I’ve also owned my M5 for 15 years and over 90,000 miles now. The S62 V8 can last 300,000 miles on original components. It can also fail at 40,000 miles. Thankfully, there seem to be many more instances of higher miles than lower. These are the primary weak points of the S62:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>E39 Production Changes</title><link>https://www.e39source.com/blog/production-changes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.e39source.com/blog/production-changes/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="../img/IMG_5648.png" alt="E39 Production Changes 1">&lt;/p>
&lt;p> &lt;br/>&lt;br/>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The BMW E39 5-series was produced from 09/1995-06/2003 for the 1996-2003 model years. In September of 2000, for the 2001 model year, BMW gave the E39 a facelift. This means that the E39 chassis was updated, renewed both technologically and aesthetically for a few more years of production. Even outside of the big 2001 facelift, things with the E39 changed each year. This article will summarize the changes BMW made to US-spec vehicles throughout the production run.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Fabien’s 2001 BMW Alpina B10 Introduction</title><link>https://www.e39source.com/blog/fabiens-2001-bmw-alpina-b10-introduction/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.e39source.com/blog/fabiens-2001-bmw-alpina-b10-introduction/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://e39source.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/04/31632002_CP_photo.jpeg" alt="Alt text">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The BMW E39 Alpina B10 V8 is based on the 540i. Restoration is on-going on this car. It is claimed to produce 347BHP and 450 Nm (332 lb/ft) of toque for the 4.6 M62B46 V8. The Alpina documentation specific to this car states power output to be 355BHP and 480 Nm (354 lb/ft). This example is from 2001, with extended Alpina leather, and the 19″ classic Alpina wheels.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hassan’s 2002 BMW 530iA Introduction</title><link>https://www.e39source.com/blog/hassans-2002-bmw-530ia-introduction/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.e39source.com/blog/hassans-2002-bmw-530ia-introduction/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://e39source.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/IMG_0962.jpg" alt="Alt text">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have always been really into cars; I can still remember my briefcase toy chest filled with hot wheels race cars. I used to love those things, I took them everywhere with me! The doctor’s office, on vacations, you name it, I always brought some little toy cars with me. I was a boy who loved cars, like many others. Like many little boys, I dreamed of driving a race car and going 300mph, and having the time of my life. Fast forward to March, 2012. I was behind the wheel of a 2002 BMW 530i, driving in a parking lot at no more than 5mph. I was very excited, and very nervous. It was my first time ever getting behind the wheel of a car and actually driving it. After some short practice time in parking lots, I hit the road with my dad.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ivor’s 2001 BMW 530i Introduction</title><link>https://www.e39source.com/blog/ivors-2001-bmw-530i-introduction/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.e39source.com/blog/ivors-2001-bmw-530i-introduction/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://e39source.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/11/3Gd3Fd3M25E95Kd5M5d62579040ac838c104d.jpg" alt="Alt text">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is my 2001 BMW 530i 5 speed. I bought this car in June of this year from a guy in Minnesota. I found the car on Craigslist, and bought it for $6,500, which was a great deal. I originally wanted an M5, but they were out of my price range, so I started looking for a 540i. After some research, I found out that the V8s are a pain to repair, and the MPGs are awful, so I decided to go for a 530i. I was specifically looking for a 530i with a manual box, which was difficult to find in South Dakota. After searching for about 3 weeks, I found this one. It met all of my criteria: facelift model with the angel eyes, 5 speed box, M bumpers, BBS style wheels, it just had my name written all over it! After about a week, it was finally in my driveway: my first BMW! Below are the pictures of it from the Craigslist ad.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Jackson’s 2002 BMW E39 M5 Introduction</title><link>https://www.e39source.com/blog/jacksons-2002-bmw-e39-m5-introduction/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.e39source.com/blog/jacksons-2002-bmw-e39-m5-introduction/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="../img/DSC_0082.jpeg" alt="Alt text">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Hello everyone, I hope winter is going well so far! I’ve been a long-time member on M5Board, and I thought I’d swing over to this neighborhood to check out the scene! It’s a great technical and video based site in my opinion. My name is Jackson, and I live all the way up in Minnesota, also known as a**hole in the winter.&lt;/p>
&lt;p> &lt;br/>&lt;br/>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To begin, I’ve always loved the E39 chassis. It was actually my first love as a child, and will always be my favorite platform on any automobile. I wouldn’t trade it for anything else. Once I was around more friends’ E39 M5s in college, I knew I wanted one, and set out to get a decent job, and start saving. Not more than a year and a half later, I found the right M5. True E39 enthusiasts WILL wait for the right car, and numerous nights have been spent awake going over all sorts of things that would come up. Color, accident history, condition, owner feedback, distance, etc. They were all obstacles on the checklist that I needed to cross off, and more times than not, my checklist was incomplete.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Jay’s 2000 BMW E39 M5</title><link>https://www.e39source.com/blog/jays-2000-bmw-e39-m5/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.e39source.com/blog/jays-2000-bmw-e39-m5/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://e39source.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/05/20160428_080940.jpg" alt="Alt text">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Hello E39Source! I am a new member to this website, and I wanted to get more involved with this close knit group of E39 enthusiasts. I just recently purchased my first M5! I bought it in Seattle, Washington with 148,000 miles on the clock. The interior is immaculate, along with the rest of the car. It honestly doesn’t feel as if it has covered 148,000 miles. I’ve driven upwards of ten M5s and this one takes the cake. It has plenty of get-up and go and, so far has none of the common E39 issues!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Josh’s 2001 530i Introduction</title><link>https://www.e39source.com/blog/joshs-2001-530i-introduction/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.e39source.com/blog/joshs-2001-530i-introduction/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://e39source.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/10/1.jpg" alt="Alt text">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Hello from Melbourne, Australia! My names Josh, i’m an automotive photographer and a mechanic. I like a plethora of cars but BMW has always been my number one. Thought I would give you all a bit of a background into my obsession with the BMW brand and an introduction to my E39. This post may get a bit long though, its a trip down memory lane for me right now 😛&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Kennan’s 2001 BMW 525i Introduction (Sold)</title><link>https://www.e39source.com/blog/kennans-2001-bmw-525i-introduction-sold/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.e39source.com/blog/kennans-2001-bmw-525i-introduction-sold/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://e39source.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/IMG_0194.jpg" alt="Alt text">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Germany has always meant a great deal to me for a variety of reasons. I admire the culture of the country, the passion in the pursuit of mechanical perfection, absolute efficiency and precision; these are just some of the stones that make up the foundation of what is the most stable country in all of Europe. Granted, my heart belongs to the Italians especially with cars, but there is a part of my soul that is tinted the colors that are all over this website.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Luke’s 2000 BMW M5</title><link>https://www.e39source.com/blog/lukes-2000-bmw-m5/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.e39source.com/blog/lukes-2000-bmw-m5/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://e39source.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/hjxmfmku8pjtnbfbpxvg.jpg" alt="Alt text">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Let me begin by saying that I may be slightly biased when it comes to my assured claim that the E39 M5 is the greatest sports sedan of all time. While there are many other remarkable performance sedans out there (E28 M5, E34 M5, W211 E55, C5 RS6, and countless others), the E39 has held a special place in my heart from a young age. Not many other sedans have aged as gracefully and the E39 M5 represents the perfect blend between past and present in the M5 lineage. While its performance is not as remarkably impressive by today’s standards, the E39 M5 blends the right amount of driver involvement with refinement.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Maintaining a Vintage BMW</title><link>https://www.e39source.com/blog/maintaining-a-vintage-bmw/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.e39source.com/blog/maintaining-a-vintage-bmw/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://e39source.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/Screen-Shot-2017-08-31-at-1.50.20-AM.png" alt="Alt text">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You’ve probably heard about the incredible story of the M1 that was found sitting in a garage in Italy for 34 years. But in case you need a refresher, it’s the 1981 production model that had only clocked 4,600 miles before being put in storage by its owner. Then last year, the vintage car specialists at Mint Classics discovered the automobile in its poor state. Fortunately it wasn’t too late, so now it’s being returned to its former glory.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Mike’s E39 528i &amp; M5 Introduction</title><link>https://www.e39source.com/blog/mikes-e39-528i-and-m5-indroduction/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.e39source.com/blog/mikes-e39-528i-and-m5-indroduction/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://e39source.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/26350336544_98285c3d7d_o.jpg" alt="Alt text">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Hey guys, thanks for welcoming me to E39source! I’ve been a YouTube subscriber for quite a while now, and actually met some of you at the Pittsburgh Vintage Grand Prix last summer. My name is Mike, and I’m 25 years old and live/work in West Chester, PA. I currently have two E39s: a 1997 528i, and a 2000 M5.&lt;/p>
&lt;p> &lt;br/>&lt;br/>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My 528i is a 3/96 build, with almost 305k miles on it now. This was my first car, and I’ve owned it for over 8 years and 60k miles now! I’ve done so much maintenance to this car, most notably the top end rebuild that was done at 275k miles due to a leaking head gasket. At the time the head gasket was replaced, all seals in top end were replaced, along with the addition of S52 cams and Raceland headers. I also fitted a new radiator and water pump. This is an automatic-transmission car, and as far as I know, the transmission fluid is still original. The engine is the original M52 as well. As far as mods go, I’ve done quite a bit to this car to make it my own. Performance wise I already mentioned the S52 cams and headers but this winter I’m going to have a Supersprint resonator delete, and a Vibrant muffler installed.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Products</title><link>https://www.e39source.com/products/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.e39source.com/products/</guid><description>&lt;script async
 src="https://js.stripe.com/v3/buy-button.js">
&lt;/script>








 



 


&lt;style>
 body {
 font-family: Arial, sans-serif;
 }
 .product-table {
 width: 100%;
 max-width: 900px;
 margin: auto;
 border-collapse: collapse;
 table-layout: fixed;
 }
 .product-table td {
 text-align: center;
 vertical-align: middle;
 padding: 15px;
 border-bottom: 1px solid #ddd;
 }
 .product-table img {
 width: 100%;
 max-width: 400px;
 height: auto;
 }
 .stripe-buy-button {
 width: 100px; 
 max-width: 100px; 
 padding: 0; 
 }
 @media (max-width: 600px) {
 .product-table, .product-table td {
 width: 100%;
 }
 .product-table img {
 max-width: 140px;
 }
 }
&lt;/style>

&lt;table class="table">
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>
 &lt;stripe-buy-button class="stripe-buy-button"
 buy-button-id="buy_btn_1OZJ1AHpTgo0eM7AO3tLW57M"
 publishable-key="pk_live_51OXBaaHpTgo0eM7ANWlWru9BjVXHCdxdRAb2tcn62lA36mBB3Gu3sW9RZIKdAJFef8VKhQyX64Il6uPpmslzpLyv00a9nkOyHB">
 &lt;/stripe-buy-button>
 &lt;/td>
 &lt;td>
 &lt;stripe-buy-button class="stripe-buy-button"
 buy-button-id="buy_btn_1OZJJRHpTgo0eM7Afb9UPGw4"
 publishable-key="pk_live_51OXBaaHpTgo0eM7ANWlWru9BjVXHCdxdRAb2tcn62lA36mBB3Gu3sW9RZIKdAJFef8VKhQyX64Il6uPpmslzpLyv00a9nkOyHB">
 &lt;/stripe-buy-button>
 &lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>
 &lt;stripe-buy-button class="stripe-buy-button"
 buy-button-id="buy_btn_1OZJM1HpTgo0eM7Am6yWfQhj"
 publishable-key="pk_live_51OXBaaHpTgo0eM7ANWlWru9BjVXHCdxdRAb2tcn62lA36mBB3Gu3sW9RZIKdAJFef8VKhQyX64Il6uPpmslzpLyv00a9nkOyHB">
 &lt;/stripe-buy-button>
 &lt;/td>
 &lt;td>
 &lt;stripe-buy-button class="stripe-buy-button"
 buy-button-id="buy_btn_1OZJOzHpTgo0eM7ANzBKkHPC"
 publishable-key="pk_live_51OXBaaHpTgo0eM7ANWlWru9BjVXHCdxdRAb2tcn62lA36mBB3Gu3sW9RZIKdAJFef8VKhQyX64Il6uPpmslzpLyv00a9nkOyHB">
 &lt;/stripe-buy-button>
 &lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 
 
 
 
&lt;/table></description></item><item><title>Restoration Project: Alpina B10 V8</title><link>https://www.e39source.com/blog/restoration-project-alpina-b10-v8/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.e39source.com/blog/restoration-project-alpina-b10-v8/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://e39source.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/04/31354076_CP_photo1.jpeg" alt="Alt text">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After two weeks of a detailed check-up at BMW Dubai (AED 4,000 or $1,100 USD) plus my additional instructions, I came to understand that the core of this car is healthy. The only big mechanical aspects are: front wishbones, rear wheel bearings suspensions (Alpina specific, will cost a fortune as I want genuine OEM only), the rubber disc connecting the gearbox output to the prop-shaft, and the spinning crankshaft joint. Also the AC/dynamo belts and steering are weak.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ryan’s 2003 BMW 530iA Introduction</title><link>https://www.e39source.com/blog/ryans-2003-bmw-530ia-introduction/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.e39source.com/blog/ryans-2003-bmw-530ia-introduction/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://e39source.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/02/IMG_7645.jpg" alt="Alt text">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For as long as I can remember, I’ve held a strong interest in cars, though my parents accredit that to a toy school bus I had as a toddler. After I turned four, I would point to cars on the road and ask my dad what they were. His limited automotive knowledge meant that every SUV was a Jeep to me; everything else was a mishmash. Through clipping pictures of nice cars out of magazines, collecting Hot Wheels sized cars, and reading the undercarriage for the label, I started to form a vague understanding of what I was seeing on the road.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Service</title><link>https://www.e39source.com/service/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.e39source.com/service/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="e39source-is-proud-to-offer-the-following-services-and-more">E39Source is proud to offer the following services and more:&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Pre-Purchase Inspections / Multi-Point Inspections.&lt;br/>&lt;br/>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>BMW S62/M62/M62TU Timing Chains &amp;amp; Guides&lt;br/>&lt;br/>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Mechanical and Cosmetic Restorations&lt;br/>&lt;br/>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>SMG to Manual Transmission Conversions (E60 M5, E63/E64 M6)&lt;br/>&lt;br/>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Performance Software Upgrades&lt;br/>&lt;br/>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Engine Diagnostic &amp;amp; Repair&lt;br/>&lt;br/>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Oil Changes &amp;amp; Tune-Ups&lt;br/>&lt;br/>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fluid Flushes&lt;br/>&lt;br/>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Brake Service&lt;br/>&lt;br/>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Check / Service Light Diagnostics&lt;br/>&lt;br/>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Transmissions, Flywheels &amp;amp; Clutches&lt;br/>&lt;br/>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Suspension &amp;amp; Steering&lt;br/>&lt;br/>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Driveline&lt;br/>&lt;br/>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fuel System&lt;br/>&lt;br/>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Cooling System&lt;br/>&lt;br/>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Battery, Alternator &amp;amp; Starter&lt;br/>&lt;br/>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Body, Chassis &amp;amp; Interior&lt;br/>&lt;br/>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>BMW Factory Scheduled Maintenance Service&lt;br/>&lt;br/>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>BMW Inspections 1 &amp;amp; 2&lt;br/>&lt;br/>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Safety Inspections&lt;br/>&lt;br/>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Exhaust Systems&lt;br/>&lt;br/>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>BMW Connecting-Rod Bearings&lt;br/>&lt;br/>
 &lt;br/>&lt;br/>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p> &lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Shit E39 Owners Say</title><link>https://www.e39source.com/blog/shit-e39-owners-say/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.e39source.com/blog/shit-e39-owners-say/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://e39source.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/09/IMG_27631.jpg" alt="Alt text">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We thought it may be rather amusing to put together a little video dedicated to BMW E39 owners. The three of us, listed below, are all E39Source owners and E39 M5 Owners. We hope you enjoy watching this video and guarantee that some of these things will sound familiar to you as a BMW/E39 owner!&lt;/p>
&lt;p> &lt;br/>&lt;br/>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ryan Schultz, &lt;a href="http://e39source.com/archives/187">2000 M5&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Kennan Rolsen, &lt;a href="http://e39source.com/archives/1011">2001 525i/5&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Andrew Chow, &lt;a href="http://e39source.com/archives/364">2000 M5 (sold)&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p> &lt;br/>&lt;br/>&lt;/p>
&lt;div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
 &lt;iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share; fullscreen" loading="eager" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Yup5pvC5BHs?autoplay=0&amp;amp;controls=1&amp;amp;end=0&amp;amp;loop=0&amp;amp;mute=0&amp;amp;start=0" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" title="YouTube video">&lt;/iframe>
 &lt;/div>

&lt;p> &lt;br/>&lt;br/>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Tanvir’s 2003 BMW M5 Information</title><link>https://www.e39source.com/blog/tanvirs-2003-bmw-m5-information/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.e39source.com/blog/tanvirs-2003-bmw-m5-information/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://e39source.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/07/My-M3-Close-front-after..jpg" alt="Alt text">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My story starts a little differently than others. It starts 13 years ago… with a different kind of BMW than the one that I now own. One that, in my opinion, is by far the finest thing to come from Germany in a very long time… The E30 M3. I owned that icon for 11 memorable years, and still marvel that I was fortunate enough to own something so pure in it’s DNA, something that rewarded your driver input, and never punished you when you got it wrong. But, as this is a post about the E39 M5 I now have, let’s fast forward to November, 2010.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Ultimate Car Detailing: Zaino</title><link>https://www.e39source.com/blog/the-ultimate-car-detailing-zaino/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.e39source.com/blog/the-ultimate-car-detailing-zaino/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://e39source.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/IMG_3282-1.png" alt="Alt text">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It’s a guy thing. In the garage or shop of any car enthusiast, you’re likely to find dozens of car products. Soaps, tire shines, glass cleaners, leather conditioners, assorted towels, brushes, sponges, etc. We like to spend our weekends polishing our cars, even if they only go back in the garage directly afterwards. For some reason, it’s a therapeutic process. Like any process, there are dozens of ways to go about it. With automotive detailing, there are millions of ways to do it wrong. Waxing and polishing products are tools, and like any tool, they are only productively effective when used correctly. Zaino products are my tools of choice. This article is designed to detail the correct way to complete the Zaino wax process on your vehicle, and then maintain all of your hard work.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Tyler’s 1993 BMW 325iS Information</title><link>https://www.e39source.com/blog/tylers-1993-bmw-325is-information/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.e39source.com/blog/tylers-1993-bmw-325is-information/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://e39source.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/Tyler-325is1.png" alt="Alt text">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My story with my E36 is one of passion, heartbreak, persistence, hard work, and courage. That may sound a bit like the makings of a shoddy Lifetime movie, but I promise you this will be more entertaining than that. In my mind, this article is going to sound like something from Dan Neil in the WSJ. Instead, it may come off a bit like something a 17 year-old wrote one day while playing hooky… and that’d be correct. The first time I saw the little E36 was about 3 years ago, I was 14. Somehow I looked passed all of its imperfections, and it sparked my interest in E36s. It’s a 1993 brillantrot 325iS that a good friend of ours bought from a broke Princeton student who knew nothing about cars. It was advertised on South Jersey Craigslist with a blown engine. After a good friend purchased it, he diagnosed the problem as being a damaged clutch fan. It was fixed, but never registered to be driven.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Welcome to E39Source</title><link>https://www.e39source.com/blog/welcome-to-e39source/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.e39source.com/blog/welcome-to-e39source/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="../img/Title1111.png" alt="Alt text">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>From the accomplished staff of &lt;a href="http://www.techinform.us/">TechInform.us&lt;/a>, Robert Francis, Colton Michael, and James Ryan have turned the key to a new service. If you’re reading this, congratulations; you’re part of our warm-up procedure. Our variable-LED red-line will be blinking out shortly, and our rev-limter has been removed. Fasten Seat Belts.&lt;/p>
&lt;p> &lt;br/>&lt;br/>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Timeline&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>September 8th, 2011- Ryan Schultz and Colton Frey open &lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/e39source">E39Source&lt;/a> on YouTube.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>September 10th, 2011- First video upload- &lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=xLjoPi_Q3nE">Welcome to the Channel!&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Your E39 is a ‘Classic’! Now What?</title><link>https://www.e39source.com/blog/your-e39-is-now-a-classic-now-what/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.e39source.com/blog/your-e39-is-now-a-classic-now-what/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://e39source.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/Screen-Shot-2018-03-08-at-2.27.50-PM-1.png" alt="Alt text">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We all recognize the E39 as a classic BMW. Its looks, its performance, the way it drives…it has all of the hallmarks of a modern classic. Recently, BMW made the E39’s status official by relocating the E39 chassis from the ‘Current’ parts catalog to the ‘Classic’ or ‘Heritage’ catalog. While this does allow for bragging rights and an inordinate use of “Respect Your Elders” stickers, what does it actually mean for the enthusiasts and owners of these cars?The short answer is not much.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>