<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>E39 M5 BMW on E39Source</title><link>https://www.e39source.com/categories/e39-m5-bmw/</link><description>Recent content in E39 M5 BMW on E39Source</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://www.e39source.com/categories/e39-m5-bmw/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Auxiliary Input Kit Installation (Non-Nav)</title><link>https://www.e39source.com/blog/auxiliary-input-kit-installation-non-nav/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.e39source.com/blog/auxiliary-input-kit-installation-non-nav/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://e39source.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/07/190895_x800.jpg" alt="Alt text"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article will go over the required parts and steps to install a hard-wired factory BMW auxiliary input kit to your E39 5-series without factory navigation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Objective:&lt;/strong&gt; Install a factory BMW hard-wired auxiliary input cable to your 5-series.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Applicable Vehicles:&lt;/strong&gt; 1997-2003 BMW E39 5-series (Without Navigation): 520i, 523i, 525i, 528i, 530i, 535i, 540i, M5.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DISCLOSURE:&lt;/strong&gt; This post may contain affiliate links, meaning when you click the links and make a purchase, we receive a commission.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>BMW E39 M5 Camshaft Position Sensors</title><link>https://www.e39source.com/blog/bmw-e39-m5-camshaft-position-sensors/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.e39source.com/blog/bmw-e39-m5-camshaft-position-sensors/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://e39source.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/S62.png" alt="Alt text"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s always something, right? Usually electrical sensors are the most prominent, annoying, and expensive problems we have with these cars, and this only perpetuates this theory. Own an E39 M5 for long enough, and you’ll end up having to replace the cam sensors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is a Camshaft Position Sensor?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s start with a camshaft. Put basically, the camshaft is responsible for opening and closing intake and exhaust valves in a combustion engine. A camshaft position sensor senses the position of the camshaft as it revolves, reporting back to the VANOS (variable intake and exhaust valve timing system) telling it where the camshaft sits. This all enhances performance, efficiency, and overall smoothness of the engine. Since the M5’s engine is a ‘V’8, there are two cylinder banks, and thus four camshafts. Each cylinder bank has one intake, and one exhaust camshaft. Each camshaft has a CPS (camshaft position sensor). This brings the total to four CPS, two intake, and two exhaust.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>BMW E39 M5: Floor/Trunk Mats</title><link>https://www.e39source.com/blog/trunk-mats/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.e39source.com/blog/trunk-mats/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://e39source.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/IMG_7047.jpg" alt="Alt text"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Really Ryan, a post about floor mats? Yeah. This article will identify the proper floor mat part numbers for our E39 M5s. Caramel and English Green are longer available, but black is; and BMW has recently updated it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Winter&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Genuine BMW Black Rubber, Front: &lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=1vz0CwG/oc8&amp;amp;mid=43304&amp;amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.ecstuning.com%2Fb-genuine-bmw-parts%2Ffront-rubber-floor-mat-set-black%2F82550302997%2F"&gt;82550302997&lt;/a&gt;
Other Brands and Options: &lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=1vz0CwG/oc8&amp;amp;mid=43304&amp;amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.ecstuning.com%2FBMW-E39-M5-S62_5.0L%2FInterior%2FFloor_Mats%2FRubber%2F"&gt;ECS Tuning&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Summer&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Genuine BMW Black Carpet, Set of Four: &lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=1vz0CwG/oc8&amp;amp;mid=43304&amp;amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.ecstuning.com%2Fb-genuine-bmw-parts%2F--m-carpeted-floor-mats-anthracite-black%2F82110009046%2F"&gt;82110009046&lt;/a&gt;
Other Brands and Options: &lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=1vz0CwG/oc8&amp;amp;mid=43304&amp;amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.ecstuning.com%2FBMW-E39-M5-S62_5.0L%2FInterior%2FFloor_Mats%2FCarpeted%2F"&gt;ECS Tuning&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Caramel and English Green mats are no longer available new. I recommend that owners of cars with these interiors try the black mats; they prove to be much more practical than the lighter colors.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>BMW E39 M5: Front PDC Retrofit</title><link>https://www.e39source.com/blog/front-pdc-retrofit/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.e39source.com/blog/front-pdc-retrofit/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://e39source.com/wp-content/uploads/2010/05/IMG_7300.jpg" alt="Alt text"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the 2000 model year, E39 M5s optioned with S508A Park Distance Control PDC included only 4 rear sensors. It wasn’t until the 2001 facelift that BMW added an additional 4 front sensors to the PDC option. This article and video content will detail how to retrofit the four front sensors to your 2000 BMW M5.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This article is a supplement to the primary DIY video posted at the bottom of this article. Reference that video to see the steps in action and for a better visual explanation.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>BMW E39 M5: Must Have Mods</title><link>https://www.e39source.com/blog/must-have-mods/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.e39source.com/blog/must-have-mods/</guid><description>I bought my 2000 BMW M5 in 2010; it was my first car and I was 17 years old. Somehow, I didn’t kill myself. By 2011, the void of E39 M5 DIY content online made me think ‘If I want to see this content, maybe others would too.’ I decided to spearhead the lack of online content with E39Source. This has allowed me to connect with thousands of fellow E39 (M5) owners. Now after 12+ years of E39 M5 experience, I have come to know this platform quite well. For the first 8 years, I serviced my own vehicle. Since 2018, I have been offering my speciality E39 M5 services professionally at our shop located in San Diego, California&amp;hellip;</description></item><item><title>BMW E39: Automatic Headlight Retrofit</title><link>https://www.e39source.com/blog/automatic-headlight-retrofit/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.e39source.com/blog/automatic-headlight-retrofit/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="../img/IMG_0060.jpeg" alt="Alt Text"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the 2002 model year (from 9/1/2001 production), BMWs came standard with automatic headlights. Five components need to be installed or replaced to bring this functionality to earlier models. This article details the steps that must be completed to retrofit automatic headlights. Additionally, please view the video at the bottom of this post for more detail.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Objective:&lt;/strong&gt; Retrofit automatic headlights to a BMW E39 5-series.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Applicable Vehicles:&lt;/strong&gt; 1997-2001 BMW E39 5-series: 520i, 523i, 525i, 528i, 530i, 535i, 540i, M5. Information from this article can also be applied to the 1994-2001 BMW E38 7-series: 730i, 740i, 740iL, 750iL, the E53 BMW X5, and the 1999-2006 BMW E46 3-series: 323i, 325i, 328i, 330i, M3.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>BMW E39: Facelift Lighting</title><link>https://www.e39source.com/blog/facelift-lighting/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.e39source.com/blog/facelift-lighting/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://e39source.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/M5.jpg" alt="Alt text"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BMW made constant changes to the E39 throughout production. I detail the majority of these changes &lt;a href="https://e39source.com/archives/1848"&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt;. Some of the most distinctive updates were to the exterior lighting. The 2001 facelift brought new headlights, fog lights, and taillights to the E39. This article will detail the upgrade process from 1996-2000 lights to 2001+ lights.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BMW themselves do not manufacture lights. Most BMWs, including the E39, use exterior lights made by Hella. You’ll also find Hella lights on many other vehicles. You can buy the lights from BMW branded as Genuine BMW (if available), but these were in fact manufactured by Hella in Germany. Buying from Hella directly (if available) cuts out the middleman and reduces your cost by approximately 2/3.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>BMW E39: Facelift Steering Wheel Upgrade</title><link>https://www.e39source.com/blog/facelift-steering-wheel-upgrade/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.e39source.com/blog/facelift-steering-wheel-upgrade/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://e39source.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/01/IMG_2978.jpg" alt="Alt text"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For 2001, BMW gave the E39 M5 the E46 M3 steering wheel. Before this, it had used the E36 M3’s wheel. The newer wheel looks a lot more modern and feels much more sporty due to it’s thicker girth, and more pronounced side bolsters. The E46 wheel also allows you to finally see both the top of the gauges and the cluster LCD display at the same time! Depending on when your E39 was made, this update process can be super easy, or damn near impossible. Let’s get to it.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>BMW E39: HVAC Panel Facelift</title><link>https://www.e39source.com/blog/hvac-panel-facelift/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.e39source.com/blog/hvac-panel-facelift/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="../img/541B-1536x1152.jpg" alt="Alt text"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a minor item to facelift, but it was included in the E39 2001 model year refresh nonetheless. From 9/00 production, BMW replaced the REST button with a MAX AC button. But fear not, REST functionality is not lost! This article details how to properly retrofit the new HVAC panel and associated solar sensor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Objective:&lt;/strong&gt; Facelift HVAC panel to add MAX AC button and functionality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>BMW E39: Navigation System Upgrades: (Computer, Display, Software, Maps)</title><link>https://www.e39source.com/blog/nav-guide/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.e39source.com/blog/nav-guide/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="../img/IMG_1.jpg" alt="Nav Guide Image"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this article, I discuss in detail the steps, hardware, and software required to upgrade your BMW’s navigation computer, display, software, and maps. The information in this article is only applicable to BMWs that speak the same electronics ‘language’. Many BMW models and series speak this same language, utilize the same connectors, and make use of the same hardware-software interface.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Applicable Vehicles:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;E38 7-series (1994-2001) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;E46 3-series (1999-2006) &lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>BMW E39: P0443/Evap Code Diagnosis</title><link>https://www.e39source.com/blog/evap-code-diagnosis/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.e39source.com/blog/evap-code-diagnosis/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://e39source.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/07/Yk4SXyaz1hWT.jpg" alt="Alt text"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I just bought my 1998 BMW 540i two weeks ago, and I knew when I bought it that there was a check engine light on for an EVAP code. I pulled the code and it came up as P0443. I just wanted to outline a short diagnostic checklist of things to check when you experience this or any other EVAP code related to the purge valve.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>BMW E39: Shift Knob Replacement</title><link>https://www.e39source.com/blog/shift-nob-replacement/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.e39source.com/blog/shift-nob-replacement/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://e39source.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/12/Shift-Knob.png" alt="Alt text"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The shifter is one of the most touched parts of the vehicle. If you own your 5-series long enough, you will probably want to replace it. What are the correct part numbers? Which one does your vehicle need? How do you change it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Objective:&lt;/strong&gt; This article will detail the replacement of the manual shift knob found in a BMW E39 5-series. A video of wiring an M5 shift knob is embedded at the bottom, as well as wiring an M shift knob into a non-M BMW.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>BMW E39: SIRIUS XM, Aux Input, BM53 Radio Retrofit</title><link>https://www.e39source.com/blog/sirius-xm/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.e39source.com/blog/sirius-xm/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="../img/IMG_3169.jpeg" alt="E39 SIRIUS XM, Aux, Radio 1"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Welcome to what is going to be a very thorough and detailed article. I am going to break down exactly what you need to do to retrofit a BM53 Radio, Auxiliary Input, and SIRIUS XM radio into your BMW E39 5-series. All of the components used in this DIY are Genuine BMW. No Chinese aftermarket garbage head units here!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DISCLOSURE: This post may contain affiliate links, meaning when you click the links and make a purchase, we receive a commission.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>BMW E39: Trunk Escape Handle Retrofit</title><link>https://www.e39source.com/blog/trunck-escape-handle-retrofit/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.e39source.com/blog/trunck-escape-handle-retrofit/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://e39source.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/IMG_1227.jpeg" alt="Alt text"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the 2002 model year (from 9/1/2001 production), the BMW E39 came standard with an emergency trunk release handle. Six components need to be installed or replaced to bring this feature to older E39s. This article details the steps that must be completed in order to retrofit the emergency release handle. Please see the video at the bottom of this post as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Objective&lt;/strong&gt;: Retrofit emergency trunk release handle to a BMW E39 5-series.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>BMW E39: Trunk Tools</title><link>https://www.e39source.com/blog/trunk-tools/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.e39source.com/blog/trunk-tools/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="../img/bmw_toolkit_labelled.jpeg" alt="Alt text"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This post lists all of the parts that can be fitted to the E39’s trunk tool kit. Not all of these tools were included for the DE93 (North American) market cars. Specifically, we didn’t receive tools A, I, or J.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TOOL,	PART NUMBER,	DESCRIPTION:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;KIT	&lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=1vz0CwG/oc8&amp;amp;mid=43304&amp;amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.ecstuning.com%2Fb-genuine-bmw-parts%2Ftool-box%2F71111182774%2F"&gt;71111180684&lt;/a&gt;	Tool kit case pre-facelift (NLA)	production ended 11/22/2001&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;KIT	&lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=1vz0CwG/oc8&amp;amp;mid=43304&amp;amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.ecstuning.com%2Fb-genuine-bmw-parts%2Ftool-box%2F71111182774%2F"&gt;71111182774&lt;/a&gt;	Tool kit case facelift	production started 09/1995&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A	&lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=1vz0CwG/oc8&amp;amp;mid=43304&amp;amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.ecstuning.com%2Fb-genuine-european-bmw-parts%2Fwarning-triangle-with-container-no-longer-available%2F71601092427%7Eoee%2F"&gt;71601092427&lt;/a&gt;	Warning triangle with container (NLA)	production ended 05/2000&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>BMW E39: Wireless Charging</title><link>https://www.e39source.com/blog/wireless-charging/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.e39source.com/blog/wireless-charging/</guid><description>In this article, we’ll discuss the required parts and procedures to retrofit wireless phone charging to your BMW E39 5-series. That’s right- a feature not available on many modern BMWs- in your 20+ year old one. And the best part? The parts cost less than $35. Be sure to watch the embedded YouTube video below, which shows these steps in more detail.</description></item><item><title>Case Study: The Cost of Owning a BMW E39 M5</title><link>https://www.e39source.com/blog/the-cost-of-owning-a-bmw-e39-m5/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.e39source.com/blog/the-cost-of-owning-a-bmw-e39-m5/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://e39source.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/15874968_761549550662427_5807226607884989751_o-1536x1024.png" alt="Alt text"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anybody can afford to buy a used BMW. But maintaining a used BMW is another story. After all, the most expensive car you every buy will probably be a cheap BMW. This is a case study of an E39 M5 owner after 9 years and 100,000 miles. So, what did that cost?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. The operating cost of the car is 53 Cents per mile.&lt;/strong&gt; The average cost for a large sedan is 56 cents per mile (AAA 2018). You get that number by dividing total miles driven by everything you put into it, like gas, insurance, repairs, and the cost of the car when you bought it versus value if you sold it today (depreciation).&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>E39 M5 Engine Reliability</title><link>https://www.e39source.com/blog/engine-reliability/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.e39source.com/blog/engine-reliability/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="../img/IMG_1030.jpeg" alt="E39 Reliability"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the past 6 years, my team and I have serviced hundreds of E39 M5s (and a few Z8s!) I’ve also owned my M5 for 15 years and over 90,000 miles now. The S62 V8 can last 300,000 miles on original components. It can also fail at 40,000 miles. Thankfully, there seem to be many more instances of higher miles than lower. These are the primary weak points of the S62:&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>E39 Production Changes</title><link>https://www.e39source.com/blog/production-changes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.e39source.com/blog/production-changes/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="../img/IMG_5648.png" alt="E39 Production Changes 1"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The BMW E39 5-series was produced from 09/1995-06/2003 for the 1996-2003 model years. In September of 2000, for the 2001 model year, BMW gave the E39 a facelift. This means that the E39 chassis was updated, renewed both technologically and aesthetically for a few more years of production. Even outside of the big 2001 facelift, things with the E39 changed each year. This article will summarize the changes BMW made to US-spec vehicles throughout the production run.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Your E39 is a ‘Classic’! Now What?</title><link>https://www.e39source.com/blog/your-e39-is-now-a-classic-now-what/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.e39source.com/blog/your-e39-is-now-a-classic-now-what/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://e39source.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/Screen-Shot-2018-03-08-at-2.27.50-PM-1.png" alt="Alt text"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We all recognize the E39 as a classic BMW. Its looks, its performance, the way it drives…it has all of the hallmarks of a modern classic. Recently, BMW made the E39’s status official by relocating the E39 chassis from the ‘Current’ parts catalog to the ‘Classic’ or ‘Heritage’ catalog. While this does allow for bragging rights and an inordinate use of “Respect Your Elders” stickers, what does it actually mean for the enthusiasts and owners of these cars?The short answer is not much.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>