<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Blog on E39Source</title><link>https://ajmameshin.github.io/E39Source/blog/</link><description>Recent content in Blog on E39Source</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Sep 2023 13:50:46 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ajmameshin.github.io/E39Source/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>BMW E39: Wireless Charging</title><link>https://ajmameshin.github.io/E39Source/blog/hugo-is-for-lovers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Sep 2023 13:50:46 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://ajmameshin.github.io/E39Source/blog/hugo-is-for-lovers/</guid><description>In this article, we’ll discuss the required parts and procedures to retrofit wireless phone charging to your BMW E39 5-series. That’s right- a feature not available on many modern BMWs- in your 20+ year old one. And the best part? The parts cost less than $35. Be sure to watch the embedded YouTube video below, which shows these steps in more detail.</description></item><item><title>BMW E39 M5: Must Have Mods</title><link>https://ajmameshin.github.io/E39Source/blog/categories-post/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ajmameshin.github.io/E39Source/blog/categories-post/</guid><description>I bought my 2000 BMW M5 in 2010; it was my first car and I was 17 years old. Somehow, I didn’t kill myself. By 2011, the void of E39 M5 DIY content online made me think ‘If I want to see this content, maybe others would too.’ I decided to spearhead the lack of online content with E39Source. This has allowed me to connect with thousands of fellow E39 (M5) owners. Now after 12+ years of E39 M5 experience, I have come to know this platform quite well. For the first 8 years, I serviced my own vehicle. Since 2018, I have been offering my speciality E39 M5 services professionally at our shop located in San Diego, California&amp;hellip;</description></item><item><title>BMW E39: Navigation System Upgrades: (Computer, Display, Software, Maps)</title><link>https://ajmameshin.github.io/E39Source/blog/linked-post/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ajmameshin.github.io/E39Source/blog/linked-post/</guid><description>In this article, I discuss in detail the steps, hardware, and software required to upgrade your BMW’s navigation computer, display, software, and maps. The information in this article is only applicable to BMWs that speak the same electronics ‘language’. Many BMW models and series speak this same language, utilize the same connectors, and make use of the same hardware-software interface.
Applicable Vehicles:
E38 7-series (1994-2001) E46 3-series (1999-2006) E39 5-series (1996-2003) E53 X5 (2000-2006) E83 X3 (2004-2010) *It is important to note that in order to upgrade your navigation system, you must first have a navigation system from factory.</description></item><item><title>BMW E39: SIRIUS XM, Aux Input, BM53 Radio Retrofit</title><link>https://ajmameshin.github.io/E39Source/blog/go-is-for-lovers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ajmameshin.github.io/E39Source/blog/go-is-for-lovers/</guid><description>Welcome to what is going to be a very thorough and detailed article. I am going to break down exactly what you need to do to retrofit a BM53 Radio, Auxiliary Input, and SIRIUS XM radio into your BMW E39 5-series. All of the components used in this DIY are Genuine BMW. No Chinese aftermarket garbage head units here!
DISCLOSURE: This post may contain affiliate links, meaning when you click the links and make a purchase, we receive a commission.</description></item><item><title>E39 M5 Engine Reliability:</title><link>https://ajmameshin.github.io/E39Source/blog/creating-a-new-theme/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ajmameshin.github.io/E39Source/blog/creating-a-new-theme/</guid><description>A common topic, S62 longevity. I could write a book about this, but I’ll try not to here. I’ve been an M5 owner for over 12 years and 85,000 miles now. Over the past 4 years, me and my term have serviced hundreds of E39 M5s. The E39 M5’s S62 V8 can last 300,000 miles on original components. The S62 can also fail at 40,000 miles. Thankfully, there seem to be many more instances of higher miles than lower.</description></item><item><title>Migrate from Jekyll</title><link>https://ajmameshin.github.io/E39Source/blog/migrate-from-jekyll/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ajmameshin.github.io/E39Source/blog/migrate-from-jekyll/</guid><description>Move static content to static Jekyll has a rule that any directory not starting with _ will be copied as-is to the _site output. Hugo keeps all static content under static. You should therefore move it all there. With Jekyll, something that looked like
▾ &amp;lt;root&amp;gt;/ ▾ images/ logo.png should become
▾ &amp;lt;root&amp;gt;/ ▾ static/ ▾ images/ logo.png Additionally, you&amp;rsquo;ll want any files that should reside at the root (such as CNAME) to be moved to static.</description></item></channel></rss>