<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Blog on E39Source</title><link>https://ajmameshin.github.io/E39Source/blog/</link><description>Recent content in Blog on E39Source</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://ajmameshin.github.io/E39Source/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>2010: The Story: Ryan’s 2000 BMW E39 M5:</title><link>https://ajmameshin.github.io/E39Source/blog/the-story-ryans-200-bmw-e39-m5/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ajmameshin.github.io/E39Source/blog/the-story-ryans-200-bmw-e39-m5/</guid><description>All cars have a story, and I’m about to get very carried away telling mine. It’ll be long, detailed, and full of links to YouTube videos and website articles that I have written through the process. This is nearly a decade in the making, after all.
Sunday, July 18th, 2010. 6:42pm. The corner of Village Way and Library Street, in the midwestern town of Hudson, Ohio. I was in the downtown area of my community with my grandparents at a concert on our square.</description></item><item><title>2011: The Story: Ryan’s 2000 BMW E39 M5:</title><link>https://ajmameshin.github.io/E39Source/blog/the-story-ryans-200-bmw-e39-m5-2011/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ajmameshin.github.io/E39Source/blog/the-story-ryans-200-bmw-e39-m5-2011/</guid><description>2011
By this point, I had learned that I could not afford to have any service/maintenance/upgrades carried out through BMW dealerships. I was on my own. And I found that there was very little quality DIY content available online. After spending years making technology DIYs on YouTube, I toyed with the idea of switching to cars. In 2011, I created E39Source DIYs for the shift knob, parking brake handle, center console trim, cup-holders, and I replaced a failed rear park distance control sensor.</description></item><item><title>2012: The Story: Ryan’s 2000 BMW E39 M5:</title><link>https://ajmameshin.github.io/E39Source/blog/the-story-ryans-200-bmw-e39-m5-2012/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ajmameshin.github.io/E39Source/blog/the-story-ryans-200-bmw-e39-m5-2012/</guid><description>2012
Fa t n eat b lts. My cluster’s pixels were committing suicide by the day. It turns out, somebody saw one of my videos showing the problem on YouTube. He sent me a message, telling me how to get BMW of North America to help fix the problem for less than the cost of a whole new cluster. This guy had a 2003 525iA do the same thing, and he is now partly responsible for this website, and one of my closest friends.</description></item><item><title>2013: The Story: Ryan’s 2000 BMW E39 M5:</title><link>https://ajmameshin.github.io/E39Source/blog/the-story-ryans-200-bmw-e39-m5-2013/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ajmameshin.github.io/E39Source/blog/the-story-ryans-200-bmw-e39-m5-2013/</guid><description>2013
Navigation. In the 2001 model year, BMW upgraded the E39’s navigation display to a 16:9 widescreen instrument. The computer also got upgraded. I took this a step further, and bought a MKIV computer in addition to 16:9 display. Big upgrade for this car, DVD readability and all!
I spent much of 2013 fixing the larger issues. They weren’t even large, but they bothered me. I replaced intake camshaft sensors, installed new floor matts and white fog bulbs, changed transmission and differentialoils, replaced control arms and tie rods, added LED license plate lights, had some more minor rust marks removed, changed shifter bushings, added a UUC Evo 3 short shift kit, replaced the FSU and blower motor and replaced my mass air flow sensors.</description></item><item><title>2014: The Story: Ryan’s 2000 BMW E39 M5:</title><link>https://ajmameshin.github.io/E39Source/blog/the-story-ryans-200-bmw-e39-m5-2014/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ajmameshin.github.io/E39Source/blog/the-story-ryans-200-bmw-e39-m5-2014/</guid><description>2014
Things will get crazy this year. I have decided to make this car as nice as I can afford to. That means every screw, every clip, every bracket, every everything has to be present, and in good working condition. They also need to look good. I ordered over 400 new parts for this car this year. It got new OEM style 65 wheels, new tires, chassis braces, instrument cluster bezel, switches, knobs, fan clutch, engine fan, door sills, M-audio subs, front bumper, trim, fog lights, rear bumper, trim, diffuser, facelift steering wheel, a total over-haul in electronics, all exterior door trim, coolant expansion tank, new filters, parking brake rebuild, rear brake overhaul, M3 oil cap, oil return hoses, and all mounting and installation hardware associated with these things.</description></item><item><title>2015: The Story: Ryan’s 2000 BMW E39 M5:</title><link>https://ajmameshin.github.io/E39Source/blog/the-story-ryans-200-bmw-e39-m5-2015/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ajmameshin.github.io/E39Source/blog/the-story-ryans-200-bmw-e39-m5-2015/</guid><description>2015
Spring 2015 started with body work. I had the new side mirrors painted, rust removed from one rocker panel, and various other minor rust spot corrections. The car is now rust free! I did the brake fluid when new lines were installed, and got fresh coolant after a thermostat replacement. At 188,026 miles now, this car is more capable than any 2003 model I’ve ever seen. A full euro lighting conversion, all OEM parts, a short shift kit, Shark tune, M-audio woofers, SIRIUS XM, aux, upgraded navigation, fresh vitals, etc.</description></item><item><title>2016: The Story: Ryan’s 2000 BMW E39 M5:</title><link>https://ajmameshin.github.io/E39Source/blog/the-story-ryans-200-bmw-e39-m5-2016/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ajmameshin.github.io/E39Source/blog/the-story-ryans-200-bmw-e39-m5-2016/</guid><description>2016
In March of 2016, the roads cleared enough for me to take the car into the shop. The plans had grown though. Not only was it getting a rebuilt 2002 engine and 2003 differential, but a full driveline, brake, gear linkage, and suspension refresh. Anything under the car that wasn’t set for at least 100,000 miles was to be rebuilt/replaced.
The engine work had been going on since January. The heads were sent out to a machine shop to be cleaned, and have new valve seals fitted.</description></item><item><title>2017: The Story: Ryan’s 2000 BMW E39 M5:</title><link>https://ajmameshin.github.io/E39Source/blog/the-story-ryans-200-bmw-e39-m5-2017/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ajmameshin.github.io/E39Source/blog/the-story-ryans-200-bmw-e39-m5-2017/</guid><description>2017
January, 2017
My original engine now in New York.
I got bored enough in January to reach out to the new owner of my old S62, and see what he had found out with it. He bought my used engine to install in a project car of his. He told me a year ago that he planned to rebuild it before installing it in another car. I received several photos of my old engine opened up, and taken apart.</description></item><item><title>2018: The Story: Ryan’s 2000 BMW E39 M5:</title><link>https://ajmameshin.github.io/E39Source/blog/the-story-ryans-200-bmw-e39-m5-2018/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ajmameshin.github.io/E39Source/blog/the-story-ryans-200-bmw-e39-m5-2018/</guid><description>2018
For April Fools day, Kennan had the great idea to film an E39Source Intro- in the voice and grandeur of US President Donald J. Tump. You have to see this video!
Kennan filming Trump’s intro with my M5.
The April Fools video was a HUUUUGGEE success.
For the summer of 2018, I added the Rogue Engineering Diablo resonated x-pipe to my exhaust setup, which now features stock headers and cats, the Rogue x-pipe, and the 4x76mm Eisenmann Race mufflers.</description></item><item><title>2019: The Story: Ryan’s 2000 BMW E39 M5:</title><link>https://ajmameshin.github.io/E39Source/blog/the-story-ryans-200-bmw-e39-m5-2019/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ajmameshin.github.io/E39Source/blog/the-story-ryans-200-bmw-e39-m5-2019/</guid><description>2019
E39Source is now an LLC, with a brick and mortar location. We rented a 3,500 square foot shop up in Escondido, 30 miles north of San Diego. We had two lifts installed, and got a badass set of tools. You can read more about what E39Source is doing now here.
New-style BMW battery (black)
February, 2019
This first winter in California was ‘rainy’ by California standards. That meant that my dad’s 1998 Ferrari 355 wasn’t driven as much over the winter as it usually does.</description></item><item><title>2020: The Story: Ryan’s 2000 BMW E39 M5:</title><link>https://ajmameshin.github.io/E39Source/blog/the-story-ryans-200-bmw-e39-m5-2020/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ajmameshin.github.io/E39Source/blog/the-story-ryans-200-bmw-e39-m5-2020/</guid><description>2020
I am now finally using this car for what I have been building it for for years! I wanted a reliable, daily-drivable M5 for when I got to California. It took me nearly a decade to build that car, and now I can finally use it. From 2014-2018, I drove the car around 3,500 miles per year. In 2019, I logged over 9,000 miles, and loved every one of them!</description></item><item><title>2021: The Story: Ryan’s 2000 BMW E39 M5:</title><link>https://ajmameshin.github.io/E39Source/blog/the-story-ryans-200-bmw-e39-m5-2021/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ajmameshin.github.io/E39Source/blog/the-story-ryans-200-bmw-e39-m5-2021/</guid><description>2021
As the E39Source, LLC service business gains more momentum, I started having the opportunity to work with some very special and unique BMWs (and their owners!) This car is nearly my identical twin; a gorgeous Silverstone/Silverstone 2001 M5. We completed loads of driveline, suspension, and cosmetic improvements on this car, and delivered it to a very happy customer in late January. Per customer request, I thoroughly test-drove this car until we were happy with it’s drivability and new feature functionality.</description></item><item><title>2022: The Story: Ryan’s 2000 BMW E39 M5:</title><link>https://ajmameshin.github.io/E39Source/blog/the-story-ryans-200-bmw-e39-m5-2022/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ajmameshin.github.io/E39Source/blog/the-story-ryans-200-bmw-e39-m5-2022/</guid><description>2022
We pick up 2022 while still waiting for the brake calipers to return from being refurbished. I took this opportunity to drop the exhaust and replace the various heat shields around and above the exhaust system. Mine were dirty, crusty, and had some of the mounting holes washed out due to aluminum corrosion. In order to remove one of the shields, the driveshaft had to come out. I noted a slight tick from the center support bearing, so I replaced that as well.</description></item><item><title>Alex’s 1999 BMW E39 540i/6 Introduction</title><link>https://ajmameshin.github.io/E39Source/blog/alexs-1999-bmw-e39-540i6-indroduction/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ajmameshin.github.io/E39Source/blog/alexs-1999-bmw-e39-540i6-indroduction/</guid><description>There comes a point in time when people decide that they want to make a change in life. For me, that change was owning a BMW. The first I heard of BMW’s was as a kid going to the auto show with my father, and grandfather. It wasn’t until high school that I really became a car guy. The very first time I rode in a E39 was in 2011, with Ryan’s 2000 E39 M5.</description></item><item><title>Alex’s 2000 BMW E46 328i Introduction</title><link>https://ajmameshin.github.io/E39Source/blog/alexs-2000-bmw-e46-328i-introduction/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ajmameshin.github.io/E39Source/blog/alexs-2000-bmw-e46-328i-introduction/</guid><description>If I were to tell you that I’ve always been a fan of BMW, I’d be lying. Two years ago, if you were to tell me my first car would be an E46, I would have called you crazy! Living in Buffalo, NY, I pictured my first car as some sort of all wheel drive vehicle. I really was set on an older WRX, due to the decent performance, and great all wheel drive system.</description></item><item><title>Andres’ 2000 540i 6 Introduction</title><link>https://ajmameshin.github.io/E39Source/blog/6-introduction/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ajmameshin.github.io/E39Source/blog/6-introduction/</guid><description>Hello E39 Source, my name is Andres and I’d like to introduce my 2000 540i/6. Here’s a little background information about how I found my car and what I’ve done to it. I’ve been a car guy for as long as I can remember; my grandpa’s a mechanic and my dad races vintage cars in SCCA. The day I turned fifteen and got my learner’s license, I was already looking into what my first car could possibly be.</description></item><item><title>Andrew’s New Benz!</title><link>https://ajmameshin.github.io/E39Source/blog/andrews-new-benz/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ajmameshin.github.io/E39Source/blog/andrews-new-benz/</guid><description>My past BMW’s were fun cars. I had a great time driving them, and I learned a lot fixing them. However, they got a bit repetitive after having cars so similar: the E53 X5, E36 318ti, and the E36 328i. These all shared so much in common that I could go through the motions to change out a thermostat or replace an oil filter housing gasket with my eyes closed.</description></item><item><title>Auxiliary Input Kit Installation (Non-Nav)</title><link>https://ajmameshin.github.io/E39Source/blog/auxiliary-input-kit-installation-non-nav/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ajmameshin.github.io/E39Source/blog/auxiliary-input-kit-installation-non-nav/</guid><description>This article will go over the required parts and steps to install a hard-wired factory BMW auxiliary input kit to your E39 5-series without factory navigation.
Objective: Install a factory BMW hard-wired auxiliary input cable to your 5-series.
Applicable Vehicles: 1997-2003 BMW E39 5-series (Without Navigation): 520i, 523i, 525i, 528i, 530i, 535i, 540i, M5.
DISCLOSURE: This post may contain affiliate links, meaning when you click the links and make a purchase, we receive a commission.</description></item><item><title>BMW Answers Tesla with a “Green” Supercar</title><link>https://ajmameshin.github.io/E39Source/blog/bmw-answers-tesla-with-a-green-supercar/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ajmameshin.github.io/E39Source/blog/bmw-answers-tesla-with-a-green-supercar/</guid><description>Up till now, Tesla has had the market for high-end electric cars pretty much to itself. But that first-mover advantage is ending. BMW has just rolled out the i8, a plug-in supercar that will test just how much big spenders are willing to pay for a racer with a green badge. This real-life Batmobile starts at about $140,000, but availability is limited for now, and some sellers are asking well over $200,000 for the car.</description></item><item><title>BMW E36: Bi-Xenon Headlight Retrofit</title><link>https://ajmameshin.github.io/E39Source/blog/bmw-e36-bi-xenon-headlight-retrofit/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ajmameshin.github.io/E39Source/blog/bmw-e36-bi-xenon-headlight-retrofit/</guid><description>How do you get high intensity lighting for under $200 $50? Easy, peasy, lemon squeeze: all you need to do is retrofit your stock plastic lens E36 headlights with bi-xenon projectors. With some modification from a Dremel, razor blade, and a pry tool, you too can have HID lighting without resorting to a eat-ramen-every-night college-esque budget.
DIY on Andrew’s Channel</description></item><item><title>BMW E39 528i: Cooling System Bleeding Insight</title><link>https://ajmameshin.github.io/E39Source/blog/cooling-system-bleeding-insight/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ajmameshin.github.io/E39Source/blog/cooling-system-bleeding-insight/</guid><description>Lesson Learned – Do Not Overfill the Cooling System. I described my experience changing the thermostat housing on my 1997 528i, but I did not describe the problem (a result of my mistake) that followed. As background, all the cars I previously worked on were older, and used a more antiquated cooling system design. “Back in the day”, the cooling system was filled directly into the radiator, and the radiator cap has a pressure relief valve built into it.</description></item><item><title>BMW E39 528i: Front Control Arm Insight</title><link>https://ajmameshin.github.io/E39Source/blog/front-control-arm-insight/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ajmameshin.github.io/E39Source/blog/front-control-arm-insight/</guid><description>I was experiencing a slight shimmy whenever I braked hard at speeds in excess of 40mph. It felt like brake judder, but was intermittent, not at low speed. When I jacked up the car, I could move the front left wheel toe-in/toe-out about a quarter of an inch. An inspection from underneath while my wife moved the wheel showed that the ball joint into the left knuckle was worn and moving.</description></item><item><title>BMW E39 528i: Thermostat Housing DIY Insight</title><link>https://ajmameshin.github.io/E39Source/blog/thermostat-housing-diy-insight/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ajmameshin.github.io/E39Source/blog/thermostat-housing-diy-insight/</guid><description>Lesson Learned: at least on my 1997 528i sedan, the radiator shroud can be removed, and replaced, with the fan still installed on the fan clutch. I had to replace a leaky thermostat housing/radiator hose connector on my 1997 528i sedan. RealOEM.com indicates that two different radiator options were available on this vehicle. Mine is the one with the separate overflow tank on the passenger side of the radiator.</description></item><item><title>BMW E39 M5: Front PDC Retrofit</title><link>https://ajmameshin.github.io/E39Source/blog/front-pdc-retrofit/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ajmameshin.github.io/E39Source/blog/front-pdc-retrofit/</guid><description>For the 2000 model year, E39 M5s optioned with S508A Park Distance Control PDC included only 4 rear sensors. It wasn’t until the 2001 facelift that BMW added an additional 4 front sensors to the PDC option. This article and video content will detail how to retrofit the four front sensors to your 2000 BMW M5.
This article is a supplement to the primary DIY video posted at the bottom of this article.</description></item><item><title>BMW E39 M5: Must Have Mods</title><link>https://ajmameshin.github.io/E39Source/blog/must-have-mods/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ajmameshin.github.io/E39Source/blog/must-have-mods/</guid><description>I bought my 2000 BMW M5 in 2010; it was my first car and I was 17 years old. Somehow, I didn’t kill myself. By 2011, the void of E39 M5 DIY content online made me think ‘If I want to see this content, maybe others would too.’ I decided to spearhead the lack of online content with E39Source. This has allowed me to connect with thousands of fellow E39 (M5) owners. Now after 12+ years of E39 M5 experience, I have come to know this platform quite well. For the first 8 years, I serviced my own vehicle. Since 2018, I have been offering my speciality E39 M5 services professionally at our shop located in San Diego, California&amp;hellip;</description></item><item><title>BMW E39: Automatic Headlight Retrofit</title><link>https://ajmameshin.github.io/E39Source/blog/automatic-headlight-retrofit/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ajmameshin.github.io/E39Source/blog/automatic-headlight-retrofit/</guid><description>For the 2002 model year (from 9/1/2001 production), BMWs came standard with automatic headlights. Five components need to be installed or replaced to bring this functionality to earlier models. This article details the steps that must be completed to retrofit automatic headlights. Additionally, please view the video at the bottom of this post for more detail.
Objective: Retrofit automatic headlights to a BMW E39 5-series.
Applicable Vehicles: 1997-2001 BMW E39 5-series: 520i, 523i, 525i, 528i, 530i, 535i, 540i, M5.</description></item><item><title>BMW E39: Europe vs North America</title><link>https://ajmameshin.github.io/E39Source/blog/europe_vs_north_america/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ajmameshin.github.io/E39Source/blog/europe_vs_north_america/</guid><description>This is a post that may continue to grow and evolve. There are countless variations between BMWs produced and sold in the European market vs those sold here, in the US / North American (DE93) market. This article will highlight some of those differences.
Hyperlinks in this article will point to more E39Source content about installing or retrofitting some of these components.
Europe Got:
Rear Fog Lights: The lower, inner portions of the tail lights were used as rear fog lights to increase vehicle visibility in foggy conditions.</description></item><item><title>BMW E39: Facelift Lighting</title><link>https://ajmameshin.github.io/E39Source/blog/facelift-lighting/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ajmameshin.github.io/E39Source/blog/facelift-lighting/</guid><description>BMW made constant changes to the E39 throughout production. I detail the majority of these changes this article. Some of the most noticeable differences are in the lighting elements. The 2001 facelift brought new headlights, fog lights, and tail lights to the E39. This article will detail the upgrade process from 1996-2000 lights to 2001+ lights.
There is a right way and a wrong way to go about this. If you use Ebay to search for E39 headlights and tail lights, you will find several significantly cheaper alternatives to what I recommend using.</description></item><item><title>BMW E39: Facelift Steering Wheel Upgrade</title><link>https://ajmameshin.github.io/E39Source/blog/facelift-steering-wheel-upgrade/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ajmameshin.github.io/E39Source/blog/facelift-steering-wheel-upgrade/</guid><description>For 2001, BMW gave the E39 M5 the E46 M3 steering wheel. Before this, it had used the E36 M3’s wheel. The newer wheel looks a lot more modern and feels much more sporty due to it’s thicker girth, and more pronounced side bolsters. The E46 wheel also allows you to finally see both the top of the gauges and the cluster LCD display at the same time! Depending on when your E39 was made, this update process can be super easy, or damn near impossible.</description></item><item><title>BMW E39: HVAC Panel Facelift</title><link>https://ajmameshin.github.io/E39Source/blog/hvac-panel-facelift/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ajmameshin.github.io/E39Source/blog/hvac-panel-facelift/</guid><description>This is a minor item to facelift, but it was included in the E39 2001 model year refresh nonetheless. From 9/00 production, BMW replaced the REST button with a MAX AC button. But fear not, REST functionality is not lost! This article details how to properly retrofit the new HVAC panel and associated solar sensor.
Objective: Facelift HVAC panel to add MAX AC button and functionality.
Applicable Vehicles: 1997-2000 BMW E39 5-series: 528i, 540i, M5.</description></item><item><title>BMW E39: Navigation System Upgrades: (Computer, Display, Software, Maps)</title><link>https://ajmameshin.github.io/E39Source/blog/nav-guide/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ajmameshin.github.io/E39Source/blog/nav-guide/</guid><description>In this article, I discuss in detail the steps, hardware, and software required to upgrade your BMW’s navigation computer, display, software, and maps. The information in this article is only applicable to BMWs that speak the same electronics ‘language’. Many BMW models and series speak this same language, utilize the same connectors, and make use of the same hardware-software interface.
Applicable Vehicles:
E38 7-series (1994-2001) E46 3-series (1999-2006) E39 5-series (1996-2003) E53 X5 (2000-2006) E83 X3 (2004-2010) *It is important to note that in order to upgrade your navigation system, you must first have a navigation system from factory.</description></item><item><title>BMW E39: P0443/Evap Code Diagnosis</title><link>https://ajmameshin.github.io/E39Source/blog/evap-code-diagnosis/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ajmameshin.github.io/E39Source/blog/evap-code-diagnosis/</guid><description>I just bought my 1998 BMW 540i two weeks ago, and I knew when I bought it that there was a check engine light on for an EVAP code. I pulled the code and it came up as P0443. I just wanted to outline a short diagnostic checklist of things to check when you experience this or any other EVAP code related to the purge valve.
Check your gas cap.</description></item><item><title>BMW E39: Shift Knob Replacement</title><link>https://ajmameshin.github.io/E39Source/blog/shift-nob-replacement/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ajmameshin.github.io/E39Source/blog/shift-nob-replacement/</guid><description>The shifter is one of the most touched parts of the vehicle. If you own your 5-series long enough, you will probably want to replace it. What are the correct part numbers? Which one does your vehicle need? How do you change it?
Objective: This article will detail the replacement of the manual shift knob found in a BMW E39 5-series. A video of wiring an M5 shift knob is embedded at the bottom, as well as wiring an M shift knob into a non-M BMW.</description></item><item><title>BMW E39: SIRIUS XM, Aux Input, BM53 Radio Retrofit</title><link>https://ajmameshin.github.io/E39Source/blog/sirius-xm/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ajmameshin.github.io/E39Source/blog/sirius-xm/</guid><description>Welcome to what is going to be a very thorough and detailed article. I am going to break down exactly what you need to do to retrofit a BM53 Radio, Auxiliary Input, and SIRIUS XM radio into your BMW E39 5-series. All of the components used in this DIY are Genuine BMW. No Chinese aftermarket garbage head units here!
DISCLOSURE: This post may contain affiliate links, meaning when you click the links and make a purchase, we receive a commission.</description></item><item><title>BMW E39: Trunk Escape Handle Retrofit</title><link>https://ajmameshin.github.io/E39Source/blog/trunck-escape-handle-retrofit/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ajmameshin.github.io/E39Source/blog/trunck-escape-handle-retrofit/</guid><description>For the 2002 model year (from 9/1/2001 production), the BMW E39 came standard with an emergency trunk release handle. Six components need to be installed or replaced to bring this feature to older E39s. This article details the steps that must be completed in order to retrofit the emergency release handle. Please see the video at the bottom of this post as well.
Objective: Retrofit emergency trunk release handle to a BMW E39 5-series.</description></item><item><title>BMW E39: Trunk Tools</title><link>https://ajmameshin.github.io/E39Source/blog/trunk-tools/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ajmameshin.github.io/E39Source/blog/trunk-tools/</guid><description>This post lists all of the parts that can be fitted to the E39’s trunk tool kit. Not all of these tools were included for the DE93 (North American) market cars. Specifically, we didn’t receive tools A, I, or J.
TOOL, PART NUMBER, DESCRIPTION:
KIT 71111180684 Tool kit case pre-facelift (NLA) production ended 11/22/2001
KIT 71111182774 Tool kit case facelift production started 09/1995
A 71601092427 Warning triangle with container (NLA) production ended 05/2000</description></item><item><title>BMW E39: Wireless Charging</title><link>https://ajmameshin.github.io/E39Source/blog/wireless-charging/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ajmameshin.github.io/E39Source/blog/wireless-charging/</guid><description>In this article, we’ll discuss the required parts and procedures to retrofit wireless phone charging to your BMW E39 5-series. That’s right- a feature not available on many modern BMWs- in your 20+ year old one. And the best part? The parts cost less than $35. Be sure to watch the embedded YouTube video below, which shows these steps in more detail.</description></item><item><title>BMW M50/M52: Intake Modification</title><link>https://ajmameshin.github.io/E39Source/blog/m52-intake-modification/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ajmameshin.github.io/E39Source/blog/m52-intake-modification/</guid><description>With this modification, your M52B25 or M52B28 engine will make more power. The M52B25 and M52B28 engines can be found in the E36, E39, E38, and in some early E46 models. This is not the easiest modification, but if you are at least a little bit handy, it is not difficult. Some people say that this will gain an additional 20HP, while some say it won’t give you any. I believe that there are power benefits.</description></item><item><title>BMW M52 I6: Serpentine Belt DIY</title><link>https://ajmameshin.github.io/E39Source/blog/serpentine-belt-diy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ajmameshin.github.io/E39Source/blog/serpentine-belt-diy/</guid><description>A serpentine, or accessory belt, is a part shared by all internal combustion piston engines. Knowing how to replace one would be a valuable skill for anyone to have. This article walks the reader through each step required to replace either the serpentine or AC belt on the BMW M52 inline 6-cylinder engine.
This post was submitted to E39Source by Brian M
Objective: Replace serpentine belt and/or AC belt on M52 I6 powered BMW.</description></item><item><title>BMW N54 Tuning &amp; Maintenance Guide</title><link>https://ajmameshin.github.io/E39Source/blog/bmw-n54-tuning--maintenance-guide/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ajmameshin.github.io/E39Source/blog/bmw-n54-tuning--maintenance-guide/</guid><description>Over the past few years, the N54 twin turbo 3.0 lite inline-6 has gained the reputation of being an easily tunable and powerful engine. With the N54 aging and the increasing number of modifications available, we are bound to begin seeing more blown engines and turbos. Although the block and internals are very strong, the N54 is prone to issues without the proper maintenance and repairs. Whether your N54 is stock or running a large single turbo set up, this guide will ensure your engine is running at its best.</description></item><item><title>BMW Removes Manual Transmission From 5-Series</title><link>https://ajmameshin.github.io/E39Source/blog/bmw-removes-manual-transmission-from-5-series/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ajmameshin.github.io/E39Source/blog/bmw-removes-manual-transmission-from-5-series/</guid><description>Roughly a month ago, I was on BMW USA’s website and noticed the manual gearbox was removed from the F10 5 series. The standard gearbox is now the 8 speed auto (sigh) or there is the sport automatic transmission for an extra $500. When a manual gearbox is removed from a fine tuned driving instrument, a part of its soul has been removed.Thankfully the manual is still available on the 3 series (probably for a short time) and on the M series line up.</description></item><item><title>BMW Wheel Center Caps</title><link>https://ajmameshin.github.io/E39Source/blog/wheel-center-caps/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ajmameshin.github.io/E39Source/blog/wheel-center-caps/</guid><description>For the 2003 model year, BMW facelift the wheel center caps for the E39 M5. This new version looks more like the hood/trunk lid badge. Gone is the gray plastic bezel and in is a nice chrome ring. The plastic feels better, the badge is a hair bigger, and these new components seem to withstand the test of time better.
Objective: Update or refresh the look of your wheels with the new-style BMW wheel center caps.</description></item><item><title>Case Study: The Cost of Owning a BMW E39 M5</title><link>https://ajmameshin.github.io/E39Source/blog/the-cost-of-owning-a-bmw-e39-m5/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ajmameshin.github.io/E39Source/blog/the-cost-of-owning-a-bmw-e39-m5/</guid><description>Anybody can afford to buy a used BMW. But maintaining a used BMW is another story. After all, the most expensive car you every buy will probably be a cheap BMW. This is a case study of an E39 M5 owner after 9 years and 100,000 miles. So, what did that cost?
1. The operating cost of the car is 53 Cents per mile. The average cost for a large sedan is 56 cents per mile (AAA 2018).</description></item><item><title>Charlie’s 2002 BMW 520i SE Introduction</title><link>https://ajmameshin.github.io/E39Source/blog/charlies-2002-bmw-520i-se-introduction/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ajmameshin.github.io/E39Source/blog/charlies-2002-bmw-520i-se-introduction/</guid><description>Hi everyone, I’m really excited to share my new vehicle with you! I have always wanted a saloon, or sedan as you guys in the states call them. I am a tall guy, 6’7″, so trying to find the right vehicle is a pain! I have to find one first, and ask to sit in the car, which is always an awkward conversation. If I fit in it, then I know what to look for.</description></item><item><title>Christian’s 1999 540i Introduction</title><link>https://ajmameshin.github.io/E39Source/blog/christians-1999-540i-introduction/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ajmameshin.github.io/E39Source/blog/christians-1999-540i-introduction/</guid><description>As far back as I can remember I have been obsessed with cars, and most recently that obsession has been channeled to my 1999 540i. My passion for cars is definitely in my family’s blood. My grandpa had a very strong interest in cars, some of which are some of the most beautiful cars from the 20th century in my opinion. These cars included a 1969 Signal Orange Porsche 911E, 1958 Blue Jaguar XK-140 convertible, 1968 Jaguar E-type convertible in Tan, and a 1966 Lincoln Continental convertible in Black with the suicide doors.</description></item><item><title>Christian’s 2000 BMW E46 330ci</title><link>https://ajmameshin.github.io/E39Source/blog/christains-2000-bmw-e46-330ci/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ajmameshin.github.io/E39Source/blog/christains-2000-bmw-e46-330ci/</guid><description>Christian’s family had tried a BMW before- and it didn’t go well. What was so terrible about that first BMW? What is it about this E46 330ci that changed things? This is the story of Christian’s first car- a 2000 E46 finished in Oxford Green metallic.
I never thought I would say this, but I bought a BMW! Let me give that statement some context. BMW’s don’t have the best reputation in my family.</description></item><item><title>Danny’s Imola 2000 BMW M5</title><link>https://ajmameshin.github.io/E39Source/blog/dannys-imola-2000-bmw-m5/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ajmameshin.github.io/E39Source/blog/dannys-imola-2000-bmw-m5/</guid><description>I was contemplating doing a video of the car and recorded one only to realize that my spoken English isn’t what it once was (Swedish sing-a-song-accent haha) so I’ll make a written post of my recently acquired M5 instead. I found out about the car a few months ago via a friend and I loosely knew the previous owner before as I were childhood friends with his brother.
PO bought the car in oct 2014 and drove it the 100 miles south from Stockholm to his home, and a week later a 500 mile round trip to get the pixels fixed, that it, he hasn’t driven it any more since.</description></item><item><title>Daryl’s 2001 525i Introduction</title><link>https://ajmameshin.github.io/E39Source/blog/daryls-2001-525i-introduction/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ajmameshin.github.io/E39Source/blog/daryls-2001-525i-introduction/</guid><description>G’day from sunny Brisbane, Queensland Australia! I’m Daryl, however I go by the online name Dodgy Haro on most car forums (clubroadster + club4AG) which I participate in. My car background is mainly JDM (previous AE86 and Na6 Miata owner amongst other cars) however I do appreciate European rides too and how they generally handle better on highways and don’t impart that plastic feeling you get from some Japanese cars.</description></item><item><title>E39 M5 Engine Reliability</title><link>https://ajmameshin.github.io/E39Source/blog/engine-reliability/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ajmameshin.github.io/E39Source/blog/engine-reliability/</guid><description>A common topic, S62 longevity. I could write a book about this, but I’ll try not to here. I’ve been an M5 owner for over 12 years and 85,000 miles now. Over the past 4 years, me and my term have serviced hundreds of E39 M5s. The E39 M5’s S62 V8 can last 300,000 miles on original components. The S62 can also fail at 40,000 miles. Thankfully, there seem to be many more instances of higher miles than lower.</description></item><item><title>E39 Production Changes</title><link>https://ajmameshin.github.io/E39Source/blog/production-changes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ajmameshin.github.io/E39Source/blog/production-changes/</guid><description>The BMW E39 5-series was produced from 09/1995-06/2003 for the 1996-2003 model years. In September of 2000, for the 2001 model year, BMW gave the E39 a facelift. This means that the E39 chassis was updated, renewed both technologically and aesthetically for a few more years of production. Even outside of the big 2001 facelift, things with the E39 changed each year. This article will summarize the changes BMW made to US-spec vehicles throughout the production run.</description></item><item><title>Fabien’s 2001 BMW Alpina B10 Introduction</title><link>https://ajmameshin.github.io/E39Source/blog/fabiens-2001-bmw-alpina-b10-introduction/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ajmameshin.github.io/E39Source/blog/fabiens-2001-bmw-alpina-b10-introduction/</guid><description>The BMW E39 Alpina B10 V8 is based on the 540i. Restoration is on-going on this car. It is claimed to produce 347BHP and 450 Nm (332 lb/ft) of toque for the 4.6 M62B46 V8. The Alpina documentation specific to this car states power output to be 355BHP and 480 Nm (354 lb/ft). This example is from 2001, with extended Alpina leather, and the 19″ classic Alpina wheels.</description></item><item><title>Hassan’s 2002 BMW 530iA Introduction</title><link>https://ajmameshin.github.io/E39Source/blog/hassans-2002-bmw-530ia-introduction/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ajmameshin.github.io/E39Source/blog/hassans-2002-bmw-530ia-introduction/</guid><description>I have always been really into cars; I can still remember my briefcase toy chest filled with hot wheels race cars. I used to love those things, I took them everywhere with me! The doctor’s office, on vacations, you name it, I always brought some little toy cars with me. I was a boy who loved cars, like many others. Like many little boys, I dreamed of driving a race car and going 300mph, and having the time of my life.</description></item><item><title>Jackson’s 2002 BMW E39 M5 Introduction</title><link>https://ajmameshin.github.io/E39Source/blog/jacksons-2002-bmw-e39-m5-introduction/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ajmameshin.github.io/E39Source/blog/jacksons-2002-bmw-e39-m5-introduction/</guid><description>Hello everyone, I hope winter is going well so far! I’ve been a long-time member on M5Board, and I thought I’d swing over to this neighborhood to check out the scene! It’s a great technical and video based site in my opinion. My name is Jackson, and I live all the way up in Minnesota, also known as a**hole in the winter.
To begin, I’ve always loved the E39 chassis.</description></item><item><title>Jay’s 2000 BMW E39 M5</title><link>https://ajmameshin.github.io/E39Source/blog/m52-intake-modification-copy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ajmameshin.github.io/E39Source/blog/m52-intake-modification-copy/</guid><description>Hello E39Source! I am a new member to this website, and I wanted to get more involved with this close knit group of E39 enthusiasts. I just recently purchased my first M5! I bought it in Seattle, Washington with 148,000 miles on the clock. The interior is immaculate, along with the rest of the car. It honestly doesn’t feel as if it has covered 148,000 miles. I’ve driven upwards of ten M5s and this one takes the cake.</description></item><item><title>Josh’s 2001 530i Introduction</title><link>https://ajmameshin.github.io/E39Source/blog/joshs-2001-530i-introduction/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ajmameshin.github.io/E39Source/blog/joshs-2001-530i-introduction/</guid><description>Hello from Melbourne, Australia! My names Josh, i’m an automotive photographer and a mechanic. I like a plethora of cars but BMW has always been my number one. Thought I would give you all a bit of a background into my obsession with the BMW brand and an introduction to my E39. This post may get a bit long though, its a trip down memory lane for me right now 😛</description></item><item><title>Luke’s 2000 BMW M5</title><link>https://ajmameshin.github.io/E39Source/blog/lukes-2000-bmw-m5/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ajmameshin.github.io/E39Source/blog/lukes-2000-bmw-m5/</guid><description>Let me begin by saying that I may be slightly biased when it comes to my assured claim that the E39 M5 is the greatest sports sedan of all time. While there are many other remarkable performance sedans out there (E28 M5, E34 M5, W211 E55, C5 RS6, and countless others), the E39 has held a special place in my heart from a young age. Not many other sedans have aged as gracefully and the E39 M5 represents the perfect blend between past and present in the M5 lineage.</description></item><item><title>Maintaining a Vintage BMW</title><link>https://ajmameshin.github.io/E39Source/blog/maintaining-a-vintage-bmw/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ajmameshin.github.io/E39Source/blog/maintaining-a-vintage-bmw/</guid><description>You’ve probably heard about the incredible story of the M1 that was found sitting in a garage in Italy for 34 years. But in case you need a refresher, it’s the 1981 production model that had only clocked 4,600 miles before being put in storage by its owner. Then last year, the vintage car specialists at Mint Classics discovered the automobile in its poor state. Fortunately it wasn’t too late, so now it’s being returned to its former glory.</description></item><item><title>Mike’s E39 528i &amp; M5 Introduction</title><link>https://ajmameshin.github.io/E39Source/blog/mikes-e39-528i-and-m5-indroduction/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ajmameshin.github.io/E39Source/blog/mikes-e39-528i-and-m5-indroduction/</guid><description>Hey guys, thanks for welcoming me to E39source! I’ve been a YouTube subscriber for quite a while now, and actually met some of you at the Pittsburgh Vintage Grand Prix last summer. My name is Mike, and I’m 25 years old and live/work in West Chester, PA. I currently have two E39s: a 1997 528i, and a 2000 M5.
My 528i is a 3/96 build, with almost 305k miles on it now.</description></item><item><title>Restoration Project: Alpina B10 V8</title><link>https://ajmameshin.github.io/E39Source/blog/restoration-project-alpina-b10-v8/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ajmameshin.github.io/E39Source/blog/restoration-project-alpina-b10-v8/</guid><description>After two weeks of a detailed check-up at BMW Dubai (AED 4,000 or $1,100 USD) plus my additional instructions, I came to understand that the core of this car is healthy. The only big mechanical aspects are: front wishbones, rear wheel bearings suspensions (Alpina specific, will cost a fortune as I want genuine OEM only), the rubber disc connecting the gearbox output to the prop-shaft, and the spinning crankshaft joint.</description></item><item><title>Ryan’s 2003 BMW 530iA Introduction</title><link>https://ajmameshin.github.io/E39Source/blog/ryans-2003-bmw-530ia-introduction/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ajmameshin.github.io/E39Source/blog/ryans-2003-bmw-530ia-introduction/</guid><description>For as long as I can remember, I’ve held a strong interest in cars, though my parents accredit that to a toy school bus I had as a toddler. After I turned four, I would point to cars on the road and ask my dad what they were. His limited automotive knowledge meant that every SUV was a Jeep to me; everything else was a mishmash. Through clipping pictures of nice cars out of magazines, collecting Hot Wheels sized cars, and reading the undercarriage for the label, I started to form a vague understanding of what I was seeing on the road.</description></item><item><title>Your E39 is a ‘Classic’! Now What?</title><link>https://ajmameshin.github.io/E39Source/blog/your-e39-is-now-a-classic-now-what/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ajmameshin.github.io/E39Source/blog/your-e39-is-now-a-classic-now-what/</guid><description>We all recognize the E39 as a classic BMW. Its looks, its performance, the way it drives…it has all of the hallmarks of a modern classic. Recently, BMW made the E39’s status official by relocating the E39 chassis from the ‘Current’ parts catalog to the ‘Classic’ or ‘Heritage’ catalog. While this does allow for bragging rights and an inordinate use of “Respect Your Elders” stickers, what does it actually mean for the enthusiasts and owners of these cars?</description></item></channel></rss>