<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Project Cars on E39Source</title><link>https://ajmameshin.github.io/E39Source/categories/project-cars/</link><description>Recent content in Project Cars on E39Source</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://ajmameshin.github.io/E39Source/categories/project-cars/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Christian’s 2000 BMW E46 330ci</title><link>https://ajmameshin.github.io/E39Source/blog/christains-2000-bmw-e46-330ci/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ajmameshin.github.io/E39Source/blog/christains-2000-bmw-e46-330ci/</guid><description>Christian’s family had tried a BMW before- and it didn’t go well. What was so terrible about that first BMW? What is it about this E46 330ci that changed things? This is the story of Christian’s first car- a 2000 E46 finished in Oxford Green metallic.
I never thought I would say this, but I bought a BMW! Let me give that statement some context. BMW’s don’t have the best reputation in my family.</description></item><item><title>Danny’s Imola 2000 BMW M5</title><link>https://ajmameshin.github.io/E39Source/blog/christains-2000-bmw-e46-330ci-copy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ajmameshin.github.io/E39Source/blog/christains-2000-bmw-e46-330ci-copy/</guid><description>I was contemplating doing a video of the car and recorded one only to realize that my spoken English isn’t what it once was (Swedish sing-a-song-accent haha) so I’ll make a written post of my recently acquired M5 instead. I found out about the car a few months ago via a friend and I loosely knew the previous owner before as I were childhood friends with his brother.
PO bought the car in oct 2014 and drove it the 100 miles south from Stockholm to his home, and a week later a 500 mile round trip to get the pixels fixed, that it, he hasn’t driven it any more since.</description></item><item><title>Luke’s 2000 BMW M5</title><link>https://ajmameshin.github.io/E39Source/blog/lukes-2000-bmw-m5/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ajmameshin.github.io/E39Source/blog/lukes-2000-bmw-m5/</guid><description>Let me begin by saying that I may be slightly biased when it comes to my assured claim that the E39 M5 is the greatest sports sedan of all time. While there are many other remarkable performance sedans out there (E28 M5, E34 M5, W211 E55, C5 RS6, and countless others), the E39 has held a special place in my heart from a young age. Not many other sedans have aged as gracefully and the E39 M5 represents the perfect blend between past and present in the M5 lineage.</description></item><item><title>Mike’s E39 528i &amp; M5 Introduction</title><link>https://ajmameshin.github.io/E39Source/blog/mikes-e39-528i-and-m5-indroduction/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ajmameshin.github.io/E39Source/blog/mikes-e39-528i-and-m5-indroduction/</guid><description>Hey guys, thanks for welcoming me to E39source! I’ve been a YouTube subscriber for quite a while now, and actually met some of you at the Pittsburgh Vintage Grand Prix last summer. My name is Mike, and I’m 25 years old and live/work in West Chester, PA. I currently have two E39s: a 1997 528i, and a 2000 M5.
My 528i is a 3/96 build, with almost 305k miles on it now.</description></item></channel></rss>