<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Project-Cars on E39Source</title><link>https://www.e39source.com/categories/project-cars/</link><description>Recent content in Project-Cars on E39Source</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://www.e39source.com/categories/project-cars/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Alex’s 1999 BMW E39 540i/6 Introduction</title><link>https://www.e39source.com/blog/alexs-1999-bmw-e39-540i6-indroduction/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.e39source.com/blog/alexs-1999-bmw-e39-540i6-indroduction/</guid><description>There comes a point in time when people decide that they want to make a change in life. For me, that change was owning a BMW. The first I heard of BMW’s was as a kid going to the auto show with my father, and grandfather. It wasn’t until high school that I really became a car guy. The very first time I rode in a E39 was in 2011, with Ryan’s 2000 E39 M5.</description></item><item><title>Alex’s 2000 BMW E46 328i Introduction</title><link>https://www.e39source.com/blog/alexs-2000-bmw-e46-328i-introduction/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.e39source.com/blog/alexs-2000-bmw-e46-328i-introduction/</guid><description>If I were to tell you that I’ve always been a fan of BMW, I’d be lying. Two years ago, if you were to tell me my first car would be an E46, I would have called you crazy! Living in Buffalo, NY, I pictured my first car as some sort of all wheel drive vehicle. I really was set on an older WRX, due to the decent performance, and great all wheel drive system.</description></item><item><title>Andrew’s 2000 BMW M5 Introduction</title><link>https://www.e39source.com/blog/andrews-2000-bmw-m5-introduction/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.e39source.com/blog/andrews-2000-bmw-m5-introduction/</guid><description>M5 ownership is a grand experience, even though it has been riddled with mistakes, hard work, and pure luck. My name is Andrew, and I didn’t start out with my current M5, but rather another BMW: my mother’s 2003 E53 X5. It has the 3.0 liter M54 motor, and a religious service history from the dealer/independent specialists so I would never be let down. It took me until halfway through my senior year in high school and I was using the X5’s utility to the max.</description></item><item><title>Andrew’s New Benz!</title><link>https://www.e39source.com/blog/andrews-new-benz/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.e39source.com/blog/andrews-new-benz/</guid><description>My past BMW’s were fun cars. I had a great time driving them, and I learned a lot fixing them. However, they got a bit repetitive after having cars so similar: the E53 X5, E36 318ti, and the E36 328i. These all shared so much in common that I could go through the motions to change out a thermostat or replace an oil filter housing gasket with my eyes closed.</description></item><item><title>BMW’s Bastard Child: My E36 318ti</title><link>https://www.e39source.com/blog/bmws-bastard-child-my-e36-318ti/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.e39source.com/blog/bmws-bastard-child-my-e36-318ti/</guid><description>Let’s keep things short, and get this started. I sold my E39 M5 at a good price, but I still miss it dearly. I’m in college studying engineering and pre-med, so I’m going to be in school for a long time. I don’t have the time anymore for photo shoots, car washes and detailing all the time. I needed something cheap, reliable and plain; and it had to be a good project car for some great E39Source content.</description></item><item><title>Charlie’s 2002 BMW 520i SE Introduction</title><link>https://www.e39source.com/blog/charlies-2002-bmw-520i-se-introduction/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.e39source.com/blog/charlies-2002-bmw-520i-se-introduction/</guid><description>Hi everyone, I’m really excited to share my new vehicle with you! I have always wanted a saloon, or sedan as you guys in the states call them. I am a tall guy, 6’7″, so trying to find the right vehicle is a pain! I have to find one first, and ask to sit in the car, which is always an awkward conversation. If I fit in it, then I know what to look for.</description></item><item><title>Christian’s 1999 540i Introduction</title><link>https://www.e39source.com/blog/christians-1999-540i-introduction/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.e39source.com/blog/christians-1999-540i-introduction/</guid><description>As far back as I can remember I have been obsessed with cars, and most recently that obsession has been channeled to my 1999 540i. My passion for cars is definitely in my family’s blood. My grandpa had a very strong interest in cars, some of which are some of the most beautiful cars from the 20th century in my opinion. These cars included a 1969 Signal Orange Porsche 911E, 1958 Blue Jaguar XK-140 convertible, 1968 Jaguar E-type convertible in Tan, and a 1966 Lincoln Continental convertible in Black with the suicide doors.</description></item><item><title>Christian’s 2000 BMW E46 330ci</title><link>https://www.e39source.com/blog/christains-2000-bmw-e46-330ci/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.e39source.com/blog/christains-2000-bmw-e46-330ci/</guid><description>Christian’s family had tried a BMW before- and it didn’t go well. What was so terrible about that first BMW? What is it about this E46 330ci that changed things? This is the story of Christian’s first car- a 2000 E46 finished in Oxford Green metallic.
I never thought I would say this, but I bought a BMW! Let me give that statement some context. BMW’s don’t have the best reputation in my family.</description></item><item><title>Colton’s 2001 BMW 540i Introduction</title><link>https://www.e39source.com/blog/coltons-2001-bmw-540i-introduction/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.e39source.com/blog/coltons-2001-bmw-540i-introduction/</guid><description>On Thursday, September 6th, 2012 at 5:08am I turned the key to the first ignition slot on what would turn into one of the biggest decisions of my life thus far. Let me start from the beginning. I’ve always been interested in automobiles, ever since I was a young boy. I was the boy who had a box full of matchbox cars which I would drive around on the floor for hours imagining different scenarios.</description></item><item><title>Compromise – Updates with Andrew and His 2000 M5</title><link>https://www.e39source.com/blog/compromise-updates-with-andrew-and-his-2000-m5/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.e39source.com/blog/compromise-updates-with-andrew-and-his-2000-m5/</guid><description>I’ve had my M5 for about seven months now, but I have only driven it 2500 miles. That is plenty of time to get familiar with my vehicle, but not enough to determine it’s reliability. For example, when I went to top off the tank before putting my M5 back into storage, it threw an SES code on the cluster. I plugged in my cheap-o generic OBDII scanner, and it came up with a P1526 and P0022 code, “A” Camshaft Position Actuator Control Open Circuit Bank 2 and “A” Camshaft Position – Timing over-retarded (Bank 2) respectively.</description></item><item><title>Danny’s Imola 2000 BMW M5</title><link>https://www.e39source.com/blog/dannys-imola-2000-bmw-m5/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.e39source.com/blog/dannys-imola-2000-bmw-m5/</guid><description>I was contemplating doing a video of the car and recorded one only to realize that my spoken English isn’t what it once was (Swedish sing-a-song-accent haha) so I’ll make a written post of my recently acquired M5 instead. I found out about the car a few months ago via a friend and I loosely knew the previous owner before as I were childhood friends with his brother.
PO bought the car in oct 2014 and drove it the 100 miles south from Stockholm to his home, and a week later a 500 mile round trip to get the pixels fixed, that it, he hasn’t driven it any more since.</description></item><item><title>Daryl’s 2001 525i Introduction</title><link>https://www.e39source.com/blog/daryls-2001-525i-introduction/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.e39source.com/blog/daryls-2001-525i-introduction/</guid><description>G’day from sunny Brisbane, Queensland Australia! I’m Daryl, however I go by the online name Dodgy Haro on most car forums (clubroadster + club4AG) which I participate in. My car background is mainly JDM (previous AE86 and Na6 Miata owner amongst other cars) however I do appreciate European rides too and how they generally handle better on highways and don’t impart that plastic feeling you get from some Japanese cars.</description></item><item><title>Fabien’s 2001 BMW Alpina B10 Introduction</title><link>https://www.e39source.com/blog/fabiens-2001-bmw-alpina-b10-introduction/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.e39source.com/blog/fabiens-2001-bmw-alpina-b10-introduction/</guid><description>The BMW E39 Alpina B10 V8 is based on the 540i. Restoration is on-going on this car. It is claimed to produce 347BHP and 450 Nm (332 lb/ft) of toque for the 4.6 M62B46 V8. The Alpina documentation specific to this car states power output to be 355BHP and 480 Nm (354 lb/ft). This example is from 2001, with extended Alpina leather, and the 19″ classic Alpina wheels.</description></item><item><title>Hassan’s 2002 BMW 530iA Introduction</title><link>https://www.e39source.com/blog/hassans-2002-bmw-530ia-introduction/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.e39source.com/blog/hassans-2002-bmw-530ia-introduction/</guid><description>I have always been really into cars; I can still remember my briefcase toy chest filled with hot wheels race cars. I used to love those things, I took them everywhere with me! The doctor’s office, on vacations, you name it, I always brought some little toy cars with me. I was a boy who loved cars, like many others. Like many little boys, I dreamed of driving a race car and going 300mph, and having the time of my life.</description></item><item><title>Ivor’s 2001 BMW 530i Introduction</title><link>https://www.e39source.com/blog/ivors-2001-bmw-530i-introduction/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.e39source.com/blog/ivors-2001-bmw-530i-introduction/</guid><description>This is my 2001 BMW 530i 5 speed. I bought this car in June of this year from a guy in Minnesota. I found the car on Craigslist, and bought it for $6,500, which was a great deal. I originally wanted an M5, but they were out of my price range, so I started looking for a 540i. After some research, I found out that the V8s are a pain to repair, and the MPGs are awful, so I decided to go for a 530i.</description></item><item><title>Jackson’s 2002 BMW E39 M5 Introduction</title><link>https://www.e39source.com/blog/jacksons-2002-bmw-e39-m5-introduction/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.e39source.com/blog/jacksons-2002-bmw-e39-m5-introduction/</guid><description>Hello everyone, I hope winter is going well so far! I’ve been a long-time member on M5Board, and I thought I’d swing over to this neighborhood to check out the scene! It’s a great technical and video based site in my opinion. My name is Jackson, and I live all the way up in Minnesota, also known as a**hole in the winter.
To begin, I’ve always loved the E39 chassis.</description></item><item><title>Jay’s 2000 BMW E39 M5</title><link>https://www.e39source.com/blog/jays-2000-bmw-e39-m5/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.e39source.com/blog/jays-2000-bmw-e39-m5/</guid><description>Hello E39Source! I am a new member to this website, and I wanted to get more involved with this close knit group of E39 enthusiasts. I just recently purchased my first M5! I bought it in Seattle, Washington with 148,000 miles on the clock. The interior is immaculate, along with the rest of the car. It honestly doesn’t feel as if it has covered 148,000 miles. I’ve driven upwards of ten M5s and this one takes the cake.</description></item><item><title>Josh’s 2001 530i Introduction</title><link>https://www.e39source.com/blog/joshs-2001-530i-introduction/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.e39source.com/blog/joshs-2001-530i-introduction/</guid><description>Hello from Melbourne, Australia! My names Josh, i’m an automotive photographer and a mechanic. I like a plethora of cars but BMW has always been my number one. Thought I would give you all a bit of a background into my obsession with the BMW brand and an introduction to my E39. This post may get a bit long though, its a trip down memory lane for me right now 😛</description></item><item><title>Kennan’s 2001 BMW 525i Introduction (Sold)</title><link>https://www.e39source.com/blog/kennans-2001-bmw-525i-introduction-sold/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.e39source.com/blog/kennans-2001-bmw-525i-introduction-sold/</guid><description>Germany has always meant a great deal to me for a variety of reasons. I admire the culture of the country, the passion in the pursuit of mechanical perfection, absolute efficiency and precision; these are just some of the stones that make up the foundation of what is the most stable country in all of Europe. Granted, my heart belongs to the Italians especially with cars, but there is a part of my soul that is tinted the colors that are all over this website.</description></item><item><title>Luke’s 2000 BMW M5</title><link>https://www.e39source.com/blog/lukes-2000-bmw-m5/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.e39source.com/blog/lukes-2000-bmw-m5/</guid><description>Let me begin by saying that I may be slightly biased when it comes to my assured claim that the E39 M5 is the greatest sports sedan of all time. While there are many other remarkable performance sedans out there (E28 M5, E34 M5, W211 E55, C5 RS6, and countless others), the E39 has held a special place in my heart from a young age. Not many other sedans have aged as gracefully and the E39 M5 represents the perfect blend between past and present in the M5 lineage.</description></item><item><title>Mike’s E39 528i &amp; M5 Introduction</title><link>https://www.e39source.com/blog/mikes-e39-528i-and-m5-indroduction/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.e39source.com/blog/mikes-e39-528i-and-m5-indroduction/</guid><description>Hey guys, thanks for welcoming me to E39source! I’ve been a YouTube subscriber for quite a while now, and actually met some of you at the Pittsburgh Vintage Grand Prix last summer. My name is Mike, and I’m 25 years old and live/work in West Chester, PA. I currently have two E39s: a 1997 528i, and a 2000 M5.
My 528i is a 3/96 build, with almost 305k miles on it now.</description></item><item><title>Ryan’s 2003 BMW 530iA Introduction</title><link>https://www.e39source.com/blog/ryans-2003-bmw-530ia-introduction/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.e39source.com/blog/ryans-2003-bmw-530ia-introduction/</guid><description>For as long as I can remember, I’ve held a strong interest in cars, though my parents accredit that to a toy school bus I had as a toddler. After I turned four, I would point to cars on the road and ask my dad what they were. His limited automotive knowledge meant that every SUV was a Jeep to me; everything else was a mishmash. Through clipping pictures of nice cars out of magazines, collecting Hot Wheels sized cars, and reading the undercarriage for the label, I started to form a vague understanding of what I was seeing on the road.</description></item><item><title>Tanvir’s 2003 BMW M5 Information</title><link>https://www.e39source.com/blog/tanvirs-2003-bmw-m5-information/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.e39source.com/blog/tanvirs-2003-bmw-m5-information/</guid><description>My story starts a little differently than others. It starts 13 years ago… with a different kind of BMW than the one that I now own. One that, in my opinion, is by far the finest thing to come from Germany in a very long time… The E30 M3. I owned that icon for 11 memorable years, and still marvel that I was fortunate enough to own something so pure in it’s DNA, something that rewarded your driver input, and never punished you when you got it wrong.</description></item><item><title>Tyler’s 1993 BMW 325iS Information</title><link>https://www.e39source.com/blog/tylers-1993-bmw-325is-information/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.e39source.com/blog/tylers-1993-bmw-325is-information/</guid><description>My story with my E36 is one of passion, heartbreak, persistence, hard work, and courage. That may sound a bit like the makings of a shoddy Lifetime movie, but I promise you this will be more entertaining than that. In my mind, this article is going to sound like something from Dan Neil in the WSJ. Instead, it may come off a bit like something a 17 year-old wrote one day while playing hooky… and that’d be correct.</description></item></channel></rss>