<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Project, Benz on E39Source</title><link>https://www.e39source.com/tags/project-benz/</link><description>Recent content in Project, Benz on E39Source</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://www.e39source.com/tags/project-benz/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Andrew’s New Benz!</title><link>https://www.e39source.com/blog/andrews-new-benz/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.e39source.com/blog/andrews-new-benz/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://e39source.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/12/IMG_5355.jpg" alt="Alt text">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My past BMW’s were fun cars. I had a great time driving them, and I learned a lot fixing them. However, they got a bit repetitive after having cars so similar: the E53 X5, E36 318ti, and the E36 328i. These all shared so much in common that I could go through the motions to change out a thermostat or replace an oil filter housing gasket with my eyes closed. So, what does a car guy do when they need a new project to tinker on? He moves on and gets a 1995 W124 Mercedes E320!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>BMW E39 M5 Camshaft Position Sensors</title><link>https://www.e39source.com/blog/bmw-e39-m5-camshaft-position-sensors/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.e39source.com/blog/bmw-e39-m5-camshaft-position-sensors/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://e39source.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/S62.png" alt="Alt text">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It’s always something, right? Usually electrical sensors are the most prominent, annoying, and expensive problems we have with these cars, and this only perpetuates this theory. Own an E39 M5 for long enough, and you’ll end up having to replace the cam sensors.&lt;/p>
&lt;p> &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>What is a Camshaft Position Sensor?&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Let’s start with a camshaft. Put basically, the camshaft is responsible for opening and closing intake and exhaust valves in a combustion engine. A camshaft position sensor senses the position of the camshaft as it revolves, reporting back to the VANOS (variable intake and exhaust valve timing system) telling it where the camshaft sits. This all enhances performance, efficiency, and overall smoothness of the engine. Since the M5’s engine is a ‘V’8, there are two cylinder banks, and thus four camshafts. Each cylinder bank has one intake, and one exhaust camshaft. Each camshaft has a CPS (camshaft position sensor). This brings the total to four CPS, two intake, and two exhaust.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>