<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>E39-SOURCE-M5 on E39Source</title><link>https://ajmameshin.github.io/E39Source/categories/e39-source-m5/</link><description>Recent content in E39-SOURCE-M5 on E39Source</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://ajmameshin.github.io/E39Source/categories/e39-source-m5/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>2011: The Story: Ryan’s 2000 BMW E39 M5:</title><link>https://ajmameshin.github.io/E39Source/blog/the-story-ryans-200-bmw-e39-m5-2011/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ajmameshin.github.io/E39Source/blog/the-story-ryans-200-bmw-e39-m5-2011/</guid><description>2011
By this point, I had learned that I could not afford to have any service/maintenance/upgrades carried out through BMW dealerships. I was on my own. And I found that there was very little quality DIY content available online. After spending years making technology DIYs on YouTube, I toyed with the idea of switching to cars. In 2011, I created E39Source DIYs for the shift knob, parking brake handle, center console trim, cup-holders, and I replaced a failed rear park distance control sensor.</description></item><item><title>2012: The Story: Ryan’s 2000 BMW E39 M5:</title><link>https://ajmameshin.github.io/E39Source/blog/the-story-ryans-200-bmw-e39-m5-2012/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ajmameshin.github.io/E39Source/blog/the-story-ryans-200-bmw-e39-m5-2012/</guid><description>2012
Fa t n eat b lts. My cluster’s pixels were committing suicide by the day. It turns out, somebody saw one of my videos showing the problem on YouTube. He sent me a message, telling me how to get BMW of North America to help fix the problem for less than the cost of a whole new cluster. This guy had a 2003 525iA do the same thing, and he is now partly responsible for this website, and one of my closest friends.</description></item><item><title>2013: The Story: Ryan’s 2000 BMW E39 M5:</title><link>https://ajmameshin.github.io/E39Source/blog/the-story-ryans-200-bmw-e39-m5-2013/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ajmameshin.github.io/E39Source/blog/the-story-ryans-200-bmw-e39-m5-2013/</guid><description>2013
Navigation. In the 2001 model year, BMW upgraded the E39’s navigation display to a 16:9 widescreen instrument. The computer also got upgraded. I took this a step further, and bought a MKIV computer in addition to 16:9 display. Big upgrade for this car, DVD readability and all!
I spent much of 2013 fixing the larger issues. They weren’t even large, but they bothered me. I replaced intake camshaft sensors, installed new floor matts and white fog bulbs, changed transmission and differentialoils, replaced control arms and tie rods, added LED license plate lights, had some more minor rust marks removed, changed shifter bushings, added a UUC Evo 3 short shift kit, replaced the FSU and blower motor and replaced my mass air flow sensors.</description></item><item><title>2014: The Story: Ryan’s 2000 BMW E39 M5:</title><link>https://ajmameshin.github.io/E39Source/blog/the-story-ryans-200-bmw-e39-m5-2014/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ajmameshin.github.io/E39Source/blog/the-story-ryans-200-bmw-e39-m5-2014/</guid><description>2014
Things will get crazy this year. I have decided to make this car as nice as I can afford to. That means every screw, every clip, every bracket, every everything has to be present, and in good working condition. They also need to look good. I ordered over 400 new parts for this car this year. It got new OEM style 65 wheels, new tires, chassis braces, instrument cluster bezel, switches, knobs, fan clutch, engine fan, door sills, M-audio subs, front bumper, trim, fog lights, rear bumper, trim, diffuser, facelift steering wheel, a total over-haul in electronics, all exterior door trim, coolant expansion tank, new filters, parking brake rebuild, rear brake overhaul, M3 oil cap, oil return hoses, and all mounting and installation hardware associated with these things.</description></item><item><title>2015: The Story: Ryan’s 2000 BMW E39 M5:</title><link>https://ajmameshin.github.io/E39Source/blog/the-story-ryans-200-bmw-e39-m5-2015/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ajmameshin.github.io/E39Source/blog/the-story-ryans-200-bmw-e39-m5-2015/</guid><description>2015</description></item><item><title>The Story: Ryan’s 2000 BMW E39 M5:</title><link>https://ajmameshin.github.io/E39Source/blog/the-story-ryans-200-bmw-e39-m5/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ajmameshin.github.io/E39Source/blog/the-story-ryans-200-bmw-e39-m5/</guid><description>All cars have a story, and I’m about to get very carried away telling mine. It’ll be long, detailed, and full of links to YouTube videos and website articles that I have written through the process. This is nearly a decade in the making, after all.
Sunday, July 18th, 2010. 6:42pm. The corner of Village Way and Library Street, in the midwestern town of Hudson, Ohio. I was in the downtown area of my community with my grandparents at a concert on our square.</description></item></channel></rss>